<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mteval>
<srcset setid="iwslt2017-tst2017plus" srclang="english">
<doc docid="2511" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/zaria_forman_drawings_that_show_the_beauty_and_fragility_of_earth</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Zaria Forman's large-scale compositions of melting glaciers, icebergs floating in glassy water and waves cresting with foam explore moments of transition, turbulence and tranquility. Join her as she discusses the meditative process of artistic creation and the motivation behind her work. "My drawings celebrate the beauty of what we all stand to lose," she says. "I hope they can serve as records of sublime landscapes in flux."</description> 
<keywords>talks, adventure, art, beauty, big problems, climate change, exploration, glacier, meditation, nature, oceans, sustainability, visualizations, water</keywords> 
<talkid>2511</talkid> 
<title>Zaria Forman: Drawings that show the beauty and fragility of Earth</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I consider it my life's mission  to convey the urgency of climate change through my work.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I've traveled north to the Arctic to the capture the unfolding story  of polar melt,  and south to the Equator to document the subsequent rising seas.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> Most recently, I visited the icy coast of Greenland  and the low-lying islands of the Maldives,  connecting two seemingly disparate but equally endangered  parts of our planet.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> My drawings explore moments of transition, turbulence  and tranquility in the landscape,  allowing viewers to emotionally connect  with a place you might never have the chance to visit.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> I choose to convey the beauty as opposed to the devastation.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> If you can experience the sublimity of these landscapes,  perhaps you'll be inspired to protect and preserve them.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Behavioral psychology tells us that we take action  and make decisions based on our emotions above all else.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And studies have shown that art impacts our emotions  more effectively than a scary news report.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Experts predict ice-free Arctic summers  as early as 2020.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And sea levels are likely to rise between two and ten feet  by century's end.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> I have dedicated my career to illuminating these projections  with an accessible medium,  one that moves us in a way that statistics may not.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> My process begins with traveling to the places  at the forefront of climate change.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> On-site, I take thousands of photographs.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Back in the studio,  I work from both my memory of the experience and the photographs  to create very large-scale compositions,  sometimes over 10 feet wide.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I draw with soft pastel, which is dry like charcoal, but colors.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> I consider my work drawings but others call them painting.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> I cringe, though, when I'm referred to as a "finger painter."    </seg>
<seg id="18">   But I don't use any tools  and I have always used my fingers and palms  to manipulate the pigment on the paper.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> Drawing is a form of meditation for me.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> It quiets my mind.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I don't perceive what I'm drawing as ice or water.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Instead, the image is stripped down  to its most basic form of color and shape.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Once the piece is complete,  I can finally experience the composition as a whole,  as an iceberg floating through glassy water,  or a wave cresting with foam.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> On average, a piece this size takes me about,  as you can see, 10 seconds.    </seg>
<seg id="25">     Really, more like 200 hours, 250 hours for something that size.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> But I've been drawing ever since I could hold a crayon, really.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> My mom was an artist, and growing up,  we always had art supplies all over the house.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> My mother's love of photography  propelled her to the most remote regions of the earth,  and my family and I were fortunate enough  to join and support her on these adventures.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> We rode camels in Northern Africa  and mushed on dog sleds near the North Pole.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> In August of 2012, I led my first expedition,  taking a group of artists and scholars up the northwest coast of Greenland.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> My mother was originally supposed to lead this trip.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> She and I were in the early stages of planning,  as we had intended to go together,  when she fell victim to a brain tumor.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> The cancer quickly took over her body and mind,  and she passed away six months later.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> During the months of her illness, though,  her dedication to the expedition never wavered, and I made a promise  to carry out her final journey.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> My mother's passion for the Arctic echoed through my experience in Greenland,  and I felt the power  and the fragility of the landscape.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> The sheer size of the icebergs is humbling.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> The ice fields are alive with movement and sound  in a way that I never expected.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> I expanded the scale of my compositions  to give you that same sense of awe that I experienced.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Yet, while the grandeur of the ice is evident,  so, too, is its vulnerability.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> From our boat,  I could see the ice sweating under the unseasonably warm sun.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> We had a chance to visit many of the Inuit communities in Greenland  that now face huge challenges.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> The locals spoke to me of vast areas of sea ice  that are no longer freezing over as they once did.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> And without ice, their hunting and harvesting grounds  are severely diminished,  threatening their way of life and survival.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> The melting glaciers in Greenland  are one of the largest contributing factors to rising sea levels,  which have already begun to drown  some of our world's lowest-lying islands.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> One year after my trip to Greenland, I visited the Maldives,  the lowest and flattest country in the entire world.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> While I was there, I collected images and inspiration  for a new body of work:  drawings of waves lapping on the coast of a nation  that could be entirely underwater within this century.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Devastating events happen every day  on scales both global and personal.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> When I was in Greenland,  I scattered my mother's ashes amidst the melting ice.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Now she remains a part of the landscape she loved so much,  even as it, too, passes and takes on new form.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Among the many gifts my mother gave me  was the ability to focus on the positive,  rather than the negative.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> My drawings celebrate the beauty of what we all stand to lose.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> I hope they can serve as records of sublime landscapes in flux,  documenting the transition and inspiring our global community  to take action for the future.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2507" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/trevor_timm_how_free_is_our_freedom_of_the_press</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: In the US, the press has a right to publish secret information the public needs to know, protected by the First Amendment. Government surveillance has made it increasingly more dangerous for whistleblowers, the source of virtually every important story about national security since 9/11, to share information. In this concise, informative talk, Freedom of the Press Foundation co-founder and TED Fellow Trevor Timm traces the recent history of government action against individuals who expose crime and injustice and advocates for technology that can help them do it safely and anonymously.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Internet, TED Fellows, corruption, crime, government</keywords> 
<talkid>2507</talkid> 
<title>Trevor Timm: How free is our freedom of the press?</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> So this is James Risen.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> You may know him as the Pulitzer Prize-winning reporter  for The New York Times.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> Long before anybody knew Edward Snowden's name,  Risen wrote a book in which he famously exposed  that the NSA was illegally wiretapping the phone calls of Americans.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> But it's another chapter in that book  that may have an even more lasting impact.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> In it, he describes a catastrophic US intelligence operation  in which the CIA quite literally handed over blueprints  of a nuclear bomb to Iran.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> If that sounds crazy, go read it.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> It's an incredible story.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> But you know who didn't like that chapter?    </seg>
<seg id="9"> The US government.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> For nearly a decade afterwards,  Risen was the subject of a US government investigation  in which prosecutors demanded that he testify  against one of his alleged sources.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And along the way, he became the face for the US government's recent pattern  of prosecuting whistleblowers and spying on journalists.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> You see, under the First Amendment,  the press has the right to publish secret information in the public interest.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> But it's impossible to exercise that right if the media can't also gather that news  and protect the identities of the brave men and women  who get it to them.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> So when the government came knocking,  Risen did what many brave reporters have done before him:  and said he'd rather go to jail.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> So from 2007 to 2015,  Risen lived under the specter of going to federal prison.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> That is, until just days before the trial, when a curious thing happened.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Suddenly, after years of claiming it was vital to their case,  the government dropped their demands to Risen altogether.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> It turns out, in the age of electronic surveillance,  there are very few places reporters and sources can hide.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And instead of trying and failing to have Risen testify,  they could have his digital trail testify against him instead.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> So completely in secret and without his consent,  prosecutors got Risen's phone records.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> They got his email records, his financial and banking information,  his credit reports,  even travel records with a list of flights he had taken.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> And it was among this information that they used to convict Jeffrey Sterling,  Risen's alleged source and CIA whistleblower.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Sadly, this is only one case of many.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> President Obama ran on a promise to protect whistleblowers,  and instead, his Justice Department has prosecuted more  than all other administrations combined.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Now, you can see how this could be a problem,  especially because the government considers so much of what it does secret.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Since 9/11, virtually every important story about national security  has been the result of a whistleblower coming to a journalist.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> So we risk seeing the press unable to do their job  that the First Amendment is supposed to protect  because of the government's expanded ability to spy on everyone.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> But just as technology has allowed the government  to circumvent reporters' rights,  the press can also use technology  to protect their sources even better than before.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> And they can start from the moment they begin speaking with them,  rather than on the witness stand after the fact.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Communications software now exists  that wasn't available when Risen was writing his book,  and is much more surveillance-resistant than regular emails or phone calls.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> For example, one such tool is SecureDrop,  an open-source whistleblower submission system  that was originally created by the late Internet luminary Aaron Swartz,  and is now developed at the non-profit where I work,  Freedom of the Press Foundation.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Instead of sending an email,  you go to a news organization's website,  like this one here on The Washington Post.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> From there, you can upload a document or send information  much like you would on any other contact form.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> It'll then be encrypted and stored on a server  that only the news organization has access to.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> So the government can no longer secretly demand the information,  and much of the information they would demand  wouldn't be available in the first place.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> SecureDrop, though, is really only a small part of the puzzle  for protecting press freedom in the 21st century.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Unfortunately, governments all over the world  are constantly developing new spying techniques  that put us all at risk.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And it's up to us going forward to make sure  that it's not just the tech-savvy whistleblowers,  like Edward Snowden, who have an avenue for exposing wrongdoing.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> It's just as vital that we protect the next veteran's health care whistleblower  alerting us to overcrowded hospitals,  or the next environmental worker  sounding the alarm about Flint's dirty water,  or a Wall Street insider  warning us of the next financial crisis.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> After all, these tools weren't just built to help the brave men and women  who expose crimes,  but are meant to protect all of our rights under the Constitution.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2504" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/laura_indolfi_good_news_in_the_fight_against_pancreatic_cancer</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Anyone who has lost a loved one to pancreatic cancer knows the devastating speed with which it can affect an otherwise healthy person. TED Fellow and biomedical entrepreneur Laura Indolfi is developing a revolutionary way to treat this complex and lethal disease: a drug delivery device that acts as a cage at the site of a tumor, preventing it from spreading and delivering medicine only where it's needed. "We are hoping that one day we can make pancreatic cancer a curable disease," she says.</description> 
<keywords>talks, TED Fellows, big problems, cancer, design, disease, entrepreneur, future, health, health care, illness, innovation, invention, medical research, medicine, potential, product design, science</keywords> 
<talkid>2504</talkid> 
<title>Laura Indolfi: Good news in the fight against pancreatic cancer</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> By raising your hand,  how many of you know at least one person on the screen?    </seg>
<seg id="2"> Wow, it's almost a full house.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> It's true, they are very famous in their fields.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> And do you know what all of them have in common?    </seg>
<seg id="5"> They all died of pancreatic cancer.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> However, although it's very, very sad this news,  it's also thanks to their personal stories  that we have raised awareness of how lethal this disease can be.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> It's become the third cause of cancer deaths,  and only eight percent of the patients will survive beyond five years.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> That's a very tiny number,  especially if you compare it with breast cancer,  where the survival rate is almost 90 percent.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> So it doesn't really come as a surprise  that being diagnosed with pancreatic cancer  means facing an almost certain death sentence.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> What's shocking, though, is that in the last 40 years,  this number hasn't changed a bit,  while much more progress has been made  with other types of tumors.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> So how can we make pancreatic cancer treatment more effective?    </seg>
<seg id="12"> As a biomedical entrepreneur,  I like to work on problems that seem impossible,  understanding their limitations  and trying to find new, innovative solutions  that can change their outcome.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> The first piece of bad news with pancreatic cancer  is that your pancreas is in the middle of your belly, literally.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> It's depicted in orange on the screen.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> But you can barely see it  until I remove all the other organs in front.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> It's also surrounded by many other vital organs,  like the liver, the stomach, the bile duct.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And the ability of the tumor to grow into those organs  is the reason why pancreatic cancer  is one of the most painful tumor types.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> The hard-to-reach location also prevents the doctor  from surgically removing it,  as is routinely done for breast cancer, for example.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> So all of these reasons leave chemotherapy as the only option  for the pancreatic cancer patient.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> This brings us to the second piece of bad news.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Pancreatic cancer tumors have very few blood vessels.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Why should we care about the blood vessel of a tumor?    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Let's think for a second how chemotherapy works.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> The drug is injected in the vein  and it navigates throughout the body until it reaches the tumor site.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> It's like driving on a highway, trying to reach a destination.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> But what if your destination doesn't have an exit on the highway?    </seg>
<seg id="27"> You will never get there.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> And that's exactly the same problem  for chemotherapy and pancreatic cancer.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> The drugs navigate throughout all of your body.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> They will reach healthy organs,  resulting in high toxic effect for the patients overall,  but very little will go to the tumor.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Therefore, the efficacy is very limited.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> To me, it seems very counterintuitive to have a whole-body treatment  to target a specific organ.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> However, in the last 40 years,  a lot of money, research and effort have gone towards  finding new, powerful drugs to treat pancreatic cancer,  but nothing has been done in changing the way  we deliver them to the patient.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> So after two pieces of bad news,  I'm going to give you good news, hopefully.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> With a collaborator at MIT  and the Massachusetts General Hospital in Boston,  we have revolutionized the way we treat cancer  by making localized drug delivery a reality.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> We are basically parachuting you on top of your destination,  avoiding your having to drive all around the highway.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> We have embedded the drug into devices that look like this one.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> They are flexible enough that they can be folded  to fit into the catheter,  so the doctor can implant it directly on top of the tumor  with minimally invasive surgery.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> But they are solid enough that once they are positioned  on top of the tumor,  they will act as a cage.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> They will actually physically prevent the tumor  from entering other organs,  controlling the metastasis.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> The devices are also biodegradable.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> That means that once in the body,  they start dissolving,  delivering the drug only locally, slowly and more effectively  than what is done with the current whole-body treatment.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> In pre-clinical study, we have demonstrated  that this localized approach  is able to improve by 12 times the response to treatment.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> So we took a drug that is already known  and by just delivering it locally where it's needed the most,  we allow a response that is 12 times more powerful,  reducing the systemic toxic effect.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> We are working relentlessly to bring this technology to the next level.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> We are finalizing the pre-clinical testing  and the animal model required prior to asking the FDA for approval  for clinical trials.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Currently, the majority of patients will die from pancreatic cancer.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> We are hoping that one day,  we can reduce their pain, extend their life  and potentially make pancreatic cancer  a curable disease.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> By rethinking the way we deliver the drug,  we don't only make it more powerful and less toxic,  we are also opening the door to finding new innovative solutions  for almost all other impossible problems  in pancreatic cancer patients and beyond.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2496" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/sanford_biggers_an_artist_s_unflinching_look_at_racial_violence</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Conceptual artist and TED Fellow Sanford Biggers uses painting, sculpture, video and performance to spark challenging conversations about the history and trauma of black America. Join him as he details two compelling works and shares the motivation behind his art. "Only through more thoughtful dialogue about history and race can we evolve as individuals and society," Biggers says.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Africa, Buddhism, Slavery, TED Fellows, activism, art, beauty, creativity, culture, global issues, identity, inequality, motivation, politics, race, social change, society, visualizations</keywords> 
<talkid>2496</talkid> 
<title>Sanford Biggers: An artist's unflinching look at racial violence</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> As a conceptual artist,  I'm constantly looking for creative ways to spark challenging conversations.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I do this though painting, sculpture, video and performance.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> But regardless of the format,  two of my favorite materials are history and dialogue.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> In 2007, I created "Lotus,"  a seven-and-a-half-foot diameter,  600-pound glass depiction of a lotus blossom.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> In Buddhism, the lotus is a symbol for transcendence  and for purity of mind and spirit.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> But a closer look at this lotus  reveals each petal to be the cross-section of a slave ship.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> This iconic diagram was taken from a British slaving manual  and later used by abolitionists to show the atrocities of slavery.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> In America, we don't like to talk about slavery,  nor do we look at it as a global industry.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> But by using this Buddhist symbol,  I hope to universalize and transcend  the history and trauma of black America  and encourage discussions about our shared past.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> To create "Lotus," we carved over 6,000 figures.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And this later led to a commission by the City of New York  to create a 28-foot version in steel  as a permanent installation at the Eagle Academy for Young Men,  a school for black and latino students,  the two groups most affected by this history.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> The same two groups are very affected by a more recent phenomenon,  but let me digress.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> I've been collecting wooden African figures  from tourist shops and flea markets around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> The authenticity and origin of them is completely debatable,  but people believe these to be imbued with power,  or even magic.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Only recently have I figured out how to use this in my own work.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> (Gun shots)  Since 2012, the world has witnessed the killings of Trayvon Martin,  Michael Brown, Eric Garner, Sandra Bland, Tamir Rice  and literally countless other unarmed black citizens  at the hands of the police,  who frequently walk away with no punishment at all.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> In consideration of these victims  and the several times that even I,  a law-abiding, Ivy League professor,  have been targeted and harassed at gunpoint by the police.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> I created this body of work simply entitled "BAM."    </seg>
<seg id="19"> It was important to erase the identity of each of these figures,  to make them all look the same and easier to disregard.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> To do this, I dip them in a thick, brown wax  before taking them to a shooting range  where I re-sculpted them using bullets.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> And it was fun,  playing with big guns and high-speed video cameras.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> But my reverence for these figures kept me from actually pulling the trigger,  somehow feeling as if I would be shooting myself.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Finally, my cameraman, Raul, fired the shots.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> I then took the fragments of these  and created molds, and cast them first in wax,  and finally in bronze like the image you see here,  which bears the marks of its violent creation  like battle wounds or scars.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> When I showed this work recently in Miami,  a woman told me she felt every gun shot to her soul.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> But she also felt that these artworks  memorialized the victims of these killings  as well as other victims of racial violence throughout US history.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> But "Lotus" and "BAM" are larger than just US history.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> While showing in Berlin last year,  a philosophy student asked me what prompted these recent killings.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> I showed him a photo of a lynching postcard  from the early 1900s  and reminded him that these killings have been going on for over 500 years.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> But it's only through questions like his  and more thoughtful dialogue about history and race  can we evolve as individuals and society.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> I hope my artwork creates a safe space  for this type of honest exchange  and an opportunity for people to engage one another  in real and necessary conversation.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2488" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/ameera_harouda_why_i_put_myself_in_danger_to_tell_the_stories_of_gaza</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: When Ameera Harouda hears the sounds of bombs or shells, she heads straight towards them. "I want to be there first because these stories should be told," says Gaza's first female "fixer," a role that allows her to guide journalists into chaotic, war zone scenarios in her home country, which she still loves despite its terrible situation. Find out what motivates Harouda to give a voice to Gaza's human suffering in this unforgettable talk.</description> 
<keywords>talks, choice, communication, fear, film, journalism, media, poverty, security, violence, war, women</keywords> 
<talkid>2488</talkid> 
<title>Ameera Harouda: Why I put myself in danger to tell the stories of Gaza</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Hello.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> This is my first trip,  first time in life I'm outside of the walls of Gaza.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I'm so happy to be here.    </seg>
<seg id="4">   My ambition always was to be a pilot, to fly a plane,  to feel free to fly the sky, to touch the sky.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> But that didn't happen.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Simply, I live in Gaza, there is no airport.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> All borders are closed on every side.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> We live in one of the biggest prisons in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> The only thing I can do is just to look up to the sky.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> On some days, we are lucky if we have electricity  for four or five hours.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> When it's cold, we make a fire on the front or on the roof of our homes.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> Sometimes we make food, too.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> My job in Gaza is to arrange everything for journalists who come to my homeland  to tell the stories about what's going on in Gaza.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Many mornings, I had to go to the border area  to collect a journalist.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> If anything should happen to the journalist,  or if the journalist decides to cover a story  the government doesn't want us to cover,  bad things could happen.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> Navigating through my country helping journalists,  filmmakers, news crews, is my working life.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> I believe my success comes from building a relationship  not only with journalists and the news crews,  but also with the communities in the Gaza Strip.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> These communities who don't want their stories to be told,  I never looked to them as stories or numbers.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> But like me, they are human beings.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> I have built up many relationships over 10 years.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> And guess what?    </seg>
<seg id="22"> This gives me the chance to get access to people,  to stories that others can't.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> In some certain situations, I feel, as a woman, I have more power.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Many male journalists in my society,  they want to cover a story about drug addiction in my country.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> That problem started when the Gaza tunnel was being built.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> With the siege on Gaza,  tunnels brought people all the basic needs  like food, building material, other stuff we needed.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> But not anymore, because the Egyptian side flooded them up with water  and they are not working anymore.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Drugs were being smuggled,  and many young people got addicted, too.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> In the tradition of the Palestinian society,  it's forbidden for men to enter the household.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> So, no male journalists get the story.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> But I did.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> I have a wonderful husband,  a wonderful husband who supports me  despite all the criticism he gets from the society.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> He's at home now with my two kids,  and I have another one that's growing in here.    </seg>
<seg id="34">   When I'm working, I call him every two hours,  and he knows if he doesn't hear from me,  he should call my contact,  the one who gives me access to the story,  which is the one who I trust.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> One of the times in Gaza,  during the kidnapping of the British journalist Alan Johnston,  I was asked by an American magazine  to set up a meeting with the kidnappers in Gaza, and I did.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> The journalist covering the story and I  were asked to meet outside of his hotel.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> They came, they picked us up in a black van with black windows,  they were wearing masks on that day.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And they drove us away, far away in the middle of a field.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> They took our cell phones  and we did the interview with the kidnapper outside in that field.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> I was so scared that day,  a day I will never forget.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> So, why do I do what I do?    </seg>
<seg id="42"> I do it because I believe if I didn't,  a huge part of the story about Gaza will be missing.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> There are some more stories I could tell you about my country.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> And not all of them are bad.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> I love my country, despite the terrible situation we live in --  siege, poverty, unemployment --  but there is life.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> There are people who are dreamers and amazing people full of energy.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> We have wonderful music, and a great music school.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> We have parkour dancers who dance in the rubble of their homes.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> And Gaza is the only place in the Arab world  where Muslims and Christians live in strong brotherhood.    </seg>
<seg id="50">   During the time of war,  the hardest part for me is leaving the house early in the morning,  leaving my children.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> I take a picture of them everyday  because I never know if I will make it back to them.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Being a fixer and a journalist is difficult and dangerous in Gaza.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> But when I hear the sound of the shelling or the sound of the bombing,  I just head straight toward it,  because I want to be there first,  because these stories should be told.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> When my children were small and we heard the sound of the war,  I used to tell them that they were fireworks.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Now they are older, they understand.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> I do have terrible nightmares  because of all that I witnessed during war times,  especially these lifeless bodies of young children.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> I still remember a little girl, her name is Hala.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> She's the only survivor from her family.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Her picture will be with me forever.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> I will never forget her.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> I'm proud that I can stand here and be here today with you.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> I'm proud that I can tell you stories, sad and happy,  stories about my small corner of the world, Gaza.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> I'm proud that I am the first female fixer working in Gaza.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> And the funny thing is they call me Mr. Rambo in Gaza.    </seg>
<seg id="65">   I hope one day, I will get the chance to tell the stories of all other women,  all other amazing women I know in my country.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> I hope that one day I can help other women in my country  to be fixers like me.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> And of course sometimes, I feel I can't do this work anymore,  it's just too much for me.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> But I remember these words:  "Don't limit your challenge, but challenge your limit.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Don't allow others to stand in front of your dreams."    </seg>
<seg id="70"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2478" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/robert_palmer_the_panama_papers_exposed_a_huge_global_problem_what_s_next</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: On April 3, 2016 we saw the largest data leak in history. The Panama Papers exposed rich and powerful people hiding vast amounts of money in offshore accounts. But what does it all mean? We called Robert Palmer of Global Witness to find out.</description> 
<keywords>talks, activism, big problems, business, corruption, economics, global issues, government, identity, inequality, investment, law, money, news, poverty</keywords> 
<talkid>2478</talkid> 
<title>Robert Palmer: The Panama Papers exposed a huge global problem. What's next?</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> [On April 3, 2016 we saw the largest data leak in history.]  [The Panama Papers exposed rich and powerful people]  [hiding vast amounts of money in offshore accounts.]  [What does this mean?]  [We called Robert Palmer of Global Witness to explain.]  This week, there have been a whole slew and deluge of stories  coming out from the leak of 11 million documents    </seg>
<seg id="2"> from a Panamanian-based law firm called Mossack Fonseca.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> The release of these papers from Panama lifts the veil on a tiny piece  of the secretive offshore world.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> We get an insight into how clients and banks and lawyers  go to companies like Mossack Fonseca  and say, "OK, we want an anonymous company,  can you give us one?"    </seg>
<seg id="5"> So you actually get to see the emails,  you get to see the exchanges of messages,  you get to see the mechanics of how this works,  how this operates.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Now, this has already started to have pretty immediate repercussions.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> The Prime Minister of Iceland has resigned.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> We've also had news  that an ally of the brutal Syrian dictator Bashar Al-Assad  has also got offshore companies.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> There's been allegations of a $2 billion money trail  that leads back to President Vladimir Putin of Russia  via his close childhood friend,  who happens to be a top cellist.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And there will be a lot of rich individuals out there  and others who will be nervous about the next set of stories  and the next set of leaked documents.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Now, this sounds like the plot of a spy thriller  or a John Grisham novel.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> It seems very distant from you, me, ordinary people.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Why should we care about this?    </seg>
<seg id="14"> But the truth is that if rich and powerful individuals  are able to keep their money offshore  and not pay the taxes that they should,  it means that there is less money for vital public services  like healthcare, education, roads.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> And that affects all of us.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> Now, for my organization Global Witness,  this exposé has been phenomenal.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> We have the world's media and political leaders  talking about how individuals can use offshore secrecy  to hide and disguise their assets --  something we have been talking about and exposing for a decade.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> Now, I think a lot of people find this entire world baffling and confusing,  and hard to understand how this sort of offshore world works.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> I like to think of it a bit like a Russian doll.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> So you can have one company stacked inside another company,  stacked inside another company,  making it almost impossible to really understand  who is behind these structures.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> It can be very difficult for law enforcement  or tax authorities, journalists, civil society  to really understand what's going on.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> I also think it's interesting  that there's been less coverage of this issue in the United States.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> And that's perhaps because some prominent US people  just haven't figured in this exposé, in this scandal.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Now, that's not because there are no rich Americans  who are stashing their assets offshore.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> It's just because of the way in which offshore works,  Mossack Fonseca has fewer American clients.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> I think if we saw leaks from the Cayman Islands  or even from Delaware or Wyoming or Nevada,  you would see many more cases and examples linking back to Americans.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> In fact, in a number of US states you need less information,  you need to provide less information to get a company  than you do to get a library card.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> That sort of secrecy in America has allowed employees of school districts  to rip off schoolchildren.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> It has allowed scammers to rip off vulnerable investors.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> This is the sort of behavior that affects all of us.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Now, at Global Witness,  we wanted to see what this actually looked like in practice.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> How does this actually work?    </seg>
<seg id="33"> So what we did  is we sent in an undercover investigator to 13 Manhattan law firms.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> Our investigator posed as an African minister  who wanted to move suspect funds into the United States  to buy a house, a yacht, a jet.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Now, what was truly shocking was that all but one of those lawyers  provided our investigator with suggestions  on how to move those suspect funds.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> These were all preliminary meetings,  and none of the lawyers took us on as a client  and of course no money moved hands,  but it really shows the problem with the system.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> It's also important  to not just think about this as individual cases.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> This is not just about an individual lawyer  who's spoken to our undercover investigator and provided suggestions.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> It's not just about a particular senior politician  who's been caught up in a scandal.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> This is about how a system works,  that entrenches corruption, tax evasion, poverty and instability.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> And in order to tackle this,  we need to change the game.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> We need to change the rules of the game  to make this sort of behavior harder.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> This may seem like doom and gloom,  like there's nothing we can do about it,  like nothing has ever changed,  like there will always be rich and powerful individuals.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> But as a natural optimist,  I do see that we are starting to get some change.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Over the last couple of years,  we've seen a real push towards greater transparency  when it comes to company ownership.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> This issue was put on the political agenda by the UK Prime Minister David Cameron  at a big G8 Summit that was held in Northern Ireland in 2013.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> And since then, the European Union is going to be creating  central registers at a national level  of who really owns and controls companies across Europe.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> One of the things that is sad is that, actually, the US is lagging behind.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> There's bipartisan legislation that had been introduced  in the House and the Senate,  but it isn't making as much progress as we'd like to see.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> So we'd really want to see the Panama leaks,  this huge peek into the offshore world,  be used as a way of opening up in the US and around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> For us at Global Witness, this is a moment for change.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> We need ordinary people to get angry  at the way in which people can hide their identity  behind secret companies.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> We need business leaders to stand up and say,  "Secrecy like this is not good for business."    </seg>
<seg id="54"> We need political leaders to recognize the problem,  and to commit to changing the law to open up this sort of secrecy.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Together, we can end the secrecy  that is currently allowing tax evasion,  corruption, money laundering to flourish.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2470" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/knut_haanaes_two_reasons_companies_fail_and_how_to_avoid_them</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Is it possible to run a company and reinvent it at the same time? For business strategist Knut Haanaes, the ability to innovate after becoming successful is the mark of a great organization. He shares insights on how to strike a balance between perfecting what we already know and exploring totally new ideas -- and lays out how to avoid two major strategy traps.</description> 
<keywords>talks, business, creativity, curiosity, goal-setting, innovation, motivation, potential, success, work</keywords> 
<talkid>2470</talkid> 
<title>Knut Haanaes: Two reasons companies fail -- and how to avoid them</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Here are two reasons companies fail:  they only do more of the same,  or they only do what's new.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> To me the real, real solution to quality growth  is figuring out the balance between two activities:  exploration and exploitation.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> Both are necessary,  but it can be too much of a good thing.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Consider Facit.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> I'm actually old enough to remember them.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Facit was a fantastic company.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> They were born deep in the Swedish forest,  and they made the best mechanical calculators in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Everybody used them.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> And what did Facit do when the electronic calculator came along?    </seg>
<seg id="10"> They continued doing exactly the same.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> In six months, they went from maximum revenue ...    </seg>
<seg id="12"> and they were gone.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Gone.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> To me, the irony about the Facit story  is hearing about the Facit engineers,  who had bought cheap, small electronic calculators in Japan  that they used to double-check their calculators.    </seg>
<seg id="15">   Facit did too much exploitation.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> But exploration can go wild, too.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> A few years back,  I worked closely alongside a European biotech company.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> Let's call them OncoSearch.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> The company was brilliant.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> They had applications that promised to diagnose, even cure,  certain forms of blood cancer.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Every day was about creating something new.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> They were extremely innovative,  and the mantra was, "When we only get it right,"  or even, "We want it perfect."    </seg>
<seg id="23"> The sad thing is,  before they became perfect --  even good enough --  they became obsolete.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> OncoSearch did too much exploration.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> I first heard about exploration and exploitation about 15 years ago,  when I worked as a visiting scholar at Stanford University.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> The founder of the idea is Jim March.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> And to me the power of the idea is its practicality.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Exploration.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> Exploration is about coming up with what's new.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> It's about search,  it's about discovery,  it's about new products,  it's about new innovations.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> It's about changing our frontiers.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Our heroes are people who have done exploration:  Madame Curie,  Picasso,  Neil Armstrong,  Sir Edmund Hillary, etc.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> I come from Norway;  all our heroes are explorers, and they deserve to be.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> We all know that exploration is risky.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> We don't know the answers,  we don't know if we're going to find them,  and we know that the risks are high.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Exploitation is the opposite.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Exploitation is taking the knowledge we have  and making good, better.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> Exploitation is about making our trains run on time.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> It's about making good products faster and cheaper.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> Exploitation is not risky --  in the short term.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> But if we only exploit,  it's very risky in the long term.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> And I think we all have memories of the famous pop groups  who keep singing the same songs again and again,  until they become obsolete or even pathetic.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> That's the risk of exploitation.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> So if we take a long-term perspective, we explore.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> If we take a short-term perspective, we exploit.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Small children, they explore all day.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> All day it's about exploration.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> As we grow older,  we explore less because we have more knowledge to exploit on.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> The same goes for companies.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Companies become, by nature, less innovative  as they become more competent.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> And this is, of course, a big worry to CEOs.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> And I hear very often questions phrased in different ways.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> For example,  "How can I both effectively run and reinvent my company?"    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Or, "How can I make sure  that our company changes before we become obsolete  or are hit by a crisis?"    </seg>
<seg id="55"> So, doing one well is difficult.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> Doing both well as the same time is art --  pushing both exploration and exploitation.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> So one thing we've found  is only about two percent of companies are able to effectively explore  and exploit at the same time, in parallel.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> But when they do,  the payoffs are huge.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> So we have lots of great examples.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> We have Nestlé creating Nespresso,  we have Lego going into animated films,  Toyota creating the hybrids,  Unilever pushing into sustainability --  there are lots of examples, and the benefits are huge.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Why is balancing so difficult?    </seg>
<seg id="62"> I think it's difficult because there are so many traps  that keep us where we are.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> So I'll talk about two, but there are many.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> So let's talk about the perpetual search trap.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> We discover something,  but we don't have the patience or the persistence  to get at it and make it work.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> So instead of staying with it, we create something new.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> But the same goes for that,  then we're in the vicious circle  of actually coming up with ideas but being frustrated.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> OncoSearch was a good example.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> A famous example is, of course, Xerox.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> But we don't only see this in companies.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> We see this in the public sector as well.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> We all know that any kind of effective reform of education,  research, health care, even defense,  takes 10, 15, maybe 20 years to work.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> But still, we change much more often.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> We really don't give them the chance.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> Another trap is the success trap.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Facit fell into the success trap.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> They literally held the future in their hands,  but they couldn't see it.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> They were simply so good at making what they loved doing,  that they wouldn't change.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> We are like that, too.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> When we know something well, it's difficult to change.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Bill Gates has said:  "Success is a lousy teacher.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> It seduces us into thinking we cannot fail."    </seg>
<seg id="83"> That's the challenge with success.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> So I think there are some lessons, and I think they apply to us.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> And they apply to our companies.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> The first lesson is: get ahead of the crisis.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> And any company that's able to innovate  is actually able to also buy an insurance in the future.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> Netflix -- they could so easily have been content  with earlier generations of distribution,  but they always -- and I think they will always --  keep pushing for the next battle.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> I see other companies that say,  "I'll win the next innovation cycle, whatever it takes."    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Second one: think in multiple time scales.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> I'll share a chart with you,  and I think it's a wonderful one.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> Any company we look at,  taking a one-year perspective  and looking at the valuation of the company,  innovation typically accounts for only about 30 percent.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> So when we think one year,  innovation isn't really that important.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> Move ahead, take a 10-year perspective on the same company --  suddenly, innovation and ability to renew account for 70 percent.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> But companies can't choose.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> They need to fund the journey and lead the long term.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> Third:  invite talent.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> I don't think it's possible for any of us  to be able to balance exploration and exploitation by ourselves.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> I think it's a team sport.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> I think we need to allow challenging.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> I think the mark of a great company is being open to be challenged,  and the mark of a good corporate board is to constructively challenge.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> I think that's also what good parenting is about.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> Last one: be skeptical of success.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> Maybe it's useful to think back at the old triumph marches in Rome,  when the generals, after a big victory,  were given their celebration.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> Riding into Rome on the carriage,  they always had a companion whispering in their ear,  "Remember, you're only human."    </seg>
<seg id="106"> So I hope I made the point:  balancing exploration and exploitation  has a huge payoff.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> But it's difficult, and we need to be conscious.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> I want to just point out two questions that I think are useful.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> First question is, looking at your own company:  In which areas do you see that the company is at the risk  of falling into success traps,  of just going on autopilot?    </seg>
<seg id="110"> And what can you do to challenge?    </seg>
<seg id="111"> Second question is:  When did I explore something new last,  and what kind of effect did it have on me?    </seg>
<seg id="112"> Is that something I should do more of?    </seg>
<seg id="113"> In my case, yes.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> So let me leave you with this.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> Whether you're an explorer by nature  or whether you tend to exploit what you already know,  don't forget: the beauty is in the balance.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2471" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/lisa_nip_how_humans_could_evolve_to_survive_in_space</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: If we hope to one day leave Earth and explore the universe, our bodies are going to have to get a lot better at surviving the harsh conditions of space. Using synthetic biology, Lisa Nip hopes to harness special powers from microbes on Earth -- such as the ability to withstand radiation -- to make humans more fit for exploring space. "We're approaching a time during which we'll have the capacity to decide our own genetic destiny," Nip says. "Augmenting the human body with new abilities is no longer a question of how, but of when."</description> 
<keywords>talks, Planets, TEDx, bacteria, biology, engineering, environment, evolution, exploration, future, innovation, intelligence, microbiology, nature, potential, science</keywords> 
<talkid>2471</talkid> 
<title>Lisa Nip: How humans could evolve to survive in space</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> So there are lands few and far between on Earth itself  that are hospitable to humans by any measure,  but survive we have.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> Our primitive ancestors, when they found their homes and livelihood endangered,  they dared to make their way into unfamiliar territories  in search of better opportunities.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> And as the descendants of these explorers,  we have their nomadic blood coursing through our own veins.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> But at the same time,  distracted by our bread and circuses  and embroiled in the wars that we have waged on each other,  it seems that we have forgotten this desire to explore.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> We, as a species, we're evolved uniquely  for Earth, on Earth, and by Earth,  and so content are we with our living conditions  that we have grown complacent and just too busy  to notice that its resources are finite,  and that our Sun's life is also finite.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> While Mars and all the movies made in its name  have reinvigorated the ethos for space travel,  few of us seem to truly realize that our species' fragile constitution  is woefully unprepared for long duration journeys into space.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Let us take a trek to your local national forest  for a quick reality check.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> So just a quick show of hands here:  how many of you think you would be able to survive in this lush wilderness  for a few days?    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Well, that's a lot of you.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> How about a few weeks?    </seg>
<seg id="11"> That's a decent amount.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> How about a few months?    </seg>
<seg id="13"> That's pretty good too.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Now, let us imagine that this local national forest  experiences an eternal winter.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Same questions: how many of you think you would be able to survive for a few days?    </seg>
<seg id="16"> That's quite a lot.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> How about a few weeks?    </seg>
<seg id="18"> So for a fun twist, let us imagine that the only source of water available  is trapped as frozen blocks miles below the surface.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> Soil nutrients are so minimal that no vegetation can be found,  and of course hardly any atmosphere exists to speak of.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> Such examples are only a few of the many challenges we would face  on a planet like Mars.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> So how do we steel ourselves for voyages whose destinations are so far removed  from a tropical vacation?    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Will we continuously ship supplies from Planet Earth?    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Build space elevators, or impossible miles of transport belts  that tether your planet of choice to our home planet?    </seg>
<seg id="24"> And how do we grow things like food that grew up on Earth like us?    </seg>
<seg id="25"> But I'm getting ahead of myself.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> In our species' journey to find a new home under a new sun,  we are more likely than not going to be spending much time  in the journey itself,  in space,  on a ship, a hermetic flying can,  possibly for many generations.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> The longest continuous amount of time that any human has spent in space  is in the vicinity of 12 to 14 months.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> From astronauts' experiences in space,  we know that spending time in a microgravity environment  means bone loss, muscle atrophy, cardiovascular problems,  among many other complications that range for the physiological to the psychological.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> And what about macrogravity,  or any other variation in gravitational pull  of the planet that we find ourselves on?    </seg>
<seg id="30"> In short, our cosmic voyages will be fraught with dangers  both known and unknown.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> So far we've been looking to this new piece of mechanical technology  or that great next generation robot  as part of a lineup to ensure our species safe passage in space.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Wonderful as they are, I believe the time has come  for us to complement these bulky electronic giants  with what nature has already invented:  the microbe,  a single-celled organism that is itself a self-generating, self-replenishing,  living machine.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> It requires fairly little to maintain,  offers much flexibility in design  and only asks to be carried in a single plastic tube.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> The field of study that has enabled us to utilize the capabilities of the microbe  is known as synthetic biology.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> It comes from molecular biology, which has given us antibiotics, vaccines  and better ways to observe the physiological nuances of the human body.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Using the tools of synthetic biology,  we can now edit the genes of nearly any organism,  microscopic or not,  with incredible speed and fidelity.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Given the limitations of our man-made machines,  synthetic biology will be a means for us to engineer not only our food,  our fuel and our environment,  but also ourselves  to compensate for our physical inadequacies  and to ensure our survival in space.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> To give you an example  of how we can use synthetic biology for space exploration,  let us return to the Mars environment.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> The Martian soil composition is similar to that of Hawaiian volcanic ash,  with trace amounts of organic material.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> Let's say, hypothetically,  what if martian soil could actually support plant growth  without using Earth-derived nutrients?    </seg>
<seg id="41"> The first question we should probably ask is,  how would we make our plants cold-tolerant?    </seg>
<seg id="42"> Because, on average, the temperature on Mars  is a very uninviting negative 60 degrees centigrade.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> The next question we should ask is,  how do we make our plants drought-tolerant?    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Considering that most of the water that forms as frost  evaporates more quickly than I can say the word "evaporate."    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Well, it turns out we've already done things like this.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> By borrowing genes for anti-freeze protein from fish  and genes for drought tolerance from other plants like rice  and then stitching them into the plants that need them,  we now have plants that can tolerate most droughts and freezes.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> They're known on Earth as GMOs,  or genetically modified organisms,  and we rely on them to feed all the mouths of human civilization.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Nature does stuff like this already, without our help.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> We have simply found more precise ways to do it.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> So why would we want to change the genetic makeup of plants for space?    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Well, to not do so would mean needing to engineer  endless acres of land on an entirely new planet  by releasing trillions of gallons of atmospheric gasses  and then constructing a giant glass dome to contain it all.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> It's an unrealistic engineering enterprise  that quickly becomes a high-cost cargo transport mission.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> One of the best ways to ensure  that we will have the food supplies and the air that we need  is to bring with us organisms that have been engineered  to adapt to new and harsh environments.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> In essence, using engineered organisms to help us terraform a planet  both in the short and long term.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> These organisms can then also be engineered to make medicine or fuel.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> So we can use synthetic biology to bring highly engineered plants with us,  but what else can we do?    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Well, I mentioned earlier that we, as a species,  were evolved uniquely for planet Earth.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> That fact has not changed much in the last five minutes  that you were sitting here and I was standing there.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> And so, if we were to dump any of us on Mars right this minute,  even given ample food, water, air  and a suit,  we are likely to experience very unpleasant health problems  from the amount of ionizing radiation that bombards the surface  of planets like Mars that have little or nonexistent atmosphere.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Unless we plan to stay holed up underground  for the duration of our stay on every new planet,  we must find better ways of protecting ourselves  without needing to resort to wearing a suit of armor  that weighs something equal to your own body weight,  or needing to hide behind a wall of lead.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> So let us appeal to nature for inspiration.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Among the plethora of life here on Earth,  there's a subset of organisms known as extremophiles,  or lovers of extreme living conditions,  if you'll remember from high school biology.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> And among these organisms is a bacterium by the name of Deinococcus radiodurans.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> It is known to be able to withstand cold, dehydration, vacuum, acid,  and, most notably, radiation.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> While its radiation tolerance mechanisms are known,  we have yet to adapt the relevant genes to mammals.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> To do so is not particularly easy.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> There are many facets that go into its radiation tolerance,  and it's not as simple as transferring one gene.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> But given a little bit of human ingenuity and a little bit of time,  I think to do so is not very hard either.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Even if we borrow just a fraction of its ability to tolerate radiation,  it would be infinitely better than what we already have,  which is just the melanin in our skin.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> Using the tools of synthetic biology,  we can harness Deinococcus radiodurans' ability  to thrive under otherwise very lethal doses of radiation.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> As difficult as it is to see,  homo sapiens, that is humans,  evolves every day,  and still continues to evolve.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Thousands of years of human evolution  has not only given us humans like Tibetans,  who can thrive in low-oxygen conditions,  but also Argentinians, who can ingest and metabolize arsenic,  the chemical element that can kill the average human being.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> Every day, the human body evolves by accidental mutations  that equally accidentally allow certain humans  to persevere in dismal situations.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> But, and this is a big but,  such evolution requires two things that we may not always have,  or be able to afford,  and they are death and time.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> In our species' struggle to find our place in the universe,  we may not always have the time necessary  for the natural evolution of extra functions  for survival on non-Earth planets.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> We're living in what E.O. Wilson has termed the age of gene circumvention,  during which we remedy our genetic defects like cystic fibrosis or muscular dystrophy  with temporary external supplements.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> But with every passing day,  we approach the age of volitional evolution,  a time during which we as a species  will have the capacity to decide for ourselves our own genetic destiny.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> Augmenting the human body with new abilities  is no longer a question of how,  but of when.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Using synthetic biology to change the genetic makeup of any living organisms,  especially our own,  is not without its moral and ethical quandaries.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Will engineering ourselves make us less human?    </seg>
<seg id="81"> But then again, what is humanity but star stuff that happens to be conscious?    </seg>
<seg id="82"> Where should human genius direct itself?    </seg>
<seg id="83"> Surely it is a bit of a waste to sit back and marvel at it.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> How do we use our knowledge  to protect ourselves from the external dangers  and then protect ourselves from ourselves?    </seg>
<seg id="85"> I pose these questions  not to engender the fear of science  but to bring to light the many possibilities  that science has afforded and continues to afford us.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> We must coalesce as humans to discuss and embrace the solutions  not only with caution but also with courage.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> Mars is a destination,  but it will not be our last.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> Our true final frontier is the line we must cross  in deciding what we can and should make of our species' improbable intelligence.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> Space is cold, brutal and unforgiving.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Our path to the stars will be rife with trials  that will bring us to question not only who we are  but where we will be going.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> The answers will lie in our choice to use or abandon the technology  that we have gleaned from life itself,  and it will define us for the remainder of our term in this universe.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2456" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/arthur_brooks_a_conservative_s_plea_let_s_work_together</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Conservatives and liberals both believe that they alone are motivated by love while their opponents are motivated by hate. How can we solve problems with so much polarization? In this talk, social scientist Arthur Brooks shares ideas for what we can each do as individuals to break the gridlock. "We might just be able to take the ghastly holy war of ideology that we're suffering under and turn it into a competition of ideas," he says.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Debate, big problems, business, capitalism, collaboration, community, democracy, economics, global issues, government, identity, leadership, philosophy, policy, politics, social change, society</keywords> 
<talkid>2456</talkid> 
<title>Arthur Brooks: A conservative's plea: Let's work together</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I come from one of the most liberal,  tolerant, progressive places in the United States,  Seattle, Washington.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> And I grew up with a family of great Seattlites.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> My mother was an artist, my father was a college professor,  and I am truly grateful for my upbringing,  because I always felt completely comfortable designing my life  exactly as I saw fit.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> And in point of fact,  I took a route that was not exactly what my parents had in mind.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> When I was 19, I dropped out of college --  dropped out, kicked out, splitting hairs.    </seg>
<seg id="6">   And I went on the road as a professional French horn player,  which was my lifelong dream.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> I played chamber music all over the United States and Europe,  and I toured for a couple of years  with a great jazz guitar player named Charlie Bird.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And by the end of my 20s,  I wound up as a member of the Barcelona Symphony Orchestra in Spain.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> What a great life.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And you know, my parents never complained.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> They supported me all the way through it.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> It wasn't their dream.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> They used to tell their neighbors and friends,  "Our son, he's taking a gap decade."    </seg>
<seg id="14">   And --  There was, however, one awkward conversation about my lifestyle  that I want to tell you about.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I was 27, and I was home from Barcelona,  and I was visiting my parents for Christmas,  and I was cooking dinner with my mother, and we were alone in the kitchen.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> And she was quiet, too quiet.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Something was wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> And so I said, "Mom, what's on your mind?"    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And she said, "Your dad and I are really worried about you."    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And I said, "What?" I mean, what could it be, at this point?    </seg>
<seg id="21"> And she said, "I want you to be completely honest with me:  have you been voting for Republicans?"    </seg>
<seg id="22">   Now, the truth is,  I wasn't really political, I was just a French horn player.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> But I had a bit of an epiphany,  and they had detected it, and it was causing some confusion.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> You see, I had become an enthusiast for capitalism,  and I want to tell you why that is.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> It stems from a lifelong interest of mine  in, believe it or not, poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> See, when I was a kid growing up in Seattle,  I remember the first time I saw real poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> We were a lower middle class family, but that's of course not real poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> That's not even close.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> The first time I saw poverty, and poverty's face,  was when I was six or seven years old, early 1970s.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> And it was like a lot of you, kind of a prosaic example, kind of trite.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> It was a picture in the National Geographic Magazine  of a kid who was my age in East Africa,  and there were flies on his face and a distended belly.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> And he wasn't going to make it, and I knew that, and I was helpless.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Some of you remember that picture,  not exactly that picture, one just like it.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> It introduced the West to grinding poverty around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Well, that vision kind of haunted me as I grew up and I went to school  and I dropped out and dropped in  and started my family.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> And I wondered, what happened to that kid?    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Or to people just like him all over the world?    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And so I started to study, even though I wasn't in college,  I was looking for the answer:  what happened to the world's poorest people?    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Has it gotten worse? Has it gotten better? What?    </seg>
<seg id="40"> And I found the answer, and it changed my life,  and I want to share it with you.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> See --  most Americans believe that poverty has gotten worse  since we were children, since they saw that vision.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> If you ask Americans, "Has poverty gotten worse or better around the world?",  70 percent will say that hunger has gotten worse since the early 1970s.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> But here's the truth.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Here's the epiphany that I had that changed my thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> From 1970 until today,  the percentage of the world's population  living in starvation levels,  living on a dollar a day or less, obviously adjusted for inflation,  that percentage has declined  by 80 percent.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> There's been an 80 percent decline in the world's worst poverty  since I was a kid.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> And I didn't even know about it.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> This, my friends, that's a miracle.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> That's something we ought to celebrate.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> It's the greatest antipoverty achievement in the history of mankind,  and it happened in our lifetimes.    </seg>
<seg id="51">   So when I learned this, I asked, what did that? What made it possible?    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Because if you don't know why, you can't do it again.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> If you want to replicate it  and get the next two billion people out of poverty,  because that's what we're talking about: since I was a kid,  two billion of the least of these, our brothers and sisters,  have been pulled out of poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> I want the next two billion, so I've got to know why.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And I went in search of an answer.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And it wasn't a political answer, because I didn't care.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> You know what, I still don't care.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> I wanted the best answer from mainstream economists  left, right and center.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> And here it is.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Here are the reasons.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> There are five reasons that two billion of our brothers and sisters  have been pulled out of poverty since I was a kid.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Number one: globalization.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> Number two: free trade.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> Number three: property rights.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Number four: rule of law.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Number five: entrepreneurship.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> It was the free enterprise system spreading around the world  after 1970 that did that.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Now, I'm not naive.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> I know that free enterprise isn't perfect,  and I know that free enterprise isn't everything we need  to build a better world.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> But that is great.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> And that's beyond politics.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Here's what I learned. This is the epiphany.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> Capitalism is not just about accumulation.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> At its best, it's about aspiration,  which is what so many people on this stage talk about,  is the aspiration that comes from dreams  that are embedded in the free enterprise system.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> And we've got to share it with more people.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Now, I want to tell you about a second epiphany  that's related to that first one  that I think can bring us progress, not just around the world,  but right here at home.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> The best quote I've ever heard  to summarize the thoughts that I've just given you  about pulling people out of poverty  is as follows:  "Free markets have created more wealth than any system in history.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> They have lifted billions out of poverty."    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Who said it?    </seg>
<seg id="80"> It sounds like Milton Friedman or Ronald Reagan.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> President Barack Obama said that.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> Why do I know it by heart?    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Because he said it to me.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Crazy.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> And I said, "Hallelujah."    </seg>
<seg id="87"> But more than that, I said,  "What an opportunity."    </seg>
<seg id="88"> You know what I was thinking?    </seg>
<seg id="89"> It was at an event that we were doing on the subject  at Georgetown University in May of 2015.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> And I thought, this is the solution  to the biggest problem facing America today. What?    </seg>
<seg id="91"> It's coming together around these ideas,  liberals and conservatives,  to help people who need us the most.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> Now, I don't have to tell anybody in this room that we're in a crisis,  in America and many countries around the world with political polarization.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> It's risen to critical, crisis levels.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> It's unpleasant. It's not right.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> There was an article last year  in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences,  which is one of the most prestigious scientific journals  published in the West.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> And it was an article in 2014  on political motive asymmetry.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> What's that? That's what psychologists call the phenomenon  of assuming that your ideology is based in love  but your opponents' ideology is based in hate.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> It's common in world conflict.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> You expect to see this between Palestinians and Israelis, for example.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> What the authors of this article found  was that in America today, a majority of Republicans and Democrats  suffer from political motive asymmetry.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> A majority of people in our country today who are politically active believe  that they are motivated by love but the other side is motivated by hate.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> Think about it. Think about it.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> Most people are walking around saying,  "You know, my ideology is based on basic benevolence,  I want to help people,  but the other guys, they're evil and out to get me."    </seg>
<seg id="104"> You can't progress as a society when you have this kind of asymmetry.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> It's impossible.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> How do we solve it?    </seg>
<seg id="107"> Well, first, let's be honest: there are differences.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> Let's not minimize the differences. That would be really naïve.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> There's a lot of good research on this.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> A veteran of the TED stage is my friend Jonathan Haidt.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> He's a psychology professor at New York University.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> He does work on the ideology and values and morals of different people  to see how they differ.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> And he's shown, for example, that conservatives and liberals  have a very different emphasis on what they think is important.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> For example, Jon Haidt has shown  that liberals care about poverty  59 percent more than they care about economic liberty.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> And conservatives care about economic liberty  28 percent more than they care about poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> Irreconcilable differences, right?    </seg>
<seg id="117"> We'll never come together. Wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> That is diversity in which lies our strength.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> Remember what pulled up the poor.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> It was the obsession with poverty,  accompanied by the method of economic freedom  spreading around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> We need each other, in other words,  if we want to help people and get the next two billion people out of poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> There's no other way.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> Hmm.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> How are we going to get that?    </seg>
<seg id="125"> It's a tricky thing, isn't it.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> We need innovative thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> A lot of it's on this stage.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> Social entrepreneurship. Yeah. Absolutely. Phenomenal.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> We need investment overseas  in a sustainable, responsible, ethical and moral way. Yes. Yes.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> But you know what we really need?    </seg>
<seg id="131"> We need a new day in flexible ideology.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> We need to be less predictable.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> Don't we?    </seg>
<seg id="134"> Do you ever feel like your own ideology is starting to get predictable?    </seg>
<seg id="135"> Kinda conventional?    </seg>
<seg id="136"> Do you ever feel like you're always listening to people who agree with you?    </seg>
<seg id="137"> Why is that dangerous?    </seg>
<seg id="138"> Because when we talk in this country about economics,  on the right, conservatives,  you're always talking about taxes and regulations and big government.    </seg>
<seg id="139"> And on the left, liberals, you're talking about economics,  it's always about income inequality.    </seg>
<seg id="140"> Right? Now those are important things,  really important to me, really important to you.    </seg>
<seg id="141"> But when it comes to lifting people up  who are starving and need us today, those are distractions.    </seg>
<seg id="142"> We need to come together around the best ways  to mitigate poverty using the best tools at our disposal,  and that comes only when conservatives recognize that they need liberals  and their obsession with poverty,  and liberals need conservatives and their obsession with free markets.    </seg>
<seg id="143"> That's the diversity in which lies the future strength of this country,  if we choose to take it.    </seg>
<seg id="144"> So how are we going to do it? How are we going to do it together?    </seg>
<seg id="145"> I've got to have some action items, not just for you but for me.    </seg>
<seg id="146"> Number one. Action item number one:  remember, it's not good enough just to tolerate people who disagree.    </seg>
<seg id="147"> It's not good enough.    </seg>
<seg id="148"> We have to remember that we need people who disagree with us,  because there are people who need all of us  who are still waiting for these tools.    </seg>
<seg id="149"> Now, what are you going to do? How are you going to express that?    </seg>
<seg id="150"> Where does this start? It starts here.    </seg>
<seg id="151"> You know, all of us in this room, we're blessed.    </seg>
<seg id="152"> We're blessed with people who listen to us.    </seg>
<seg id="153"> We're blessed with prosperity. We're blessed with leadership.    </seg>
<seg id="154"> When people hear us, with the kind of unpredictable ideology,  then maybe people will listen.    </seg>
<seg id="155"> Maybe progress will start at that point.    </seg>
<seg id="156"> That's number one. Number two.    </seg>
<seg id="157"> Number two: I'm asking you and I'm asking me  to be the person specifically who blurs the lines,  who is ambiguous, who is hard to classify.    </seg>
<seg id="158"> If you're a conservative,  be the conservative who is always going on about poverty  and the moral obligation to be a warrior for the poor.    </seg>
<seg id="159"> And if you're a liberal, be a liberal who is always talking  about the beauty of free markets to solve our problems  when we use them responsibly.    </seg>
<seg id="160"> If we do that, we get two things.    </seg>
<seg id="161"> Number one: we get to start to work on the next two billion  and be the solution that we've seen so much of in the past  and we need to see more of in the future. That's what we get.    </seg>
<seg id="162"> And the second is that we might just be able  to take the ghastly holy war of ideology that we're suffering under in this country  and turn it into a competition of ideas  based on solidarity and mutual respect.    </seg>
<seg id="163"> And then maybe, just maybe,  we'll all realize that our big differences  aren't really that big after all.    </seg>
<seg id="164"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2447" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/joe_gebbia_how_airbnb_designs_for_trust</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Joe Gebbia, the co-founder of Airbnb, bet his whole company on the belief that people can trust each other enough to stay in one another's homes. How did he overcome the stranger-danger bias? Through good design. Now, 123 million hosted nights (and counting) later, Gebbia sets out his dream for a culture of sharing in which design helps foster community and connection instead of isolation and separation.</description> 
<keywords>talks, behavioral economics, business, collaboration, community, culture, design, economics, entrepreneur, future, innovation, potential, privacy, product design, relationships, social change, technology, urban planning</keywords> 
<talkid>2447</talkid> 
<title>Joe Gebbia: How Airbnb designs for trust</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I want to tell you the story  about the time I almost got kidnapped  in the trunk of a red Mazda Miata.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> It's the day after graduating from design school  and I'm having a yard sale.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> And this guy pulls up in this red Mazda  and he starts looking through my stuff.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> And he buys a piece of art that I made.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> And it turns out he's alone in town for the night,  driving cross-country on a road trip  before he goes into the Peace Corps.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> So I invite him out for a beer  and he tells me all about his passion  for making a difference in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Now it's starting to get late,  and I'm getting pretty tired.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> As I motion for the tab,  I make the mistake of asking him,  "So where are you staying tonight?"    </seg>
<seg id="9"> And he makes it worse by saying,  "Actually, I don't have a place."    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And I'm thinking, "Oh, man!"    </seg>
<seg id="11"> What do you do?    </seg>
<seg id="12"> We've all been there, right?    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Do I offer to host this guy?    </seg>
<seg id="14"> But, I just met him -- I mean,  he says he's going to the Peace Corps,  but I don't really know if he's going to the Peace Corps  and I don't want to end up kidnapped in the trunk of a Miata.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> That's a small trunk!    </seg>
<seg id="16"> So then I hear myself saying,  "Hey, I have an airbed you can stay on in my living room."    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And the voice in my head goes,  "Wait, what?"    </seg>
<seg id="18"> That night, I'm laying in bed,  I'm staring at the ceiling and thinking,  "Oh my god, what have I done?    </seg>
<seg id="19"> There's a complete stranger sleeping in my living room.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> What if he's psychotic?"    </seg>
<seg id="21"> My anxiety grows so much,  I leap out of bed,  I sneak on my tiptoes to the door,  and I lock the bedroom door.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> It turns out he was not psychotic.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> We've kept in touch ever since.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> And the piece of art he bought at the yard sale  is hanging in his classroom; he's a teacher now.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> This was my first hosting experience,  and it completely changed my perspective.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Maybe the people that my childhood taught me to label as strangers  were actually friends waiting to be discovered.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> The idea of hosting people on airbeds gradually became natural to me  and when I moved to San Francisco,  I brought the airbed with me.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> So now it's two years later.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> I'm unemployed, I'm almost broke,  my roommate moves out, and then the rent goes up.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> And then I learn there's a design conference coming to town,  and all the hotels are sold out.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> And I've always believed that turning fear into fun  is the gift of creativity.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> So here's what I pitch my best friend and my new roommate Brian Chesky:  "Brian, thought of a way to make a few bucks --  turning our place into 'designers bed and breakfast,'  offering young designers who come to town a place to crash,  complete with wireless Internet, a small desk space,  sleeping mat, and breakfast each morning.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Ha!"    </seg>
<seg id="34"> We built a basic website and Airbed and Breakfast was born.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Three lucky guests got to stay  on a 20-dollar airbed on the hardwood floor.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> But they loved it, and so did we.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> I swear, the ham and Swiss cheese omelets we made  tasted totally different because we made them for our guests.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> We took them on adventures around the city,  and when we said goodbye to the last guest,  the door latch clicked,  Brian and I just stared at each other.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Did we just discover it was possible to make friends  while also making rent?    </seg>
<seg id="40"> The wheels had started to turn.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> My old roommate, Nate Blecharczyk,  joined as engineering co-founder.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> And we buckled down to see  if we could turn this into a business.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Here's what we pitched investors:  "We want to build a website  where people publicly post pictures of their most intimate spaces,  their bedrooms, the bathrooms --  the kinds of rooms you usually keep closed when people come over.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> And then, over the Internet,  they're going to invite complete strangers to come sleep in their homes.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> It's going to be huge!"    </seg>
<seg id="46">   We sat back, and we waited for the rocket ship to blast off.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> It did not.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> No one in their right minds would invest in a service  that allows strangers to sleep in people's homes.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Why?    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Because we've all been taught as kids, strangers equal danger.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Now, when you're faced with a problem, you fall back on what you know,  and all we really knew was design.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> In art school, you learn that design is much more  than the look and feel of something -- it's the whole experience.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> We learned to do that for objects,  but here, we were aiming to build Olympic trust  between people who had never met.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Could design make that happen?    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Is it possible to design for trust?    </seg>
<seg id="56"> I want to give you a sense of the flavor of trust  that we were aiming to achieve.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> I've got a 30-second experiment  that will push you past your comfort zone.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> OK, I need you to take out your phones.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Now that you have your phone out,  I'd like you to unlock your phone.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Now hand your unlocked phone to the person on your left.    </seg>
<seg id="61">   That tiny sense of panic you're feeling right now --    is exactly how hosts feel the first time they open their home.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Because the only thing more personal than your phone  is your home.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> People don't just see your messages,  they see your bedroom,  your kitchen, your toilet.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> Now, how does it feel holding someone's unlocked phone?    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Most of us feel really responsible.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> That's how most guests feel when they stay in a home.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> And it's because of this that our company can even exist.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> By the way, who's holding Al Gore's phone?    </seg>
<seg id="69">   Would you tell Twitter he's running for President?    </seg>
<seg id="70">     OK, you can hand your phones back now.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> So now that you've experienced the kind of trust challenge  we were facing,  I'd love to share a few discoveries we've made along the way.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> What if we changed one small thing  about the design of that experiment?    </seg>
<seg id="73"> What if your neighbor had introduced themselves first, with their name,  where they're from, the name of their kids or their dog?    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Imagine that they had 150 reviews of people saying,  "They're great at holding unlocked phones!"    </seg>
<seg id="75">   Now how would you feel about handing your phone over?    </seg>
<seg id="76"> It turns out,  a well-designed reputation system is key for building trust.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> And we didn't actually get it right the first time.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> It's hard for people to leave bad reviews.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Eventually, we learned to wait until both guests and hosts  left the review before we reveal them.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Now, here's a discovery we made just last week.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> We did a joint study with Stanford,  where we looked at people's willingness to trust someone  based on how similar they are in age, location and geography.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> The research showed, not surprisingly,  we prefer people who are like us.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> The more different somebody is,  the less we trust them.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Now, that's a natural social bias.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> But what's interesting is what happens  when you add reputation into the mix,  in this case, with reviews.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> Now, if you've got less than three reviews,  nothing changes.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> But if you've got more than 10,  everything changes.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> High reputation beats high similarity.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> The right design can actually help us overcome  one of our most deeply rooted biases.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Now we also learned that building the right amount of trust  takes the right amount of disclosure.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> This is what happens when a guest first messages a host.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> If you share too little, like, "Yo,"  acceptance rates go down.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> And if you share too much, like,  "I'm having issues with my mother,"    acceptance rates also go down.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> But there's a zone that's just right,  like, "Love the artwork in your place. Coming for vacation with my family."    </seg>
<seg id="95"> So how do we design for just the right amount of disclosure?    </seg>
<seg id="96"> We use the size of the box to suggest the right length,  and we guide them with prompts to encourage sharing.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> We bet our whole company  on the hope that,  with the right design,  people would be willing to overcome the stranger-danger bias.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> What we didn't realize  is just how many people  were ready and waiting to put the bias aside.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> This is a graph that shows our rate of adoption.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> There's three things happening here.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> The first, an unbelievable amount of luck.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> The second is the efforts of our team.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> And third is the existence of a previously unsatisfied need.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> Now, things have been going pretty well.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> Obviously, there are times when things don't work out.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> Guests have thrown unauthorized parties  and trashed homes.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> Hosts have left guests stranded in the rain.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> In the early days, I was customer service,  and those calls came right to my cell phone.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> I was at the front lines of trust breaking.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> And there's nothing worse than those calls,  it hurts to even think about them.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> And the disappointment in the sound of someone's voice  was and, I would say, still is  our single greatest motivator to keep improving.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> Thankfully, out of the 123 million nights we've ever hosted,  less than a fraction of a percent have been problematic.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> Turns out, people are justified in their trust.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> And when trust works out right,  it can be absolutely magical.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> We had a guest stay with a host in Uruguay,  and he suffered a heart attack.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> The host rushed him to the hospital.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> They donated their own blood for his operation.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> Let me read you his review.    </seg>
<seg id="119">   "Excellent house for sedentary travelers  prone to myocardial infarctions.    </seg>
<seg id="120">   The area is beautiful and has direct access to the best hospitals.    </seg>
<seg id="121">   Javier and Alejandra instantly become guardian angels  who will save your life without even knowing you.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> They will rush you to the hospital in their own car while you're dying  and stay in the waiting room while the doctors give you a bypass.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> They don't want you to feel lonely, they bring you books to read.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> And they let you stay at their house extra nights without charging you.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> Highly recommended!"    </seg>
<seg id="126">   Of course, not every stay is like that.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> But this connection beyond the transaction  is exactly what the sharing economy is aiming for.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> Now, when I heard that term,  I have to admit, it tripped me up.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> How do sharing and transactions go together?    </seg>
<seg id="130"> So let's be clear; it is about commerce.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> But if you just called it the rental economy,  it would be incomplete.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> The sharing economy is commerce with the promise of human connection.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> People share a part of themselves,  and that changes everything.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> You know how most travel today is, like,  I think of it like fast food --  it's efficient and consistent,  at the cost of local and authentic.    </seg>
<seg id="135"> What if travel were like a magnificent buffet  of local experiences?    </seg>
<seg id="136"> What if anywhere you visited,  there was a central marketplace of locals  offering to get you thoroughly drunk  on a pub crawl in neighborhoods you didn't even know existed.    </seg>
<seg id="137"> Or learning to cook from the chef of a five-star restaurant?    </seg>
<seg id="138"> Today, homes are designed around the idea of privacy and separation.    </seg>
<seg id="139"> What if homes were designed to be shared from the ground up?    </seg>
<seg id="140"> What would that look like?    </seg>
<seg id="141"> What if cities embraced a culture of sharing?    </seg>
<seg id="142"> I see a future of shared cities that bring us community and connection  instead of isolation and separation.    </seg>
<seg id="143"> In South Korea, in the city of Seoul,  they've actually even started this.    </seg>
<seg id="144"> They've repurposed hundreds of government parking spots  to be shared by residents.    </seg>
<seg id="145"> They're connecting students who need a place to live  with empty-nesters who have extra rooms.    </seg>
<seg id="146"> And they've started an incubator to help fund the next generation  of sharing economy start-ups.    </seg>
<seg id="147"> Tonight, just on our service,  785,000 people  in 191 countries  will either stay in a stranger's home  or welcome one into theirs.    </seg>
<seg id="148"> Clearly, it's not as crazy as we were taught.    </seg>
<seg id="149"> We didn't invent anything new.    </seg>
<seg id="150"> Hospitality has been around forever.    </seg>
<seg id="151"> There's been many other websites like ours.    </seg>
<seg id="152"> So, why did ours eventually take off?    </seg>
<seg id="153"> Luck and timing aside,  I've learned that you can take the components of trust,  and you can design for that.    </seg>
<seg id="154"> Design can overcome our most deeply rooted  stranger-danger bias.    </seg>
<seg id="155"> And that's amazing to me.    </seg>
<seg id="156"> It blows my mind.    </seg>
<seg id="157"> I think about this every time I see a red Miata go by.    </seg>
<seg id="158"> Now, we know design won't solve all the world's problems.    </seg>
<seg id="159"> But if it can help out with this one,  if it can make a dent in this,  it makes me wonder, what else can we design for next?    </seg>
<seg id="160"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2442" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/dalia_mogahed_what_do_you_think_when_you_look_at_me</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: When you look at Muslim scholar Dalia Mogahed, what do you see: a woman of faith? a scholar, a mom, a sister? or an oppressed, brainwashed, potential terrorist? In this personal, powerful talk, Mogahed asks us, in this polarizing time, to fight negative perceptions of her faith in the media -- and to choose empathy over prejudice.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Islam, United States, culture, faith, politics</keywords> 
<talkid>2442</talkid> 
<title>Dalia Mogahed: What do you think when you look at me?</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> What do you think when you look at me?    </seg>
<seg id="2"> A woman of faith? An expert?    </seg>
<seg id="3"> Maybe even a sister.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Or oppressed,  brainwashed,  a terrorist.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Or just an airport security line delay.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> That one's actually true.    </seg>
<seg id="7">   If some of your perceptions were negative, I don't really blame you.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> That's just how the media has been portraying  people who look like me.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> One study found  that 80 percent of news coverage about Islam and Muslims is negative.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And studies show that Americans say that most don't know a Muslim.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> I guess people don't talk to their Uber drivers.    </seg>
<seg id="12">   Well, for those of you who have never met a Muslim,  it's great to meet you.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Let me tell you who I am.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> I'm a mom, a coffee lover --  double espresso, cream on the side.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I'm an introvert.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> I'm a wannabe fitness fanatic.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And I'm a practicing, spiritual Muslim.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> But not like Lady Gaga says, because baby, I wasn't born this way.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> It was a choice.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> When I was 17, I decided to come out.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> No, not as a gay person like some of my friends,  but as a Muslim,  and decided to start wearing the hijab, my head covering.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> My feminist friends were aghast:  "Why are you oppressing yourself?"    </seg>
<seg id="23"> The funny thing was,  it was actually at that time a feminist declaration of independence  from the pressure I felt as a 17-year-old,  to conform to a perfect and unattainable standard of beauty.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> I didn't just passively accept the faith of my parents.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> I wrestled with the Quran.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> I read and reflected and questioned and doubted  and, ultimately, believed.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> My relationship with God -- it was not love at first sight.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> It was a trust and a slow surrender  that deepened with every reading of the Quran.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> Its rhythmic beauty sometimes moves me to tears.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> I see myself in it. I feel that God knows me.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Have you ever felt like someone sees you, completely understands you  and yet loves you anyway?    </seg>
<seg id="32"> That's how it feels.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> And so later, I got married,  and like all good Egyptians,  started my career as an engineer.    </seg>
<seg id="34">   I later had a child, after getting married,  and I was living essentially the Egyptian-American dream.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> And then that terrible morning of September, 2001.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> I think a lot of you probably remember exactly where you were that morning.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> I was sitting in my kitchen finishing breakfast,  and I look up on the screen and see the words "Breaking News."    </seg>
<seg id="38"> There was smoke, airplanes flying into buildings,  people jumping out of buildings.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> What was this?    </seg>
<seg id="40"> An accident?    </seg>
<seg id="41"> A malfunction?    </seg>
<seg id="42"> My shock quickly turned to outrage.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Who would do this?    </seg>
<seg id="44"> And I switch the channel and I hear,  "... Muslim terrorist ...,"  "... in the name of Islam ...,"  "... Middle-Eastern descent ...,"  "... jihad ...,"  "... we should bomb Mecca."    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Oh my God.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Not only had my country been attacked,  but in a flash,  somebody else's actions had turned me from a citizen  to a suspect.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> That same day, we had to drive across Middle America  to move to a new city to start grad school.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> And I remember sitting in the passenger seat  as we drove in silence,  crouched as low as I could go in my seat,  for the first time in my life, afraid for anyone to know I was a Muslim.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> We moved into our apartment that night in a new town  in what felt like a completely different world.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> And then I was hearing and seeing and reading  warnings from national Muslim organizations  saying things like, "Be alert," "Be aware,"  "Stay in well-lit areas," "Don't congregate."    </seg>
<seg id="51"> I stayed inside all week.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> And then it was Friday that same week,  the day that Muslims congregate for worship.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> And again the warnings were, "Don't go that first Friday,  it could be a target."    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And I was watching the news, wall-to-wall coverage.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Emotions were so raw, understandably,  and I was also hearing about attacks on Muslims,  or people who were perceived to be Muslim, being pulled out  and beaten in the street.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> Mosques were actually firebombed.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> And I thought, we should just stay home.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> And yet, something didn't feel right.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Because those people who attacked our country  attacked our country.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> I get it that people were angry at the terrorists.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Guess what? So was I.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> And so to have to explain yourself all the time isn't easy.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> I don't mind questions. I love questions.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> It's the accusations that are tough.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Today we hear people actually saying things like,  "There's a problem in this country, and it's called Muslims.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> When are we going to get rid of them?"    </seg>
<seg id="67"> So, some people want to ban Muslims and close down mosques.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> They talk about my community kind of like we're a tumor  in the body of America.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> And the only question is, are we malignant or benign?    </seg>
<seg id="70"> You know, a malignant tumor you extract altogether,  and a benign tumor you just keep under surveillance.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> The choices don't make sense, because it's the wrong question.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Muslims, like all other Americans, aren't a tumor in the body of America,  we're a vital organ.    </seg>
<seg id="73">   Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="74">   Muslims are inventors and teachers,  first responders and Olympic athletes.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> Now, is closing down mosques going to make America safer?    </seg>
<seg id="76"> It might free up some parking spots,  but it will not end terrorism.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> Going to a mosque regularly is actually linked  to having more tolerant views of people of other faiths  and greater civic engagement.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> And as one police chief in the Washington, DC area  recently told me,  people don't actually get radicalized at mosques.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> They get radicalized in their basement or bedroom, in front of a computer.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> And what you find about the radicalization process  is it starts online,  but the first thing that happens  is the person gets cut off from their community,  from even their family,  so that the extremist group can brainwash them  into believing that they, the terrorists, are the true Muslims,  and everyone else who abhors their behavior and ideology  are sellouts or apostates.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> So if we want to prevent radicalization,  we have to keep people going to the mosque.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> Now, some will still argue Islam is a violent religion.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> After all, a group like ISIS bases its brutality on the Quran.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Now, as a Muslim, as a mother, as a human being,  I think we need to do everything we can to stop a group like ISIS.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> But we would be giving in to their narrative  if we cast them as representatives of a faith of 1.6 billion people.    </seg>
<seg id="86">   Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> ISIS has as much to do with Islam  as the Ku Klux Klan has to do with Christianity.    </seg>
<seg id="88">   Both groups claim to base their ideology on their holy book.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> But when you look at them, they're not motivated  by what they read in their holy book.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> It's their brutality that makes them read these things into the scripture.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> Recently, a prominent imam told me a story that really took me aback.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> He said that a girl came to him  because she was thinking of going to join ISIS.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> And I was really surprised and asked him,  had she been in contact with a radical religious leader?    </seg>
<seg id="94"> And he said the problem was quite the opposite,  that every cleric that she had talked to had shut her down  and said that her rage, her sense of injustice in the world,  was just going to get her in trouble.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> And so with nowhere to channel and make sense of this anger,  she was a prime target to be exploited  by extremists promising her a solution.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> What this imam did was to connect her back to God and to her community.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> He didn't shame her for her rage -- instead, he gave her constructive ways  to make real change in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> What she learned at that mosque prevented her from going to join ISIS.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> I've told you a little bit  about how Islamophobia affects me and my family.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> But how does it impact ordinary Americans?    </seg>
<seg id="101"> How does it impact everyone else?    </seg>
<seg id="102"> How does consuming fear 24 hours a day affect the health of our democracy,  the health of our free thought?    </seg>
<seg id="103"> Well, one study -- actually, several studies in neuroscience --  show that when we're afraid, at least three things happen.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> We become more accepting of authoritarianism,  conformity and prejudice.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> One study showed that when subjects were exposed to news stories  that were negative about Muslims,  they became more accepting of military attacks on Muslim countries  and policies that curtail the rights of American Muslims.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> Now, this isn't just academic.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> When you look at when anti-Muslim sentiment spiked  between 2001 and 2013,  it happened three times,  but it wasn't around terrorist attacks.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> It was in the run up to the Iraq War and during two election cycles.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> So Islamophobia isn't just the natural response to Muslim terrorism  as I would have expected.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> It can actually be a tool of public manipulation,  eroding the very foundation of a free society,  which is rational and well-informed citizens.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> Muslims are like canaries in the coal mine.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> We might be the first to feel it,  but the toxic air of fear is harming us all.    </seg>
<seg id="113">   And assigning collective guilt  isn't just about having to explain yourself all the time.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> Deah and his wife Yusor were a young married couple  living in Chapel Hill, North Carolina,  where they both went to school.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> Deah was an athlete.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> He was in dental school, talented, promising ...    </seg>
<seg id="117"> And his sister would tell me that he was the sweetest,  most generous human being she knew.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> She was visiting him there and he showed her his resume,  and she was amazed.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> She said, "When did my baby brother become such an accomplished young man?"    </seg>
<seg id="120"> Just a few weeks after Suzanne's visit to her brother and his new wife,  their neighbor,  Craig Stephen Hicks,  murdered them,  as well as Yusor's sister, Razan, who was visiting for the afternoon,  in their apartment,  execution style,  after posting anti-Muslim statements on his Facebook page.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> He shot Deah eight times.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> So bigotry isn't just immoral, it can even be lethal.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> So, back to my story.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> What happened after 9/11?    </seg>
<seg id="125"> Did we go to the mosque or did we play it safe and stay home?    </seg>
<seg id="126"> Well, we talked it over,  and it might seem like a small decision, but to us,  it was about what kind of America we wanted to leave for our kids:  one that would control us by fear  or one where we were practicing our religion freely.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> So we decided to go to the mosque.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> And we put my son in his car seat,  buckled him in, and we drove silently, intensely, to the mosque.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> I took him out, I took off my shoes, I walked into the prayer hall  and what I saw made me stop.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> The place was completely full.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> And then the imam made an announcement,  thanking and welcoming our guests,  because half the congregation  were Christians, Jews, Buddhists, atheists,  people of faith and no faith,  who had come not to attack us, but to stand in solidarity with us.    </seg>
<seg id="132">   I just break down at this time.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> These people were there because they chose courage and compassion  over panic and prejudice.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> What will you choose?    </seg>
<seg id="135"> What will you choose at this time of fear and bigotry?    </seg>
<seg id="136"> Will you play it safe?    </seg>
<seg id="137"> Or will you join those who say  we are better than that?    </seg>
<seg id="138"> Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="139">   Thank you so much.    </seg>
<seg id="140"> Helen Walters: So Dalia, you seem to have struck a chord.    </seg>
<seg id="141"> But I wonder,  what would you say to those who might argue  that you're giving a TED Talk,  you're clearly a deep thinker,  you work at a fancy think tank,  you're an exception, you're not the rule.    </seg>
<seg id="142"> What would you say to those people?    </seg>
<seg id="143"> Dalia Mogahed: I would say, don't let this stage distract you,  I'm completely ordinary.    </seg>
<seg id="144"> I'm not an exception.    </seg>
<seg id="145"> My story is not unusual.    </seg>
<seg id="146"> I am as ordinary as they come.    </seg>
<seg id="147"> When you look at Muslims around the world --  and I've done this, I've done the largest study ever done  on Muslims around the world --  people want ordinary things.    </seg>
<seg id="148"> They want prosperity for their family,  they want jobs  and they want to live in peace.    </seg>
<seg id="149"> So I am not in any way an exception.    </seg>
<seg id="150"> When you meet people who seem like an exception to the rule,  oftentimes it's that the rule is broken,  not that they're an exception to it.    </seg>
<seg id="151"> HW: Thank you so much. Dalia Mogahed.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2435" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/celeste_headlee_10_ways_to_have_a_better_conversation</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: When your job hinges on how well you talk to people, you learn a lot about how to have conversations -- and that most of us don't converse very well. Celeste Headlee has worked as a radio host for decades, and she knows the ingredients of a great conversation: Honesty, brevity, clarity and a healthy amount of listening. In this insightful talk, she shares 10 useful rules for having better conversations. "Go out, talk to people, listen to people," she says. "And, most importantly, be prepared to be amazed."</description> 
<keywords>talks, TEDx, communication, interview, language, personal growth</keywords> 
<talkid>2435</talkid> 
<title>Celeste Headlee: 10 ways to have a better conversation</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> All right, I want to see a show of hands:  how many of you have unfriended someone on Facebook  because they said something offensive about politics or religion,  childcare, food?    </seg>
<seg id="2">   And how many of you know at least one person that you avoid  because you just don't want to talk to them?    </seg>
<seg id="3">   You know, it used to be that in order to have a polite conversation,  we just had to follow the advice of Henry Higgins in "My Fair Lady":  Stick to the weather and your health.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> But these days, with climate change and anti-vaxxing, those subjects --    are not safe either.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> So this world that we live in,  this world in which every conversation  has the potential to devolve into an argument,  where our politicians can't speak to one another  and where even the most trivial of issues  have someone fighting both passionately for it and against it, it's not normal.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Pew Research did a study of 10,000 American adults,  and they found that at this moment, we are more polarized,  we are more divided,  than we ever have been in history.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> We're less likely to compromise,  which means we're not listening to each other.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And we make decisions about where to live,  who to marry and even who our friends are going to be,  based on what we already believe.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Again, that means we're not listening to each other.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> A conversation requires a balance between talking and listening,  and somewhere along the way, we lost that balance.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Now, part of that is due to technology.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> The smartphones that you all either have in your hands  or close enough that you could grab them really quickly.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> According to Pew Research,  about a third of American teenagers send more than a hundred texts a day.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> And many of them, almost most of them, are more likely to text their friends  than they are to talk to them face to face.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> There's this great piece in The Atlantic.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> It was written by a high school teacher named Paul Barnwell.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And he gave his kids a communication project.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> He wanted to teach them how to speak on a specific subject without using notes.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And he said this: "I came to realize..."    </seg>
<seg id="20">   "I came to realize that conversational competence  might be the single most overlooked skill we fail to teach.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Kids spend hours each day engaging with ideas and each other through screens,  but rarely do they have an opportunity  to hone their interpersonal communications skills.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> It might sound like a funny question, but we have to ask ourselves:  Is there any 21st-century skill  more important than being able to sustain coherent, confident conversation?"    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Now, I make my living talking to people:  Nobel Prize winners, truck drivers,  billionaires, kindergarten teachers,  heads of state, plumbers.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> I talk to people that I like. I talk to people that I don't like.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> I talk to some people that I disagree with deeply on a personal level.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> But I still have a great conversation with them.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> So I'd like to spend the next 10 minutes or so teaching you how to talk  and how to listen.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Many of you have already heard a lot of advice on this,  things like look the person in the eye,  think of interesting topics to discuss in advance,  look, nod and smile to show that you're paying attention,  repeat back what you just heard or summarize it.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> So I want you to forget all of that. It is crap.    </seg>
<seg id="30">   There is no reason to learn how to show you're paying attention  if you are in fact paying attention.    </seg>
<seg id="31">     Now, I actually use the exact same skills as a professional interviewer  that I do in regular life.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> So, I'm going to teach you how to interview people,  and that's actually going to help you learn how to be better conversationalists.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Learn to have a conversation  without wasting your time, without getting bored,  and, please God, without offending anybody.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> We've all had really great conversations.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> We've had them before. We know what it's like.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> The kind of conversation where you walk away feeling engaged and inspired,  or where you feel like you've made a real connection  or you've been perfectly understood.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> There is no reason  why most of your interactions can't be like that.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> So I have 10 basic rules. I'm going to walk you through all of them,  but honestly, if you just choose one of them and master it,  you'll already enjoy better conversations.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Number one: Don't multitask.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> And I don't mean just set down your cell phone  or your tablet or your car keys or whatever is in your hand.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> I mean, be present.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> Be in that moment.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Don't think about your argument you had with your boss.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Don't think about what you're going to have for dinner.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> If you want to get out of the conversation,  get out of the conversation,  but don't be half in it and half out of it.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Number two: Don't pontificate.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> If you want to state your opinion  without any opportunity for response or argument or pushback or growth,  write a blog.    </seg>
<seg id="48">   Now, there's a really good reason why I don't allow pundits on my show:  Because they're really boring.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> If they're conservative, they're going to hate Obama and food stamps and abortion.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> If they're liberal, they're going to hate  big banks and oil corporations and Dick Cheney.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Totally predictable.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> And you don't want to be like that.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> You need to enter every conversation assuming that you have something to learn.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> The famed therapist M. Scott Peck said  that true listening requires a setting aside of oneself.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And sometimes that means setting aside your personal opinion.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> He said that sensing this acceptance,  the speaker will become less and less vulnerable  and more and more likely to open up the inner recesses  of his or her mind to the listener.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Again, assume that you have something to learn.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> Bill Nye: "Everyone you will ever meet knows something that you don't."    </seg>
<seg id="59"> I put it this way:  Everybody is an expert in something.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Number three: Use open-ended questions.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> In this case, take a cue from journalists.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Start your questions with who, what, when, where, why or how.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> If you put in a complicated question, you're going to get a simple answer out.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> If I ask you, "Were you terrified?"    </seg>
<seg id="65"> you're going to respond to the most powerful word in that sentence,  which is "terrified," and the answer is "Yes, I was" or "No, I wasn't."    </seg>
<seg id="66"> "Were you angry?" "Yes, I was very angry."    </seg>
<seg id="67"> Let them describe it. They're the ones that know.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Try asking them things like, "What was that like?"    </seg>
<seg id="69"> "How did that feel?"    </seg>
<seg id="70"> Because then they might have to stop for a moment and think about it,  and you're going to get a much more interesting response.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Number four: Go with the flow.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> That means thoughts will come into your mind  and you need to let them go out of your mind.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> We've heard interviews often  in which a guest is talking for several minutes  and then the host comes back in and asks a question  which seems like it comes out of nowhere, or it's already been answered.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> That means the host probably stopped listening two minutes ago  because he thought of this really clever question,  and he was just bound and determined to say that.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> And we do the exact same thing.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> We're sitting there having a conversation with someone,  and then we remember that time that we met Hugh Jackman in a coffee shop.    </seg>
<seg id="77">   And we stop listening.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> Stories and ideas are going to come to you.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> You need to let them come and let them go.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Number five: If you don't know, say that you don't know.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Now, people on the radio, especially on NPR,  are much more aware that they're going on the record,  and so they're more careful about what they claim to be an expert in  and what they claim to know for sure.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> Do that. Err on the side of caution.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> Talk should not be cheap.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Number six: Don't equate your experience with theirs.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> If they're talking about having lost a family member,  don't start talking about the time you lost a family member.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> If they're talking about the trouble they're having at work,  don't tell them about how much you hate your job.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> It's not the same. It is never the same.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> All experiences are individual.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> And, more importantly, it is not about you.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> You don't need to take that moment to prove how amazing you are  or how much you've suffered.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> Somebody asked Stephen Hawking once what his IQ was, and he said,  "I have no idea. People who brag about their IQs are losers."    </seg>
<seg id="92">   Conversations are not a promotional opportunity.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> Number seven:  Try not to repeat yourself. It's condescending, and it's really boring,  and we tend to do it a lot.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> Especially in work conversations or in conversations with our kids,  we have a point to make,  so we just keep rephrasing it over and over.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> Don't do that.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> Number eight: Stay out of the weeds.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> Frankly, people don't care  about the years, the names,  the dates, all those details  that you're struggling to come up with in your mind.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> They don't care. What they care about is you.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> They care about what you're like,  what you have in common.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> So forget the details. Leave them out.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> Number nine:  This is not the last one, but it is the most important one.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> Listen.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> I cannot tell you how many really important people have said  that listening is perhaps the most, the number one most important skill  that you could develop.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> Buddha said, and I'm paraphrasing,  "If your mouth is open, you're not learning."    </seg>
<seg id="105"> And Calvin Coolidge said, "No man ever listened his way out of a job."    </seg>
<seg id="106">   Why do we not listen to each other?    </seg>
<seg id="107"> Number one, we'd rather talk.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> When I'm talking, I'm in control.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> I don't have to hear anything I'm not interested in.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> I'm the center of attention.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> I can bolster my own identity.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> But there's another reason:  We get distracted.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> The average person talks at about 225 word per minute,  but we can listen at up to 500 words per minute.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> So our minds are filling in those other 275 words.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> And look, I know, it takes effort and energy  to actually pay attention to someone,  but if you can't do that, you're not in a conversation.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> You're just two people shouting out barely related sentences  in the same place.    </seg>
<seg id="117">   You have to listen to one another.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> Stephen Covey said it very beautifully.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> He said, "Most of us don't listen with the intent to understand.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> We listen with the intent to reply."    </seg>
<seg id="121"> One more rule, number 10, and it's this one: Be brief.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> [A good conversation is like a miniskirt; short enough to retain interest,  but long enough to cover the subject. -- My Sister]      All of this boils down to the same basic concept, and it is this one:  Be interested in other people.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> You know, I grew up with a very famous grandfather,  and there was kind of a ritual in my home.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> People would come over to talk to my grandparents,  and after they would leave, my mother would come over to us,  and she'd say, "Do you know who that was?    </seg>
<seg id="125"> She was the runner-up to Miss America.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> He was the mayor of Sacramento.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> She won a Pulitzer Prize. He's a Russian ballet dancer."    </seg>
<seg id="128"> And I kind of grew up assuming  everyone has some hidden, amazing thing about them.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> And honestly, I think it's what makes me a better host.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> I keep my mouth shut as often as I possibly can,  I keep my mind open,  and I'm always prepared to be amazed,  and I'm never disappointed.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> You do the same thing.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> Go out, talk to people,  listen to people,  and, most importantly, be prepared to be amazed.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> Thanks.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2429" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/jocelyne_bloch_the_brain_may_be_able_to_repair_itself_with_help</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Through treating everything from strokes to car accident traumas, neurosurgeon Jocelyne Bloch knows the brain's inability to repair itself all too well. But now, she suggests, she and her colleagues may have found the key to neural repair: Doublecortin-positive cells. Similar to stem cells, they are extremely adaptable and, when extracted from a brain, cultured and then re-injected in a lesioned area of the same brain, they can help repair and rebuild it. "With a little help," Bloch says, "the brain may be able to help itself."</description> 
<keywords>talks, Surgery, brain, health, medical research, medicine, mind, neuroscience, science</keywords> 
<talkid>2429</talkid> 
<title>Jocelyne Bloch: The brain may be able to repair itself -- with help</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> So I'm a neurosurgeon.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> And like most of my colleagues,  I have to deal, every day, with human tragedies.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I realize how your life can change from one second to the other  after a major stroke or after a car accident.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> And what is very frustrating for us neurosurgeons  is to realize that unlike other organs of the body,  the brain has very little ability for self-repair.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> And after a major injury of your central nervous system,  the patients often remain with a severe handicap.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> And that's probably the reason why I've chosen  to be a functional neurosurgeon.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> What is a functional neurosurgeon?    </seg>
<seg id="8"> It's a doctor who is trying to improve a neurological function  through different surgical strategies.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> You've certainly heard of one of the famous ones  called deep brain stimulation,  where you implant an electrode in the depths of the brain  in order to modulate a circuit of neurons  to improve a neurological function.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> It's really an amazing technology  in that it has improved the destiny of patients  with Parkinson's disease,  with severe tremor, with severe pain.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> However, neuromodulation does not mean neuro-repair.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> And the dream of functional neurosurgeons  is to repair the brain.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> I think  that we are approaching this dream.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> And I would like to show you  that we are very close to this.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> And that with a little bit of help,  the brain is able to help itself.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> So the story started 15 years ago.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> At that time, I was a chief resident  working days and nights in the emergency room.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> I often had to take care of patients with head trauma.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> You have to imagine that when a patient comes in with a severe head trauma,  his brain is swelling  and he's increasing his intracranial pressure.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And in order to save his life,  you have to decrease this intracranial pressure.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> And to do that,  you sometimes have to remove a piece of swollen brain.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> So instead of throwing away these pieces of swollen brain,  we decided with Jean-François Brunet,  who is a colleague of mine, a biologist,  to study them.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> What do I mean by that?    </seg>
<seg id="24"> We wanted to grow cells from these pieces of tissue.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> It's not an easy task.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Growing cells from a piece of tissue  is a bit the same as growing very small children  out from their family.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> So you need to find the right nutrients,  the warmth, the humidity  and all the nice environments to make them thrive.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> So that's exactly what we had to do with these cells.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> And after many attempts,  Jean-François did it.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> And that's what he saw under his microscope.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> And that was, for us, a major surprise.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Why?    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Because this looks exactly the same as a stem cell culture,  with large green cells surrounding small, immature cells.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> And you may remember from biology class  that stem cells are immature cells,  able to turn into any type of cell of the body.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> The adult brain has stem cells, but they're very rare  and they're located in deep and small niches  in the depths of the brain.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> So it was surprising to get this kind of stem cell culture  from the superficial part of swollen brain we had  in the operating theater.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> And there was another intriguing observation:  Regular stem cells are very active cells --  cells that divide, divide, divide very quickly.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And they never die, they're immortal cells.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> But these cells behave differently.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> They divide slowly,  and after a few weeks of culture,  they even died.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> So we were in front of a strange new cell population  that looked like stem cells but behaved differently.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> And it took us a long time to understand where they came from.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> They come from these cells.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> These blue and red cells are called doublecortin-positive cells.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> All of you have them in your brain.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> They represent four percent of your cortical brain cells.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> They have a very important role during the development stage.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> When you were fetuses,  they helped your brain to fold itself.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> But why do they stay in your head?    </seg>
<seg id="50"> This, we don't know.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> We think that they may participate in brain repair  because we find them in higher concentration  close to brain lesions.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> But it's not so sure.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> But there is one clear thing --  that from these cells,  we got our stem cell culture.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And we were in front of a potential new source of cells  to repair the brain.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And we had to prove this.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> So to prove it,  we decided to design an experimental paradigm.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> The idea was to biopsy a piece of brain  in a non-eloquent area of the brain,  and then to culture the cells  exactly the way Jean-François did it in his lab.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> And then label them, to put color in them  in order to be able to track them in the brain.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> And the last step was to re-implant them  in the same individual.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> We call these  autologous grafts -- autografts.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> So the first question we had,  "What will happen if we re-implant these cells in a normal brain,  and what will happen if we re-implant the same cells  in a lesioned brain?"    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Thanks to the help of professor Eric Rouiller,  we worked with monkeys.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> So in the first-case scenario,  we re-implanted the cells in the normal brain  and what we saw is that they completely disappeared after a few weeks,  as if they were taken from the brain,  they go back home,  the space is already busy,  they are not needed there, so they disappear.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> In the second-case scenario,  we performed the lesion,  we re-implanted exactly the same cells,  and in this case, the cells remained --  and they became mature neurons.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> And that's the image of what we could observe under the microscope.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Those are the cells that were re-implanted.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> And the proof they carry,  these little spots, those are the cells that we've labeled  in vitro, when they were in culture.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> But we could not stop here, of course.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Do these cells also help a monkey to recover after a lesion?    </seg>
<seg id="70"> So for that, we trained monkeys to perform a manual dexterity task.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> They had to retrieve food pellets from a tray.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> They were very good at it.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> And when they had reached a plateau of performance,  we did a lesion in the motor cortex corresponding to the hand motion.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> So the monkeys were plegic,  they could not move their hand anymore.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> And exactly the same as humans would do,  they spontaneously recovered to a certain extent,  exactly the same as after a stroke.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Patients are completely plegic,  and then they try to recover due to a brain plasticity mechanism,  they recover to a certain extent,  exactly the same for the monkey.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> So when we were sure that the monkey had reached his plateau  of spontaneous recovery,  we implanted his own cells.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> So on the left side, you see the monkey that has spontaneously recovered.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> He's at about 40 to 50 percent of his previous performance  before the lesion.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> He's not so accurate, not so quick.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> And look now, when we re-impant the cells:  Two months after re-implantation, the same individual.    </seg>
<seg id="82">   It was also very exciting results for us, I tell you.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> Since that time, we've understood much more about these cells.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> We know that we can cryopreserve them,  we can use them later on.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> We know that we can apply them in other neuropathological models,  like Parkinson's disease, for example.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> But our dream is still to implant them in humans.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> And I really hope that I'll be able to show you soon  that the human brain is giving us the tools to repair itself.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="89">   Bruno Giussani: Jocelyne, this is amazing,  and I'm sure that right now, there are several dozen people in the audience,  possibly even a majority,  who are thinking, "I know somebody who can use this."    </seg>
<seg id="90"> I do, in any case.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> And of course the question is,  what are the biggest obstacles  before you can go into human clinical trials?    </seg>
<seg id="92"> Jocelyne Bloch: The biggest obstacles are regulations.   So, from these exciting results, you need to fill out  about two kilograms of papers and forms  to be able to go through these kind of trials.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> BG: Which is understandable, the brain is delicate, etc.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> JB: Yes, it is, but it takes a long time  and a lot of patience and almost a professional team to do it, you know?    </seg>
<seg id="95"> BG: If you project yourself --  having done the research  and having tried to get permission to start the trials,  if you project yourself out in time,  how many years before somebody gets into a hospital  and this therapy is available?    </seg>
<seg id="96"> JB: So, it's very difficult to say.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> It depends, first, on the approval of the trial.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> Will the regulation allow us to do it soon?    </seg>
<seg id="99"> And then, you have to perform this kind of study  in a small group of patients.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> So it takes, already, a long time to select the patients,  do the treatment  and evaluate if it's useful to do this kind of treatment.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> And then you have to deploy this to a multicentric trial.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> You have to really prove first that it's useful  before offering this treatment up for everybody.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> BG: And safe, of course. JB: Of course.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> BG: Jocelyne, thank you for coming to TED and sharing this.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> BG: Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2425" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/pardis_sabeti_how_we_ll_fight_the_next_deadly_virus</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: When Ebola broke out in March 2014, Pardis Sabeti and her team got to work sequencing the virus's genome, learning how it mutated and spread. Sabeti immediately released her research online, so virus trackers and scientists from around the world could join in the urgent fight. In this talk, she shows how open cooperation was key to halting the virus ... and to attacking the next one to come along. "We had to work openly, we had to share and we had to work together," Sabeti says. "Let us not let the world be defined by the destruction wrought by one virus, but illuminated by billions of hearts and minds working in unity."</description> 
<keywords>talks, Africa, big problems, disease, ebola, future, genetics, global issues, health, humanity, illness, innovation, medical research, medicine, pandemic, public health, science</keywords> 
<talkid>2425</talkid> 
<title>Pardis Sabeti: How we'll fight the next deadly virus</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> You may never have heard of Kenema, Sierra Leone  or Arua, Nigeria.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> But I know them as two of the most extraordinary places on earth.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> In hospitals there, there's a community of nurses, physicians and scientists  that have been quietly battling  one of the deadliest threats to humanity for years:  Lassa virus.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Lassa virus is a lot like Ebola.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> It can cause a severe fever and can often be fatal.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> But these individuals, they risk their lives every day  to protect the individuals in their communities,  and by doing so, protect us all.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> But one of the most extraordinary things I learned about them  on one of my first visits out there many years ago  was that they start each morning --  these challenging, extraordinary days on the front lines -- by singing.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> They gather together, and they show their joy.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> They show their spirit.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And over the years,  from year after year as I've visited them and they've visited me,  I get to gather with them and I sing  and we write and we love it,  because it reminds us that we're not just there to pursue science together;  we're bonded through a shared humanity.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And that of course, as you can imagine, becomes extremely important,  even essential, as things begin to change.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> And that changed a great deal in March of 2014,  when the Ebola outbreak was declared in Guinea.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> This is the first outbreak in West Africa,  near the border of Sierra Leone and Liberia.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> And it was frightening, frightening for us all.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> We had actually suspected for some time  that Lassa and Ebola were more widespread than thought,  and we thought it could one day come to Kenema.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> And so members of my team immediately went out  and joined Dr. Humarr Khan and his team there,  and we set up diagnostics to be able to have sensitive molecular tests  to pick up Ebola if it came across the border  and into Sierra Leone.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> We'd already set up this kind of capacity for Lassa virus,  we knew how to do it,  the team is outstanding.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> We just had to give them the tools and place to survey for Ebola.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And unfortunately, that day came.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> On May 23, 2014, a woman checked into the maternity ward at the hospital,  and the team ran those important molecular tests  and they identified the first confirmed case of Ebola in Sierra Leone.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> This was an exceptional work that was done.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> They were able to diagnose the case immediately,  to safely treat the patient  and to begin to do contact tracing to follow what was going on.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> It could've stopped something.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> But by the time that day came,  the outbreak had already been breeding for months.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> With hundreds of cases, it had already eclipsed all previous outbreaks.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> And it came into Sierra Leone not as that singular case,  but as a tidal wave.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> We had to work with the international community,  with the Ministry of Health, with Kenema, to begin to deal with the cases,  as the next week brought 31,  then 92, then 147 cases -- all coming to Kenema,  one of the only places in Sierra Leone that could deal with this.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> And we worked around the clock trying to do everything we could,  trying to help the individuals, trying to get attention,  but we also did one other simple thing.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> From that specimen that we take from a patient's blood to detect Ebola,  we can discard it, obviously.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> The other thing we can do is, actually, put in a chemical and deactivate it,  so just place it into a box and ship it across the ocean,  and that's what we did.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> We sent it to Boston, where my team works.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> And we also worked around the clock doing shift work, day after day,  and we quickly generated 99 genomes of the Ebola virus.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> This is the blueprint -- the genome of a virus is the blueprint.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> We all have one.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> It says everything that makes up us,  and it tells us so much information.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> The results of this kind of work are simple and they're powerful.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> We could actually take these 99 different viruses,  look at them and compare them,  and we could see, actually, compared to three genomes  that had been previously published from Guinea,  we could show that the outbreak emerged in Guinea months before,  once into the human population,  and from there had been transmitting from human to human.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> Now, that's incredibly important  when you're trying to figure out how to intervene,  but the important thing is contact tracing.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> We also could see that as the virus was moving between humans,  it was mutating.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> And each of those mutations are so important,  because the diagnostics, the vaccines,  the therapies that we're using,  are all based on that genome sequence, fundamentally --  that's what drives it.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> And so global health experts would need to respond,  would have to develop,  to recalibrate everything that they were doing.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> But the way that science works, the position I was in at that point  is, I had the data,  and I could have worked in a silo for many, many months,  analyzed the data carefully, slowly,  submitted the paper for publication, gone through a few back-and-forths,  and then finally when the paper came out, might release that data.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> That's the way the status quo works.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Well, that was not going to work at this point, right?    </seg>
<seg id="45"> We had friends on the front lines  and to us it was just obvious that what we needed is help,  lots of help.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> So the first thing we did is,  as soon as the sequences came off the machines,  we published it to the web.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> We just released it to the whole world and said, "Help us."    </seg>
<seg id="48"> And help came.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Before we knew it,  we were being contacted from people all over,  surprised to see the data out there and released.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Some of the greatest viral trackers in the world  were suddenly part of our community.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> We were working together in this virtual way,  sharing, regular calls, communications,  trying to follow the virus minute by minute,  to see ways that we could stop it.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> And there are so many ways that we can form communities like that.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Everybody, particularly when the outbreak started to expand globally,  was reaching out to learn, to participate, to engage.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Everybody wants to play a part.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> The amount of human capacity out there is just amazing,  and the Internet connects us all.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And could you imagine that instead of being frightened of each other,  that we all just said, "Let's do this.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Let's work together, and let's make this happen."    </seg>
<seg id="58"> But the problem is that the data that all of us are using,  Googling on the web, is just too limited to do what we need to do.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> And so many opportunities get missed when that happens.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> So in the early part of the epidemic from Kenema,  we'd had 106 clinical records from patients,  and we once again made that publicly available to the world.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> And in our own lab, we could show that you could take those 106 records,  we could train computers to predict the prognosis for Ebola patients  to near 100 percent accuracy.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> And we made an app that could release that,  to make that available to health-care workers in the field.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> But 106 is just not enough to make it powerful,  to validate it.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> So we were waiting for more data to release that.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> and the data has still not come.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> We are still waiting, tweaking away,  in silos rather than working together.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> And this just -- we can't accept that.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Right? You, all of you, cannot accept that.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> It's our lives on the line.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> And in fact, actually,  many lives were lost, many health-care workers,  including beloved colleagues of mine,  five colleagues: Mbalu Fonnie, Alex Moigboi,  Dr. Humarr Khan, Alice Kovoma and Mohamed Fullah.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> These are just five of many health-care workers  at Kenema and beyond  that died while the world waited and while we all worked,  quietly and separately.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> See, Ebola, like all threats to humanity,  it's fueled by mistrust and distraction and division.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> When we build barriers amongst ourselves and we fight amongst ourselves,  the virus thrives.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> But unlike all threats to humanity,  Ebola is one where we're actually all the same.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> We're all in this fight together.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Ebola on one person's doorstep could soon be on ours.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> And so in this place with the same vulnerabilities,  the same strengths, the same fears, the same hopes,  I hope that we work together with joy.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> A graduate student of mine was reading a book about Sierra Leone,  and she discovered that the word "Kenema,"  the hospital that we work at and the city where we work in Sierra Leone,  is named after the Mende word for "clear like a river, translucent  and open to the public gaze."    </seg>
<seg id="79"> That was really profound for us,  because without knowing it, we'd always felt  that in order to honor the individuals in Kenema where we worked,  we had to work openly, we had to share and we had to work together.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> And we have to do that.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> We all have to demand that of ourselves and others --  to be open to each other when an outbreak happens,  to fight in this fight together.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> Because this is not the first outbreak of Ebola,  it will not be the last,  and there are many other microbes out there that are lying in wait,  like Lassa virus and others.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> And the next time this happens,  it could happen in a city of millions, it could start there.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> It could be something that's transmitted through the air.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> It could even be disseminated intentionally.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> And I know that that is frightening, I understand that,  but I know also, and this experience shows us,  that we have the technology and we have the capacity  to win this thing,  to win this and have the upper hand over viruses.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> But we can only do it if we do it together  and we do it with joy.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> So for Dr. Khan  and for all of those who sacrificed their lives on the front lines  in this fight with us always,  let us be in this fight with them always.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> And let us not let the world be defined  by the destruction wrought by one virus,  but illuminated by billions of hearts and minds  working in unity.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2413" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/yanis_varoufakis_capitalism_will_eat_democracy_unless_we_speak_up</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Have you wondered why politicians aren't what they used to be, why governments seem unable to solve real problems? Economist Yanis Varoufakis, the former Minister of Finance for Greece, says that it's because you can be in politics today but not be in power -- because real power now belongs to those who control the economy. He believes that the mega-rich and corporations are cannibalizing the political sphere, causing financial crisis. In this talk, hear his dream for a world in which capital and labor no longer struggle against each other, "one that is simultaneously libertarian, Marxist and Keynesian."</description> 
<keywords>talks, Europe, United States, activism, big problems, business, capitalism, democracy, economics, finance, global issues, government, investment, leadership, money, politics, society</keywords> 
<talkid>2413</talkid> 
<title>Yanis Varoufakis: Capitalism will eat democracy -- unless we speak up</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Democracy.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> In the West,  we make a colossal mistake taking it for granted.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> We see democracy  not as the most fragile of flowers that it really is,  but we see it as part of our society's furniture.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> We tend to think of it as an intransigent given.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> We mistakenly believe that capitalism begets inevitably democracy.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> It doesn't.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Singapore's Lee Kuan Yew and his great imitators in Beijing  have demonstrated beyond reasonable doubt  that it is perfectly possible to have a flourishing capitalism,  spectacular growth,  while politics remains democracy-free.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Indeed, democracy is receding in our neck of the woods,  here in Europe.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Earlier this year, while I was representing Greece --  the newly elected Greek government --  in the Eurogroup as its Finance Minister,  I was told in no uncertain terms that our nation's democratic process --  our elections --  could not be allowed to interfere  with economic policies that were being implemented in Greece.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> At that moment,  I felt that there could be no greater vindication of Lee Kuan Yew,  or the Chinese Communist Party,  indeed of some recalcitrant friends of mine who kept telling me  that democracy would be banned if it ever threatened to change anything.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Tonight, here, I want to present to you  an economic case for an authentic democracy.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> I want to ask you to join me in believing again  that Lee Kuan Yew,  the Chinese Communist Party  and indeed the Eurogroup  are wrong in believing that we can dispense with democracy --  that we need an authentic, boisterous democracy.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> And without democracy,  our societies will be nastier,  our future bleak  and our great, new technologies wasted.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Speaking of waste,  allow me to point out an interesting paradox  that is threatening our economies as we speak.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I call it the twin peaks paradox.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> One peak you understand --  you know it, you recognize it --  is the mountain of debts that has been casting a long shadow  over the United States, Europe, the whole world.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> We all recognize the mountain of debts.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> But few people discern its twin.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> A mountain of idle cash  belonging to rich savers and to corporations,  too terrified to invest it  into the productive activities that can generate the incomes  from which you can extinguish the mountain of debts  and which can produce all those things that humanity desperately needs,  like green energy.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> Now let me give you two numbers.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Over the last three months,  in the United States, in Britain and in the Eurozone,  we have invested, collectively, 3.4 trillion dollars  on all the wealth-producing goods --  things like industrial plants, machinery,  office blocks, schools,  roads, railways, machinery, and so on and so forth.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> $3.4 trillion sounds like a lot of money  until you compare it to the $5.1 trillion  that has been slushing around in the same countries,  in our financial institutions,  doing absolutely nothing during the same period  except inflating stock exchanges and bidding up house prices.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> So a mountain of debt and a mountain of idle cash  form twin peaks, failing to cancel each other out  through the normal operation of the markets.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> The result is stagnant wages,  more than a quarter of 25- to 54-year-olds in America, in Japan and in Europe  And consequently, low aggregate demand,  which in a never-ending cycle,  reinforces the pessimism of the investors,  who, fearing low demand, reproduce it by not investing --  exactly like Oedipus' father,  who, terrified by the prophecy of the oracle  that his son would grow up to kill him,    </seg>
<seg id="25"> unwittingly engineered the conditions  that ensured that Oedipus, his son, would kill him.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> This is my quarrel with capitalism.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> Its gross wastefulness,  all this idle cash,  should be energized to improve lives,  to develop human talents,  and indeed to finance all these technologies,  green technologies,  which are absolutely essential for saving planet Earth.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Am I right in believing that democracy might be the answer?    </seg>
<seg id="29"> I believe so,  but before we move on,  what do we mean by democracy?    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Aristotle defined democracy  as the constitution in which the free and the poor,  being in the majority, control government.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Now, of course Athenian democracy excluded too many.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Women, migrants and, of course, the slaves.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> But it would be a mistake  to dismiss the significance of ancient Athenian democracy  on the basis of whom it excluded.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> What was more pertinent,  and continues to be so about ancient Athenian democracy,  was the inclusion of the working poor,  who not only acquired the right to free speech,  but more importantly, crucially,  they acquired the rights to political judgments that were afforded equal weight  in the decision-making concerning matters of state.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Now, of course, Athenian democracy didn't last long.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Like a candle that burns brightly, it burned out quickly.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> And indeed,  our liberal democracies today do not have their roots in ancient Athens.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> They have their roots in the Magna Carta,  in the 1688 Glorious Revolution,  indeed in the American constitution.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Whereas Athenian democracy was focusing on the masterless citizen  and empowering the working poor,  our liberal democracies are founded on the Magna Carta tradition,  which was, after all, a charter for masters.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> And indeed, liberal democracy only surfaced when it was possible  to separate fully the political sphere from the economic sphere,  so as to confine the democratic process fully in the political sphere,  leaving the economic sphere --  the corporate world, if you want --  as a democracy-free zone.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Now, in our democracies today,  this separation of the economic from the political sphere,  the moment it started happening,  it gave rise to an inexorable, epic struggle between the two,  with the economic sphere colonizing the political sphere,  eating into its power.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> Have you wondered why politicians are not what they used to be?    </seg>
<seg id="43"> It's not because their DNA has degenerated.    </seg>
<seg id="44">   It is rather because one can be in government today and not in power,  because power has migrated from the political to the economic sphere,  which is separate.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Indeed,  I spoke about my quarrel with capitalism.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> If you think about it,  it is a little bit like a population of predators,  that are so successful in decimating the prey that they must feed on,  that in the end they starve.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Similarly,  the economic sphere has been colonizing and cannibalizing the political sphere  to such an extent that it is undermining itself,  causing economic crisis.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Corporate power is increasing,  political goods are devaluing,  inequality is rising,  aggregate demand is falling  and CEOs of corporations are too scared to invest the cash of their corporations.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> So the more capitalism succeeds in taking the demos out of democracy,  the taller the twin peaks  and the greater the waste of human resources  and humanity's wealth.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Clearly, if this is right,  we must reunite the political and economic spheres  and better do it with a demos being in control,  like in ancient Athens except without the slaves  or the exclusion of women and migrants.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Now, this is not an original idea.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> The Marxist left had that idea 100 years ago  and it didn't go very well, did it?    </seg>
<seg id="53"> The lesson that we learned from the Soviet debacle  is that only by a miracle will the working poor be reempowered,  as they were in ancient Athens,  without creating new forms of brutality and waste.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> But there is a solution:  eliminate the working poor.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Capitalism's doing it  by replacing low-wage workers with automata, androids, robots.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> The problem is  that as long as the economic and the political spheres are separate,  automation makes the twin peaks taller,  the waste loftier  and the social conflicts deeper,  including --  soon, I believe --  in places like China.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> So we need to reconfigure,  we need to reunite the economic and the political spheres,  but we'd better do it by democratizing the reunified sphere,  lest we end up with a surveillance-mad hyperautocracy  that makes The Matrix, the movie, look like a documentary.    </seg>
<seg id="58">   So the question is not whether capitalism will survive  the technological innovations it is spawning.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> The more interesting question  is whether capitalism will be succeeded by something resembling a Matrix dystopia  or something much closer to a Star Trek-like society,  where machines serve the humans  and the humans expend their energies exploring the universe  and indulging in long debates about the meaning of life  in some ancient, Athenian-like, high tech agora.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> I think we can afford to be optimistic.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> But what would it take,  what would it look like  to have this Star Trek-like utopia, instead of the Matrix-like dystopia?    </seg>
<seg id="62"> In practical terms,  allow me to share just briefly,  a couple of examples.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> At the level of the enterprise,  imagine a capital market,  where you earn capital as you work,  and where your capital follows you from one job to another,  from one company to another,  and the company -- whichever one you happen to work at at that time --  is solely owned by those who happen to work in it at that moment.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> Then all income stems from capital, from profits,  and the very concept of wage labor becomes obsolete.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> No more separation between those who own but do not work in the company  and those who work but do not own the company;  no more tug-of-war between capital and labor;  no great gap between investment and saving;  indeed, no towering twin peaks.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> At the level of the global political economy,  imagine for a moment  that our national currencies have a free-floating exchange rate,  with a universal, global, digital currency,  one that is issued by the International Monetary Fund,  the G-20,  on behalf of all humanity.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> And imagine further  that all international trade is denominated in this currency --  let's call it "the cosmos,"  in units of cosmos --  with every government agreeing to be paying into a common fund  a sum of cosmos units proportional to the country's trade deficit,  or indeed to a country's trade surplus.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> And imagine that that fund is utilized to invest in green technologies,  especially in parts of the world where investment funding is scarce.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> This is not a new idea.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> It's what, effectively, John Maynard Keynes proposed  in 1944 at the Bretton Woods Conference.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> The problem is  that back then, they didn't have the technology to implement it.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Now we do,  especially in the context of a reunified political-economic sphere.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> The world that I am describing to you  is simultaneously libertarian,  in that it prioritizes empowered individuals,  Marxist,  since it will have confined to the dustbin of history  the division between capital and labor,  and Keynesian,  global Keynesian.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> But above all else,  it is a world in which we will be able to imagine an authentic democracy.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> Will such a world dawn?    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Or shall we descend into a Matrix-like dystopia?    </seg>
<seg id="77"> The answer lies in the political choice that we shall be making collectively.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> It is our choice,  and we'd better make it democratically.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="80">   Bruno Giussani: Yanis ...    </seg>
<seg id="81"> It was you who described yourself in your bios as a libertarian Marxist.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> What is the relevance of Marx's analysis today?    </seg>
<seg id="83"> Yanis Varoufakis: Well, if there was any relevance in what I just said,  then Marx is relevant.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Because the whole point of reunifying the political and economic is --  if we don't do it,  then technological innovation is going to create  such a massive fall in aggregate demand,  what Larry Summers refers to as secular stagnation.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> With this crisis migrating from one part of the world,  as it is now,  it will destabilize not only our democracies,  but even the emerging world that is not that keen on liberal democracy.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> So if this analysis holds water, then Marx is absolutely relevant.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> But so is Hayek,  that's why I'm a libertarian Marxist,  and so is Keynes,  so that's why I'm totally confused.    </seg>
<seg id="88">   BG: Indeed, and possibly we are too, now.    </seg>
<seg id="89">     YV: If you are not confused, you are not thinking, OK?    </seg>
<seg id="90"> BG: That's a very, very Greek philosopher kind of thing to say --  YV: That was Einstein, actually --  BG: During your talk you mentioned Singapore and China,  and last night at the speaker dinner,  you expressed a pretty strong opinion about how the West looks at China.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> Would you like to share that?    </seg>
<seg id="92"> YV: Well, there's a great degree of hypocrisy.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> In our liberal democracies, we have a semblance of democracy.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> It's because we have confined, as I was saying in my talk,  democracy to the political sphere,  while leaving the one sphere where all the action is --  the economic sphere -- a completely democracy-free zone.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> In a sense,  if I am allowed to be provocative,  China today is closer to Britain in the 19th century.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> Because remember,  we tend to associate liberalism with democracy --  that's a mistake, historically.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> Liberalism, liberal, it's like John Stuart Mill.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> John Stuart Mill was particularly skeptical about the democratic process.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> So what you are seeing now in China is a very similar process  to the one that we had in Britain during the Industrial Revolution,  especially the transition from the first to the second.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> And to be castigating China  for doing that which the West did in the 19th century,  smacks of hypocrisy.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> BG: I am sure that many people here are wondering about your experience  as the Finance Minister of Greece earlier this year.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> YV: I knew this was coming. BG: Yes.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> BG: Six months after,  how do you look back at the first half of the year?    </seg>
<seg id="104"> YV: Extremely exciting, from a personal point of view,  and very disappointing,  because we had an opportunity to reboot the Eurozone.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> Not just Greece, the Eurozone.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> To move away from the complacency  and the constant denial that there was a massive --  and there is a massive architectural fault line  going through the Eurozone,  which is threatening, massively, the whole of the European Union process.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> We had an opportunity on the basis of the Greek program --  which by the way,  was the first program to manifest that denial --  And, unfortunately,  the powers in the Eurozone,  in the Eurogroup,  chose to maintain denial.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> But you know what happens.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> This is the experience of the Soviet Union.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> When you try to keep alive  an economic system that architecturally cannot survive,  through political will and through authoritarianism,  you may succeed in prolonging it,  but when change happens  it happens very abruptly and catastrophically.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> BG: What kind of change are you foreseeing?    </seg>
<seg id="112"> YV: Well, there's no doubt  that if we don't change the architecture of the Eurozone,  the Eurozone has no future.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> BG: Did you make any mistakes when you were Finance Minister?    </seg>
<seg id="114"> YV: Every day.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> BG: For example? YV: Anybody who looks back --    No, but seriously.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> If there's any Minister of Finance, or of anything else for that matter,  who tells you after six months in a job,  especially in such a stressful situation,  that they have made no mistake, they're dangerous people.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> Of course I made mistakes.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> The greatest mistake was to sign the application  for the extension of a loan agreement  in the end of February.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> I was imagining  that there was a genuine interest on the side of the creditors  to find common ground.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> And there wasn't.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> They were simply interested in crushing our government,  just because they did not want  to have to deal with the architectural fault lines  that were running through the Eurozone.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> And because they didn't want to admit  that for five years they were implementing a catastrophic program in Greece.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> We lost one-third of our nominal GDP.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> This is worse than the Great Depression.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> And no one has come clean  from the troika of lenders that have been imposing this policy  to say, "This was a colossal mistake."    </seg>
<seg id="126"> BG: Despite all this,  and despite the aggressiveness of the discussion,  you seem to be remaining quite pro-European.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> YV: Absolutely.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> Look, my criticism of the European Union and the Eurozone  comes from a person who lives and breathes Europe.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> My greatest fear is that the Eurozone will not survive.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> Because if it doesn't,  the centrifugal forces that will be unleashed  will be demonic,  and they will destroy the European Union.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> And that will be catastrophic not just for Europe  but for the whole global economy.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> We are probably the largest economy in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> And if we allow ourselves  to fall into a route of the postmodern 1930's,  which seems to me to be what we are doing,  then that will be detrimental  to the future of Europeans and non-Europeans alike.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> BG: We definitely hope you are wrong on that point.    </seg>
<seg id="135"> Yanis, thank you for coming to TED.    </seg>
<seg id="136"> YV: Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
</srcset>
</mteval>
