<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mteval>
<srcset setid="iwslt2017-tst2015-16" srclang="english">
<doc docid="2361" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/daniel_levitin_how_to_stay_calm_when_you_know_you_ll_be_stressed</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: You're not at your best when you're stressed. In fact, your brain has evolved over millennia to release cortisol in stressful situations, inhibiting rational, logical thinking but potentially helping you survive, say, being attacked by a lion. Neuroscientist Daniel Levitin thinks there's a way to avoid making critical mistakes in stressful situations, when your thinking becomes clouded -- the pre-mortem. "We all are going to fail now and then," he says. "The idea is to think ahead to what those failures might be."</description> 
<keywords>talks, brain, cognitive science, health, medicine, memory, mental health, neuroscience</keywords> 
<talkid>2361</talkid> 
<title>Daniel Levitin: How to stay calm when you know you'll be stressed</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> A few years ago, I broke into my own house.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I had just driven home,  it was around midnight in the dead of Montreal winter,  I had been visiting my friend, Jeff, across town,  and the thermometer on the front porch read minus 40 degrees --  and don't bother asking if that's Celsius or Fahrenheit,  minus 40 is where the two scales meet --  it was very cold.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> And as I stood on the front porch fumbling in my pockets,  I found I didn't have my keys.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> In fact, I could see them through the window,  lying on the dining room table where I had left them.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> So I quickly ran around and tried all the other doors and windows,  and they were locked tight.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> I thought about calling a locksmith -- at least I had my cellphone,  but at midnight, it could take a while for a locksmith to show up,  and it was cold.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> I couldn't go back to my friend Jeff's house for the night  because I had an early flight to Europe the next morning,  and I needed to get my passport and my suitcase.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> So, desperate and freezing cold,  I found a large rock and I broke through the basement window,  cleared out the shards of glass,  I crawled through,  I found a piece of cardboard and taped it up over the opening,  figuring that in the morning, on the way to the airport,  I could call my contractor and ask him to fix it.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> This was going to be expensive,  but probably no more expensive than a middle-of-the-night locksmith,  so I figured, under the circumstances, I was coming out even.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Now, I'm a neuroscientist by training  and I know a little bit about how the brain performs under stress.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> It releases cortisol that raises your heart rate,  it modulates adrenaline levels  and it clouds your thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> So the next morning,  when I woke up on too little sleep,  worrying about the hole in the window,  and a mental note that I had to call my contractor,  and the freezing temperatures,  and the meetings I had upcoming in Europe,  and, you know, with all the cortisol in my brain,  my thinking was cloudy,  but I didn't know it was cloudy because my thinking was cloudy.    </seg>
<seg id="13">   And it wasn't until I got to the airport check-in counter,  that I realized I didn't have my passport.    </seg>
<seg id="14">   So I raced home in the snow and ice, 40 minutes,  got my passport, raced back to the airport,  I made it just in time,  but they had given away my seat to someone else,  so I got stuck in the back of the plane, next to the bathrooms,  in a seat that wouldn't recline, on an eight-hour flight.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Well, I had a lot of time to think during those eight hours and no sleep.    </seg>
<seg id="16">   And I started wondering, are there things that I can do,  systems that I can put into place,  that will prevent bad things from happening?    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Or at least if bad things happen,  will minimize the likelihood of it being a total catastrophe.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> So I started thinking about that,  but my thoughts didn't crystallize until about a month later.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> I was having dinner with my colleague, Danny Kahneman, the Nobel Prize winner,  and I somewhat embarrassedly told him about having broken my window,  and, you know, forgotten my passport,  and Danny shared with me  that he'd been practicing something called prospective hindsight.    </seg>
<seg id="20">   It's something that he had gotten from the psychologist Gary Klein,  who had written about it a few years before,  also called the pre-mortem.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Now, you all know what the postmortem is.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Whenever there's a disaster,  a team of experts come in and they try to figure out what went wrong, right?    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Well, in the pre-mortem, Danny explained,  you look ahead and you try to figure out all the things that could go wrong,  and then you try to figure out what you can do  to prevent those things from happening, or to minimize the damage.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> So what I want to talk to you about today  are some of the things we can do in the form of a pre-mortem.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Some of them are obvious, some of them are not so obvious.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> I'll start with the obvious ones.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> Around the home, designate a place for things that are easily lost.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Now, this sounds like common sense, and it is,  but there's a lot of science to back this up,  based on the way our spatial memory works.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> There's a structure in the brain called the hippocampus,  that evolved over tens of thousands of years,  to keep track of the locations of important things --  where the well is, where fish can be found,  that stand of fruit trees,  where the friendly and enemy tribes live.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> The hippocampus is the part of the brain  that in London taxicab drivers becomes enlarged.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> It's the part of the brain that allows squirrels to find their nuts.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> And if you're wondering, somebody actually did the experiment  where they cut off the olfactory sense of the squirrels,  and they could still find their nuts.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> They weren't using smell, they were using the hippocampus,  this exquisitely evolved mechanism in the brain for finding things.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> But it's really good for things that don't move around much,  not so good for things that move around.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> So this is why we lose car keys and reading glasses and passports.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> So in the home, designate a spot for your keys --  a hook by the door, maybe a decorative bowl.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> For your passport, a particular drawer.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> For your reading glasses, a particular table.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> If you designate a spot and you're scrupulous about it,  your things will always be there when you look for them.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> What about travel?    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Take a cell phone picture of your credit cards,  your driver's license, your passport,  mail it to yourself so it's in the cloud.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> If these things are lost or stolen, you can facilitate replacement.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Now these are some rather obvious things.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Remember, when you're under stress, the brain releases cortisol.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Cortisol is toxic, and it causes cloudy thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> So part of the practice of the pre-mortem  is to recognize that under stress you're not going to be at your best,  and you should put systems in place.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> And there's perhaps no more stressful a situation  than when you're confronted with a medical decision to make.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> And at some point, all of us are going to be in that position,  where we have to make a very important decision  about the future of our medical care or that of a loved one,  to help them with a decision.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> And so I want to talk about that.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> And I'm going to talk about a very particular medical condition.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> But this stands as a proxy for all kinds of medical decision-making,  and indeed for financial decision-making, and social decision-making --  any kind of decision you have to make  that would benefit from a rational assessment of the facts.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> So suppose you go to your doctor and the doctor says,  "I just got your lab work back, your cholesterol's a little high."    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Now, you all know that high cholesterol  is associated with an increased risk of cardiovascular disease,  heart attack, stroke.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And so you're thinking  having high cholesterol isn't the best thing,  and so the doctor says, "You know, I'd like to give you a drug  that will help you lower your cholesterol, a statin."    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And you've probably heard of statins,  you know that they're among the most widely prescribed drugs in the world today,  you probably even know people who take them.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And so you're thinking, "Yeah! Give me the statin."    </seg>
<seg id="57"> But there's a question you should ask at this point,  a statistic you should ask for  that most doctors don't like talking about,  and pharmaceutical companies like talking about even less.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> It's for the number needed to treat.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Now, what is this, the NNT?    </seg>
<seg id="60"> It's the number of people that need to take a drug  or undergo a surgery or any medical procedure  before one person is helped.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> And you're thinking, what kind of crazy statistic is that?    </seg>
<seg id="62"> The number should be one.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> My doctor wouldn't prescribe something to me  if it's not going to help.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> But actually, medical practice doesn't work that way.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> And it's not the doctor's fault,  if it's anybody's fault, it's the fault of scientists like me.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> We haven't figured out the underlying mechanisms well enough.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> But GlaxoSmithKline estimates  that 90 percent of the drugs work in only 30 to 50 percent of the people.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> So the number needed to treat for the most widely prescribed statin,  what do you suppose it is?    </seg>
<seg id="69"> How many people have to take it before one person is helped?    </seg>
<seg id="70"> 300.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> This is according to research  by research practitioners Jerome Groopman and Pamela Hartzband,  independently confirmed by Bloomberg.com.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> I ran through the numbers myself.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> 300 people have to take the drug for a year  before one heart attack, stroke or other adverse event is prevented.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Now you're probably thinking,  "Well, OK, one in 300 chance of lowering my cholesterol.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> Why not, doc? Give me the prescription anyway."    </seg>
<seg id="76"> But you should ask at this point for another statistic,  and that is, "Tell me about the side effects." Right?    </seg>
<seg id="77"> So for this particular drug,  the side effects occur in five percent of the patients.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> And they include terrible things --  debilitating muscle and joint pain, gastrointestinal distress --  but now you're thinking, "Five percent,  not very likely it's going to happen to me, I'll still take the drug."    </seg>
<seg id="79"> But wait a minute.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Remember under stress you're not thinking clearly.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> So think about how you're going to work through this ahead of time,  so you don't have to manufacture the chain of reasoning on the spot.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> 300 people take the drug, right? One person's helped,  five percent of those 300 have side effects,  that's 15 people.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> You're 15 times more likely to be harmed by the drug  than you are to be helped by the drug.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Now, I'm not saying whether you should take the statin or not.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> I'm just saying you should have this conversation with your doctor.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> Medical ethics requires it,  it's part of the principle of informed consent.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> You have the right to have access to this kind of information  to begin the conversation about whether you want to take the risks or not.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> Now you might be thinking  I've pulled this number out of the air for shock value,  but in fact it's rather typical, this number needed to treat.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> For the most widely performed surgery on men over the age of 50,  removal of the prostate for cancer,  the number needed to treat is 49.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> That's right, 49 surgeries are done for every one person who's helped.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> And the side effects in that case occur in 50 percent of the patients.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> They include impotence, erectile dysfunction,  urinary incontinence, rectal tearing,  fecal incontinence.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> And if you're lucky, and you're one of the 50 percent who has these,  they'll only last for a year or two.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> So the idea of the pre-mortem is to think ahead of time  to the questions that you might be able to ask  that will push the conversation forward.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> You don't want to have to manufacture all of this on the spot.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> And you also want to think about things like quality of life.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> Because you have a choice oftentimes,  do you I want a shorter life that's pain-free,  or a longer life that might have a great deal of pain towards the end?    </seg>
<seg id="98"> These are things to talk about and think about now,  with your family and your loved ones.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> You might change your mind in the heat of the moment,  but at least you're practiced with this kind of thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> Remember, our brain under stress releases cortisol,  and one of the things that happens at that moment  is a whole bunch on systems shut down.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> There's an evolutionary reason for this.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> Face-to-face with a predator, you don't need your digestive system,  or your libido, or your immune system,  because if you're body is expending metabolism on those things  and you don't react quickly,  you might become the lion's lunch, and then none of those things matter.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> Unfortunately,  one of the things that goes out the window during those times of stress  is rational, logical thinking,  as Danny Kahneman and his colleagues have shown.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> So we need to train ourselves to think ahead  to these kinds of situations.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> I think the important point here is recognizing that all of us are flawed.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> We all are going to fail now and then.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> The idea is to think ahead to what those failures might be,  to put systems in place that will help minimize the damage,  or to prevent the bad things from happening in the first place.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> Getting back to that snowy night in Montreal,  when I got back from my trip,  I had my contractor install a combination lock next to the door,  with a key to the front door in it, an easy to remember combination.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> And I have to admit,  I still have piles of mail that haven't been sorted,  and piles of emails that I haven't gone through.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> So I'm not completely organized,  but I see organization as a gradual process,  and I'm getting there.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2363" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/cesar_harada_how_i_teach_kids_to_love_science</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: At the Harbour School in Hong Kong, TED Senior Fellow Cesar Harada teaches citizen science and invention to the next generation of environmentalists. He's moved his classroom into an industrial mega-space where imaginative kids work with wood, metal, chemistry, biology, optics and, occasionally, power tools to create solutions to the threats facing the world's oceans. There, he instills a universal lesson that his own parents taught him at a young age: "You can make a mess, but you have to clean up after yourself."</description> 
<keywords>talks, TED Fellows, collaboration, design, education, environment, global issues, green, innovation, invention, oceans, water</keywords> 
<talkid>2363</talkid> 
<title>Cesar Harada: How I teach kids to love science</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> When I was a kid, my parents would tell me,  "You can make a mess, but you have to clean up after yourself."    </seg>
<seg id="2"> So freedom came with responsibility.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> But my imagination would take me to all these wonderful places,  where everything was possible.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> So I grew up in a bubble of innocence --  or a bubble of ignorance, I should say,  because adults would lie to us to protect us from the ugly truth.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> And growing up, I found out that adults make a mess,  and they're not very good at cleaning up after themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Fast forward, I am an adult now,  and I teach citizen science and invention at the Hong Kong Harbour School.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> And it doesn't take too long  before my students walk on a beach and stumble upon piles of trash.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> So as good citizens, we clean up the beaches --  and no, he is not drinking alcohol, and if he is, I did not give it to him.    </seg>
<seg id="9">   And so it's sad to say,  but today more than 80 percent of the oceans have plastic in them.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> It's a horrifying fact.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And in past decades,  we've been taking those big ships out and those big nets,  and we collect those plastic bits that we look at under a microscope,  and we sort them,  and then we put this data onto a map.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> But that takes forever, it's very expensive,  and so it's quite risky to take those big boats out.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> So with my students, ages six to 15,  we've been dreaming of inventing a better way.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> So we've transformed our tiny Hong Kong classroom into a workshop.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> And so we started building this small workbench,  with different heights, so even really short kids can participate.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> And let me tell you, kids with power tools are awesome and safe.    </seg>
<seg id="17">   Not really.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> And so, back to plastic.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> We collect this plastic and we grind it to the size we find it in the ocean,  which is very small because it breaks down.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And so this is how we work.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I let the imaginations of my students run wild.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> And my job is to try to collect the best of each kid's idea  and try to combine it into something that hopefully would work.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> And so we have agreed that instead of collecting plastic bits,  we are going to collect only the data.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> So we're going to get an image of the plastic with a robot --  so robots, kids get very excited.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> And the next thing we do -- we do what we call "rapid prototyping."    </seg>
<seg id="26"> We are so rapid at prototyping  that the lunch is still in the lunchbox when we're hacking it.    </seg>
<seg id="27">   And we hack table lamps and webcams, into plumbing fixtures  and we assemble that into a floating robot that will be slowly moving through water  and through the plastic that we have there --  and this is the image that we get in the robot.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> So we see the plastic pieces floating slowly through the sensor,  and the computer on board will process this image,  and measure the size of each particle,  so we have a rough estimate of how much plastic there is in the water.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> So we documented this invention step by step  on a website for inventors called Instructables,  in the hope that somebody would make it even better.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> What was really cool about this project was that the students saw a local problem,  and boom -- they are trying to immediately address it.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> [I can investigate my local problem]  But my students in Hong Kong are hyperconnected kids.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> And they watch the news, they watch the Internet,  and they came across this image.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> This was a child, probably under 10, cleaning up an oil spill bare-handed,  in the Sundarbans, which is the world's largest mangrove forest in Bangladesh.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> So they were very shocked,  because this is the water they drink, this is the water they bathe in,  this is the water they fish in -- this is the place where they live.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> And also you can see the water is brown, the mud is brown and oil is brown,  so when everything is mixed up,  it's really hard to see what's in the water.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> But, there's a technology that's rather simple,  that's called spectrometry,  that allows you see what's in the water.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> So we built a rough prototype of a spectrometer,  and you can shine light through different substances  that produce different spectrums,  so that can help you identify what's in the water.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> So we packed this prototype of a sensor,  and we shipped it to Bangladesh.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> So what was cool about this project  was that beyond addressing a local problem,  or looking at a local problem,  my students used their empathy and their sense of being creative  to help, remotely, other kids.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> [I can investigate a remote problem]  So I was very compelled by doing the second experiments,  and I wanted to take it even further --  maybe addressing an even harder problem, and it's also closer to my heart.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> So I'm half Japanese and half French,  and maybe you remember in 2011 there was a massive earthquake in Japan.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> It was so violent that it triggered several giant waves --  they are called tsunami --  and those tsunami destroyed many cities on the eastern coast of Japan.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> More than 14,000 people died in an instant.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Also, it damaged the nuclear power plant of Fukushima,  the nuclear power plant just by the water.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> And today, I read the reports  and an average of 300 tons  are leaking from the nuclear power plant into the Pacific Ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> And today the whole Pacific Ocean has traces of contamination of cesium-137.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> If you go outside on the West Coast, you can measure Fukushima everywhere.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> But if you look at the map, it can look like most of the radioactivity  has been washed away from the Japanese coast,  and most of it is now -- it looks like it's safe, it's blue.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Well, reality is a bit more complicated than this.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> So I've been going to Fukushima every year since the accident,  and I measure independently and with other scientists,  on land, in the river --  and this time we wanted to take the kids.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> So of course we didn't take the kids, the parents wouldn't allow that to happen.    </seg>
<seg id="52">   But every night we would report to "Mission Control" --  different masks they're wearing.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> It could look like they didn't take the work seriously, but they really did  because they're going to have to live with radioactivity their whole life.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And so what we did with them  is that we'd discuss the data we collected that day,  and talk about where we should be going next --  strategy, itinerary, etc...    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And to do this, we built a very rough topographical map  of the region around the nuclear power plant.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And so we built the elevation map,  we sprinkled pigments to represent real-time data for radioactivity,  and we sprayed water to simulate the rainfall.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> And with this we could see that the radioactive dust  was washing from the top of the mountain into the river system,  and leaking into the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> So it was a rough estimate.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> But with this in mind, we organized this expedition,  which was the closest civilians have been to the nuclear power plant.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> We are sailing 1.5 kilometers away from the nuclear power plant,  and with the help of the local fisherman,  we are collecting sediment from the seabed  with a custom sediment sampler we've invented and built.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> We pack the sediment into small bags,  we then dispatch them to hundreds of small bags  that we send to different universities,  and we produce the map of the seabed radioactivity,  especially in estuaries where the fish will reproduce,  and I will hope that we will have improved  the safety of the local fishermen and of your favorite sushi.    </seg>
<seg id="62">   You can see a progression here --  we've gone from a local problem to a remote problem to a global problem.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> And it's been super exciting to work at these different scales,  with also very simple, open-source technologies.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> But at the same time, it's been increasingly frustrating  because we have only started to measure the damage that we have done.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> We haven't even started to try to solve the problems.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> And so I wonder if we should just take a leap  and try to invent better ways to do all these things.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> And so the classroom started to feel a little bit small,  so we found an industrial site in Hong Kong,  and we turned it into the largest mega-space  focused on social and environmental impact.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> It's in central Hong Kong,  and it's a place we can work with wood, metal, chemistry,  a bit of biology, a bit of optics,  basically you can build pretty much everything there.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> And its a place where adults and kids can play together.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> It's a place where kids' dreams can come true,  with the help of adults,  and where adults can be kids again.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Student: Acceleration! Acceleration!    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Cesar Harada: We're asking questions such as,  can we invent the future of mobility with renewable energy?    </seg>
<seg id="73"> For example.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Or, can we help the mobility of the aging population  by transforming very standard wheelchairs into cool, electric vehicles?    </seg>
<seg id="75"> So plastic, oil and radioactivity are horrible, horrible legacies,  but the very worst legacy that we can leave our children is lies.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> We can no longer afford to shield the kids from the ugly truth  because we need their imagination to invent the solutions.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> So citizen scientists, makers, dreamers --  we must prepare the next generation  that cares about the environment and people,  and that can actually do something about it.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2319" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/dustin_yellin_a_journey_through_the_mind_of_an_artist</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Dustin Yellin makes mesmerizing artwork that tells complex, myth-inspired stories. How did he develop his style? In this disarming talk, he shares the journey of an artist -- starting from age 8 -- and his idiosyncratic way of thinking and seeing. Follow the path that leads him up to his latest major work (or two).</description> 
<keywords>talks, art, collaboration, creativity</keywords> 
<talkid>2319</talkid> 
<title>Dustin Yellin: A journey through the mind of an artist</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I was raised by lesbians in the mountains,  and I sort of came like a forest gnome to New York City a while back.    </seg>
<seg id="2">   Really messed with my head, but I'll get into that later.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I'll start with when I was eight years old.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> I took a wood box,  and I buried a dollar bill, a pen and a fork inside this box in Colorado.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> And I thought some strange humanoids or aliens in 500 years would find this box  and learn about the way our species exchanged ideas,  maybe how we ate our spaghetti.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> I really didn't know.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Anyway, this is kind of funny,  because here I am, 30 years later, and I'm still making boxes.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Now, at some point I was in Hawaii --  I like to hike and surf and do all that weird stuff,  and I was making a collage for my ma.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> And I took a dictionary and I ripped it up,  and I made it into a sort of Agnes Martin grid,  and I poured resin all over it and a bee got stuck.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Now, she's afraid of bees and she's allergic to them,  so I poured more resin on the canvas, thinking I could hide it or something.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Instead, the opposite happened:  It sort of created a magnification,  like a magnifying glass, on the dictionary text.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> So what did I do? I built more boxes.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> This time, I started putting electronics, frogs,  strange bottles I'd find in the street -- anything I could find --  because I was always finding things my whole life,  and trying to make relationships and tell stories between these objects.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> So I started drawing around the objects,  and I realized: Holy moly, I can draw in space!    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I can make free-floating lines,  like the way you would draw around a dead body at a crime scene.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> So I took the objects out,  and I created my own taxonomy of invented specimens.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> First, botanical -- which you can kind of get a sense of.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> Then I made some weird insects and creatures.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> It was really fun; I was just drawing on the layers of resin.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And it was cool, because I was actually starting to have shows and stuff,  I was making some money, I could take my girlfriend for dinner,  and like, go to Sizzler.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> It was some good shit, man.    </seg>
<seg id="22">   At some point, I got up to the human form,  life-size resin sculptures with drawings of humans inside the layers.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> This was great, except for one thing:  I was going to die.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> I didn't know what to do, because the resin was going to kill me.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> And I went to bed every night thinking about it.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> So I tried using glass.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> I started drawing on the layers of glass,  almost like if you drew on a window, then you put another window,  and another window, and you had all these windows together  that made a three-dimensional composition.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> And this really worked, because I could stop using the resin.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> So I did this for years,  which culminated in a very large work, which I call "The Triptych."    </seg>
<seg id="30"> "The Triptych" was largely inspired  by Hieronymus Bosch's "[The] Garden of Earthly Delights,"  which is a painting in the [Museo del] Prado in Spain.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Do you guys know this painting?    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Good, it's a cool painting.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> It's kind of ahead of its time, they say.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> So, "The Triptych." I'll walk you through this piece.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> It weighs 24,000 pounds.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> It's 18 feet long.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> It's double-sided, so it's 36 feet of composition.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> It's kind of weird.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Well, that's the blood fountain.    </seg>
<seg id="40">   To the left, you have Jesus and the locusts.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> There's a cave  where all these animal-headed creatures travel between two worlds.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> They go from the representational world,  to this analog-mesh underworld, where they're hiding.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> This is where the animal-headed creatures are by the lighthouse,  and they're all about to commit mass suicide into the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> The ocean is made up of thousands of elements.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> This is a bird god tied up to a battleship.    </seg>
<seg id="46">   Billy Graham is in the ocean;  the Horizon from the oil spill; Waldo; Osama Bin Laden's shelter --  there's all kinds of weird stuff that you can find if you look really hard, in the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Anyway, this is a lady creature.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> She's coming out of the ocean, and she's spitting oil into one hand  and she has clouds coming out of her other hand.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Her hands are like scales,  and she has the mythological reference of the Earth and cosmos in balance.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> So that's one side of "The Triptych."    </seg>
<seg id="51"> It's a little narrative thing.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> That's her hand that she's spitting into.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> And then, when you go to the other side,  she has like a trunk, like a bird's beak, and she's spitting clouds out of her trunk.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Then she has an 18-foot-long serpent's tail that connects "The Triptych."    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Anyway, her tail catches on fire from the back of the volcano.    </seg>
<seg id="56">   I don't know why that happened.    </seg>
<seg id="57">   That happens, you know.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> Her tail terminates in a cycloptic eyeball, made out of 1986 terrorist cards.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Have you guys seen those?    </seg>
<seg id="60"> They were made in the 1980's, they're like baseball cards of terrorists.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Way ahead of their time.    </seg>
<seg id="62">   That will bring you to my latest project.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> I'm in the middle of two projects:  One's called "Psychogeographies."    </seg>
<seg id="64"> It's about a six-year project to make 100 of these humans.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Each one is an archive of our culture,  through our ripped-up media and matter, whether it's encyclopedias or dictionaries or magazines.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> But each one acts as a sort of an archive in the shape of a human,  and they travel in groups of 20, 4, or 12 at a time.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> They're like cells -- they come together, they divide.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> And you kind of walk through them. It's taking me years.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Each one is basically a 3,000-pound microscope slide  with a human stuck inside.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> This one has a little cave in his chest.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> That's his head; there's the chest, you can kind of see the beginning.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> I'm going to go down the body for you:  There's a waterfall coming out of his chest,  covering his penis -- or not-penis, or whatever it is,  a kind of androgynous thing.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> I'll take you quickly through these works,  because I can't explain them for too long.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> There are the layers, you can kind of see it.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> This one has two heads,  and it's communicating between the two heads.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> You can see the pills coming out, going into one head from this weird statue.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> There's a little forest scene inside the chest cavity.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> Can you see that?    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Anyway, this talk's all about these boxes,  like the boxes we're in.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> This box we're in, the solar system is a box.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> This brings you to my latest box.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> It's a brick box. It's called Pioneer Works.    </seg>
<seg id="83">   Inside of this box is a physicist, a neuroscientist, a painter, a musician,  a writer, a radio station, a museum, a school,  a publishing arm to disseminate all the content we make there into the world; a garden.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> We shake this box up,  and all these people kind of start hitting each other like particles.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> And I think that's the way you change the world.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> You redefine your insides and the box that you're living in.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> And you come together to realize that we're all in this together,  that this delusion of difference --  this idea of countries, of borders, of religion -- doesn't work.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> We're all really made up of the same stuff, in the same box.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> And if we don't start exchanging that stuff sweetly and nicely,  we're all going to die real soon.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2313" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/patience_mthunzi_could_we_cure_hiv_with_lasers</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Swallowing pills to get medication is a quick, painless and often not entirely effective way of treating disease. A potentially better way? Lasers. In this passionate talk, TED Fellow Patience Mthunzi explains her idea to use lasers to deliver drugs directly to cells infected with HIV. It's early days yet, but could a cure be on the horizon?</description> 
<keywords>talks, AIDS, HIV, health, health care, innovation, medical research, medicine, molecular biology, pharmaceuticals, science</keywords> 
<talkid>2313</talkid> 
<title>Patience Mthunzi: Could we cure HIV with lasers?</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> What do you do when you have a headache?    </seg>
<seg id="2"> You swallow an aspirin.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> But for this pill to get to your head, where the pain is,  it goes through your stomach, intestines and various other organs first.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Swallowing pills is the most effective and painless way of delivering  any medication in the body.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> The downside, though, is that swallowing any medication leads to its dilution.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> And this is a big problem, particularly in HIV patients.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> When they take their anti-HIV drugs,  these drugs are good for lowering the virus in the blood,  and increasing the CD4 cell counts.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> But they are also notorious for their adverse side effects,  but mostly bad, because they get diluted by the time they get to the blood,  and worse, by the time they get to the sites  where it matters most: within the HIV viral reservoirs.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> These areas in the body -- such as the lymph nodes,  the nervous system, as well as the lungs --  where the virus is sleeping,  and will not readily get delivered in the blood  of patients that are under consistent anti-HIV drugs therapy.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> However, upon discontinuation of therapy,  the virus can awake and infect new cells in the blood.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Now, all this is a big problem in treating HIV with the current drug treatment,  which is a life-long treatment that must be swallowed by patients.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> One day, I sat and thought,  "Can we deliver anti-HIV directly within its reservoir sites,  without the risk of drug dilution?"    </seg>
<seg id="13"> As a laser scientist, the answer was just before my eyes:  Lasers, of course.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> If they can be used for dentistry,  for diabetic wound-healing and surgery,  they can be used for anything imaginable,  including transporting drugs into cells.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> As a matter of fact, we are currently using laser pulses  to poke or drill extremely tiny holes,  which open and close almost immediately in HIV-infected cells,  in order to deliver drugs within them.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> "How is that possible?" you may ask.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Well, we shine a very powerful but super-tiny laser beam  onto the membrane of HIV-infected cells  while these cells are immersed in liquid containing the drug.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> The laser pierces the cell, while the cell swallows the drug  in a matter of microseconds.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> Before you even know it,  the induced hole becomes immediately repaired.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> Now, we are currently testing this technology in test tubes  or in Petri dishes,  but the goal is to get this technology in the human body,  apply it in the human body.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> "How is that possible?" you may ask.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Well, the answer is: through a three-headed device.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Using the first head, which is our laser,  we will make an incision in the site of infection.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Using the second head, which is a camera,  we meander to the site of infection.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Finally, using a third head, which is a drug-spreading sprinkler,  we deliver the drugs directly at the site of infection,  while the laser is again used to poke those cells open.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Well, this might not seem like much right now.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> But one day, if successful, this technology can lead  to complete eradication of HIV in the body.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Yes. A cure for HIV.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> This is every HIV researcher's dream --  in our case, a cure lead by lasers.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2309" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/benedetta_berti_the_surprising_way_groups_like_isis_stay_in_power</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: ISIS, Hezbollah, Hamas. These three very different groups are known for violence — but that’s only a portion of what they do, says policy analyst Benedetta Berti. They also attempt to win over populations with social work: setting up schools and hospitals, offering safety and security, and filling the gaps left by weak governments. Understanding the broader work of these groups suggests new strategies for ending the violence.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Middle East, TED Fellows, global issues, politics, terrorism, violence</keywords> 
<talkid>2309</talkid> 
<title>Benedetta Berti: The surprising way groups like ISIS stay in power</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> For the past decade,  I've been studying non-state armed groups:  armed organizations like terrorists, insurgents or militias.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I document what these groups do when they're not shooting.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> My goal is to better understand these violent actors  and to study ways to encourage transition from violent engagement  to nonviolent confrontation.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> I work in the field, in the policy world and in the library.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Understanding non-state armed groups is key to solving most ongoing conflict,  because war has changed.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> It used to be a contest between states.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> No longer.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> It is now a conflict between states and non-state actors.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> For example, of the 216 peace agreements  signed between 1975 and 2011,  196 of them were between a state and a non-state actor.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> So we need to understand these groups; we need to either engage them  or defeat them in any conflict resolution process that has to be successful.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> So how do we do that?    </seg>
<seg id="12"> We need to know what makes these organizations tick.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> We know a lot about how they fight, why they fight,  but no one looks at what they're doing when they're not fighting.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Yet, armed struggle and unarmed politics are related.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> It is all part of the same organization.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> We cannot understand these groups, let alone defeat them,  if we don't have the full picture.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And armed groups today are complex organizations.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> Take the Lebanese Hezbollah,  known for its violent confrontation against Israel.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> But since its creation in the early 1980s,  Hezbollah has also set up a political party,  a social-service network, and a military apparatus.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> Similarly, the Palestinian Hamas,  known for its suicide attacks against Israel,  also runs the Gaza Strip since 2007.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> So these groups do way more than just shoot.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> They multi-task.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> They set up complex communication machines --  radio stations, TV channels,  Internet websites and social media strategies.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> And up here, you have the ISIS magazine,  printed in English and published to recruit.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Armed groups also invest in complex fund-raising --  not looting, but setting up profitable businesses;  for example, construction companies.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Now, these activities are keys.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> They allow these groups to increase their strength,  increase their funds,  to better recruit and to build their brand.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Armed groups also do something else:  they build stronger bonds with the population  by investing in social services.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> They build schools, they run hospitals,  they set up vocational-training programs or micro-loan programs.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Hezbollah offers all of these services and more.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Armed groups also seek to win the population over  by offering something that the state is not providing:  safety and security.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> The initial rise of the Taliban in war-torn Afghanistan,  or even the beginning of the ascent of ISIS,  can be understood also by looking at these groups' efforts  to provide security.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Now, unfortunately, in these cases,  the provision of security came at an unbearably high price  for the population.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> But in general, providing social services fills a gap,  a governance gap left by the government,  and allows these groups to increase their strength  and their power.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> For example, the 2006 electoral victory of the Palestinian Hamas  cannot be understood without acknowledging the group's social work.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Now, this is a really complex picture,  yet in the West, when we look at armed groups,  we only think of the violent side.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> But that's not enough to understand these groups' strength,  strategy or long-term vision.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> These groups are hybrid.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> They rise because they fill a gap left by the government,  and they emerge to be both armed and political,  engage in violent struggle and provide governance.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> And the more these organizations are complex and sophisticated,  the less we can think of them as the opposite of a state.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Now, what do you call a group like Hezbollah?    </seg>
<seg id="42"> They run part of a territory, they administer all their functions,  they pick up the garbage, they run the sewage system.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Is this a state? Is it a rebel group?    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Or maybe something else, something different and new?    </seg>
<seg id="45"> And what about ISIS?    </seg>
<seg id="46"> The lines are blurred.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> We live in a world of states, non-states, and in-between,  and the more states are weak, like in the Middle East today,  the more non-state actors step in and fill that gap.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> This matters for governments, because to counter these groups,  they will have to invest more in non-military tools.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Filling that governance gap  has to be at the center of any sustainable approach.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> This also matters very much for peacemaking and peacebuilding.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> If we better understand armed groups,  we will better know what incentives to offer  to encourage the transition from violence to nonviolence.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> So in this new contest between states and non-states,  military power can win some battles,  but it will not give us peace nor stability.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> To achieve these objectives,  what we need is a long-term investment in filling that security gap,  in filling that governance gap  that allowed these groups to thrive in the first place.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2284" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/roxane_gay_confessions_of_a_bad_feminist</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: When writer Roxane Gay dubbed herself a "bad feminist," she was making a joke, acknowledging that she couldn't possibly live up to the demands for perfection of the feminist movement. But she's realized that the joke rang hollow. In a thoughtful and provocative talk, she asks us to embrace all flavors of feminism -- and make the small choices that, en masse, might lead to actual change.</description> 
<keywords>talks, feminism, identity, women</keywords> 
<talkid>2284</talkid> 
<title>Roxane Gay: Confessions of a bad feminist</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I am failing as a woman,  I am failing as a feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I have passionate opinions about gender equality,  but I worry that to freely accept the label of "feminist,"  would not be fair to good feminists.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I'm a feminist, but I'm a rather bad one.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Oh, so I call myself a Bad Feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Or at least, I wrote an essay,  and then I wrote a book called "Bad Feminist,"  and then in interviews, people started calling me The Bad Feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="6">   So, what started as a bit of an inside joke with myself  and a willful provocation,  has become a thing.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Let me take a step back.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> When I was younger,  mostly in my teens and 20s,  I had strange ideas about feminists  as hairy, angry, man-hating, sex-hating women --  as if those are bad things.    </seg>
<seg id="9">   These days, I look at how women are treated the world over,  and anger, in particular, seems like a perfectly reasonable response.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> But back then,  I worried about the tone people used  when suggesting I might be a feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> The feminist label was an accusation,  it was an "F" word, and not a nice one.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> I was labeled a woman who doesn't play by the rules,  who expects too much,  who thinks far too highly of myself,  by daring to believe I'm equal --  -- superior to a man.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> You don't want to be that rebel woman,  until you realize that you very much are that woman,  and cannot imagine being anyone else.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> As I got older, I began to accept  that I am, indeed, a feminist, and a proud one.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I hold certain truths to be self-evident:  Women are equal to men.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> We deserve equal pay for equal work.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> We have the right to move through the world as we choose,  free from harassment or violence.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> We have the right to easy, affordable access to birth control,  and reproductive services.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> We have the right to make choices about our bodies,  free from legislative oversight or evangelical doctrine.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> We have the right to respect.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> There's more.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> When we talk about the needs of women,  we have to consider the other identities we inhabit.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> We are not just women.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> We are people with different bodies,  gender expressions, faiths, sexualities,  class backgrounds, abilities, and so much more.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> We need to take into account  these differences and how they affect us,  as much as we account for what we have in common.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Without this kind of inclusion, our feminism is nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> I hold these truths to be self-evident, but let me be clear:  I'm a mess.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> I am full of contradictions.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> There are many ways in which I'm doing feminism wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> I have another confession.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> When I drive to work, I listen to thuggish rap at a very loud volume.    </seg>
<seg id="32">   Even though the lyrics are degrading to women --  these lyrics offend me to my core --  the classic Yin Yang Twins song "Salt Shaker" --  it is amazing.    </seg>
<seg id="33">   "Make it work with your wet t-shirt.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> Bitch, you gotta shake it 'til your camel starts to hurt!"    </seg>
<seg id="35">   Think about it.    </seg>
<seg id="36">   Poetry, right?    </seg>
<seg id="37"> I am utterly mortified by my music choices.    </seg>
<seg id="38">   I firmly believe in man work,  which is anything I don't want to do, including --   --  all domestic tasks,  but also: bug killing, trash removal, lawn care and vehicle maintenance.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> I want no part of any of that.    </seg>
<seg id="40">   Pink is my favorite color.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> I enjoy fashion magazines and pretty things.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> I watch "The Bachelor" and romantic comedies,  and I have absurd fantasies about fairy tales coming true.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Some of my transgressions are more flagrant.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> If a woman wants to take her husband's name,  that is her choice, and it is not my place to judge.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> If a woman chooses to stay home to raise her children,  I embrace that choice, too.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> The problem is not that she makes herself economically vulnerable in that choice;  the problem is that our society is set up  to make women economically vulnerable when they choose.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Let's deal with that.    </seg>
<seg id="48">   I reject the mainstream feminism  that has historically ignored or deflected the needs  of women of color, working-class women, queer women and transgender women,  in favor of supporting white, middle- and upper-class straight women.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Listen, if that's good feminism -- I am a very bad feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="50">   There is also this:  As a feminist, I feel a lot of pressure.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> We have this tendency to put visible feminists on a pedestal.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> We expect them to pose perfectly.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> When they disappoint us,  we gleefully knock them from the very pedestal we put them on.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Like I said, I am a mess --  consider me knocked off that pedestal  before you ever try to put me up there.    </seg>
<seg id="55">   Too many women,  particularly groundbreaking women and industry leaders,  are afraid to be labeled as feminists.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> They're afraid to stand up and say, "Yes, I am a feminist,"  for fear of what that label means,  for fear of being unable to live up to unrealistic expectations.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Take, for example, Beyoncé, or as I call her, The Goddess.    </seg>
<seg id="58">   She has emerged, in recent years, as a visible feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> At the 2014 MTV Video Music Awards,  she performed in front of the word "feminist" 10 feet high.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> It was a glorious spectacle to see  this pop star openly embracing feminism  and letting young women and men know  that being a feminist is something to celebrate.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> As the moment faded, cultural critics began endlessly debating  whether or not Beyoncé was, indeed, a feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> They graded her feminism,  instead of simply taking a grown, accomplished woman at her word.    </seg>
<seg id="63">     We demand perfection from feminists,  because we are still fighting for so much,  we want so much,  we need so damn much.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> We go far beyond reasonable, constructive criticism,  to dissecting any given woman's feminism,  tearing it apart until there's nothing left.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> We do not need to do that.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Bad feminism -- or really, more inclusive feminism -- is a starting point.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> But what happens next?    </seg>
<seg id="68"> We go from acknowledging our imperfections to accountability,  or walking the walk, and being a little bit brave.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> If I listen to degrading music,  I am creating a demand for which artists are more than happy  to contribute a limitless supply.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> These artists are not going to change  how they talk about women in their songs  until we demand that change by affecting their bottom line.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Certainly, it is difficult.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Why must it be so catchy?    </seg>
<seg id="73">   It's hard to make the better choice,  and it is so easy to justify a lesser one.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> But --  when I justify bad choices,  I make it harder for women to achieve equality,  the equality that we all deserve,  and I need to own that.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> I think of my nieces, ages three and four.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> They are gorgeous and headstrong, brilliant girls,  who are a whole lot of brave.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> I want them to thrive in a world where they are valued  for the powerful creatures they are.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> I think of them,  and suddenly, the better choice becomes far easier to make.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> We can all make better choices.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> We can change the channel when a television show  treats sexual violence against women like sport,  Game of Thrones.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> We can change the radio station  when we hear songs that treat women as nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> We can spend our box office dollars elsewhere  when movies don't treat women  as anything more than decorative objects.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> We can stop supporting professional sports  where the athletes treat their partners like punching bags.    </seg>
<seg id="84">   In other ways, men -- and especially straight white men --  can say, "No, I will not publish with your magazine,  or participate in your project, or otherwise work with you,  until you include a fair number of women,  both as participants and decision makers.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> I won't work with you until your publication,  or your organization, is more inclusive of all kinds of difference."    </seg>
<seg id="86"> Those of us who are underrepresented  and invited to participate in such projects,  can also decline to be included  until more of us are invited through the glass ceiling,  and we are tokens no more.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> Without these efforts,  without taking these stands,  our accomplishments are going to mean very little.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> We can commit these small acts of bravery  and hope that our choices trickle upward to the people in power --  editors, movie and music producers,  CEOs, lawmakers --  the people who can make bigger, braver choices  to create lasting, meaningful change.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> We can also boldly claim our feminism --  good, bad, or anywhere in between.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> The last line of my book "Bad Feminist" says,  "I would rather be a bad feminist than no feminist at all."    </seg>
<seg id="91"> This is true for so many reasons,  but first and foremost, I say this because once upon a time,  my voice was stolen from me,  and feminism helped me to get my voice back.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> There was an incident.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> I call it an incident so I can carry the burden of what happened.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> Some boys broke me,  when I was so young, I did not know  what boys can do to break a girl.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> They treated me like I was nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> I began to believe I was nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> They stole my voice, and in the after,  I did not dare to believe  that anything I might say could matter.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> But --  I had writing.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> And there, I wrote myself back together.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> I wrote myself toward a stronger version of myself.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> I read the words of women  who might understand a story like mine,  and women who looked like me,  and understood what it was like to move through the world with brown skin.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> I read the words of women who showed me I was not nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> I learned to write like them,  and then I learned to write as myself.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> I found my voice again,  and I started to believe that my voice is powerful beyond measure.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> Through writing and feminism,  I also found that if I was a little bit brave,  another woman might hear me and see me and recognize  that none of us are the nothing the world tries to tell us we are.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> In one hand,  I hold the power to accomplish anything.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> And in my other,  I hold the humbling reality that I am just one woman.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> I am a bad feminist,  I am a good woman,  I am trying to become better in how I think,  and what I say, and what I do,  without abandoning everything that makes me human.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> I hope that we can all do the same.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> I hope that we can all be a little bit brave,  when we most need such bravery.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2183" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/marc_kushner_why_the_buildings_of_the_future_will_be_shaped_by_you</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: "Architecture is not about math or zoning -- it's about visceral emotions," says Marc Kushner. In a sweeping — often funny — talk, he zooms through the past thirty years of architecture to show how the public, once disconnected, have become an essential part of the design process. With the help of social media, feedback reaches architects years before a building is even created. The result? Architecture that will do more for us than ever before.</description> 
<keywords>talks, TED Books, architecture, design, social media</keywords> 
<talkid>2183</talkid> 
<title>Marc Kushner: Why the buildings of the future will be shaped by ... you</title> 
<reviewer href="http://www.ted.com/profiles/78265">Krystian Aparta</reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Today I'm going to speak to you about the last 30 years of architectural history.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> That's a lot to pack into 18 minutes.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> It's a complex topic,  so we're just going to dive right in at a complex place:  New Jersey.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Because 30 years ago, I'm from Jersey,  and I was six, and I lived there in my parents' house in a town called Livingston,  and this was my childhood bedroom.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Around the corner from my bedroom was the bathroom that I used to share with my sister.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> And in between my bedroom and the bathroom was a balcony that overlooked the family room.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> And that's where everyone would hang out and watch TV,  so that every time that I walked from my bedroom to the bathroom,  everyone would see me,  and every time I took a shower and would come back in a towel,  everyone would see me.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And I looked like this.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> I was awkward, insecure, and I hated it.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> I hated that walk, I hated that balcony,  I hated that room, and I hated that house.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And that's architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="12">   Done.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> That feeling, those emotions that I felt, that's the power of architecture,  because architecture is not about math and it's not about zoning,  it's about those visceral, emotional connections  that we feel to the places that we occupy.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> And it's no surprise that we feel that way,  because according to the EPA,  Americans spend 90 percent of their time indoors.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> That's 90 percent of our time surrounded by architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> That's huge.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> That means that architecture is shaping us in ways that we didn't even realize.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> That makes us a little bit gullible and very, very predictable.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> It means that when I show you a building like this,  I know what you think:  You think "power" and "stability" and "democracy."    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And I know you think that because it's based on a building  that was build 2,500 years ago by the Greeks.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> This is a trick.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> This is a trigger that architects use  to get you to create an emotional connection  to the forms that we build our buildings out of.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> It's a predictable emotional connection,  and we've been using this trick for a long, long time.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> We used it [200] years ago to build banks.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> We used it in the 19th century to build art museums.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> And in the 20th century in America, we used it to build houses.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> And look at these solid, stable little soldiers  facing the ocean and keeping away the elements.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> This is really, really useful,  because building things is terrifying. It's expensive, it takes a long time, and it's very complicated.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> And the people that build things -- developers and governments --  they're naturally afraid of innovation,  and they'd rather just use those forms that they know you'll respond to.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> That's how we end up with buildings like this.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> This is a nice building.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> This is the Livingston Public Library that was completed in 2004 in my hometown,  and, you know, it's got a dome and it's got this round thing and columns, red brick,  and you can kind of guess what Livingston is trying to say with this building:  children, property values and history.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> But it doesn't have much to do with what a library actually does today.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> That same year, in 2004, on the other side of the country,  another library was completed, and it looks like this.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> It's in Seattle.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> This library is about how we consume media in a digital age.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> It's about a new kind of public amenity for the city,  a place to gather and read and share.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> So how is it possible that in the same year, in the same country,  two buildings, both called libraries,  look so completely different?    </seg>
<seg id="39"> And the answer is that architecture works on the principle of a pendulum.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> On the one side is innovation,  and architects are constantly pushing, pushing for new technologies,  new typologies, new solutions for the way that we live today.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> And we push and we push and we push until we completely alienate all of you.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> We wear all black, we get very depressed,  you think we're adorable,  we're dead inside because we've got no choice.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> We have to go to the other side  and reengage those symbols that we know you love.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> So we do that, and you're happy,  we feel like sellouts, so we start experimenting again  and we push the pendulum back and back and forth and back and forth  we've gone for the last 300 years,  and certainly for the last 30 years.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Okay, 30 years ago we were coming out of the '70s.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Architects had been busy experimenting with something called brutalism.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> It's about concrete.    </seg>
<seg id="48">   You can guess this.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Small windows, dehumanizing scale.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> This is really tough stuff.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> So as we get closer to the '80s, we start to reengage those symbols.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> We push the pendulum back into the other direction.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> We take these forms that we know you love  and we update them. We add neon  and we add pastels and we use new materials.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And you love it.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And we can't give you enough of it.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> We take Chippendale armoires and we turned those into skyscrapers,  and skyscrapers can be medieval castles made out of glass.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Forms got big,  forms got bold and colorful.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> Dwarves became columns.    </seg>
<seg id="59">   Swans grew to the size of buildings.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> It was crazy.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> But it's the '80s, it's cool.    </seg>
<seg id="62">   We're all hanging out in malls and we're all moving to the suburbs,  and out there, out in the suburbs, we can create our own architectural fantasies.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> And those fantasies,  they can be Mediterranean or French or Italian.    </seg>
<seg id="64">   Possibly with endless breadsticks.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> This is the thing about postmodernism.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> This is the thing about symbols.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> They're easy, they're cheap, because instead of making places,  we're making memories of places.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Because I know, and I know all of you know,  this isn't Tuscany.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> This is Ohio.    </seg>
<seg id="70">   So architects get frustrated,  and we start pushing the pendulum back into the other direction.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> In the late '80s and early '90s,  we start experimenting with something called deconstructivism.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> We throw out historical symbols,  we rely on new, computer-aided design techniques,  and we come up with new compositions, forms crashing into forms.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> This is academic and heady stuff, it's super unpopular,  we totally alienate you.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Ordinarily, the pendulum would just swing back into the other direction.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> And then, something amazing happened.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> In 1997, this building opened.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> This is the Guggenheim Bilbao, by Frank Gehry.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> And this building fundamentally changes the world's relationship to architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Paul Goldberger said that Bilbao was one of those rare moments  when critics, academics, and the general public were completely united around a building.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> The New York Times called this building a miracle.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Tourism in Bilbao increased 2,500 percent after this building was completed.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> So all of a sudden, everybody wants one of these buildings:  L.A.,  Seattle,  Chicago,  New York,  Cleveland,  Springfield.    </seg>
<seg id="83">   Everybody wants one, and Gehry is everywhere.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> He is our very first starchitect.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Now, how is it possible that these forms -- they're wild and radical --  how is it possible that they become so ubiquitous throughout the world?    </seg>
<seg id="86"> And it happened because media so successfully galvanized around them  that they quickly taught us that these forms mean culture and tourism.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> We created an emotional reaction to these forms.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> So did every mayor in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> So every mayor knew that if they had these forms,  they had culture and tourism.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> This phenomenon at the turn of the new millennium happened to a few other starchitects. It happened to Zaha  and it happened to Libeskind,  and what happened to these elite few architects  at the turn of the new millennium  could actually start to happen to the entire field of architecture,  as digital media starts to increase the speed  with which we consume information.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> Because think about how you consume architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> A thousand years ago,  you would have had to have walked to the village next door to see a building.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> Transportation speeds up:  You can take a boat, you can take a plane, you can be a tourist.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> Technology speeds up: You can see it in a newspaper, on TV,  until finally, we are all architectural photographers,  and the building has become disembodied from the site.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> Architecture is everywhere now,  and that means that the speed of communication has finally caught up to the speed of architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> Because architecture actually moves quite quickly.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> It doesn't take long to think about a building.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> It takes a long time to build a building, three or four years,  and in the interim, an architect will design two or eight  or a hundred other buildings  before they know if that building that they designed four years ago was a success or not.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> That's because there's never been a good feedback loop in architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> That's how we end up with buildings like this.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> Brutalism wasn't a two-year movement, it was a 20-year movement.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> For 20 years, we were producing buildings like this  because we had no idea how much you hated it.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> It's never going to happen again, I think,  because we are living on the verge of the greatest revolution in architecture  since the invention of concrete, of steel, or of the elevator, and it's a media revolution.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> So my theory is that when you apply media to this pendulum,  it starts swinging faster and faster, until it's at both extremes nearly simultaneously,  and that effectively blurs the difference between innovation and symbol,  between us, the architects, and you, the public.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> Now we can make nearly instantaneous, emotionally charged symbols  out of something that's brand new.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> Let me show you how this plays out in a project that my firm recently completed.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> We were hired to replace this building, which burned down.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> This is the center of a town called the Pines in Fire Island in New York State.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> It's a vacation community.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> We proposed a building that was audacious,  that was different than any of the forms that the community was used to,  and we were scared and our client was scared and the community was scared,  so we created a series of photorealistic renderings  that we put onto Facebook and we put onto Instagram,  and we let people start to do what they do:    </seg>
<seg id="111"> share it, comment, like it, hate it.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> But that meant that two years before the building was complete,  it was already a part of the community,  so that when the renderings looked exactly like the finished product,  there were no surprises.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> This building was already a part of this community,  and then that first summer,  when people started arriving and sharing the building on social media,  the building ceased to be just an edifice and it became media,  because these, these are not just pictures of a building, they're your pictures of a building.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> And as you use them to tell your story,  they become part of your personal narrative,  and what you're doing is you're short-circuiting all of our collective memory,  and you're making these charged symbols for us to understand.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> That means we don't need the Greeks anymore to tell us what to think about architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> We can tell each other what we think about architecture,  because digital media hasn't just changed the relationship between all of us,  it's changed the relationship between us and buildings.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> Think for a second about those librarians back in Livingston.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> If that building was going to be built today,  the first thing they would do is go online and search "new libraries."    </seg>
<seg id="119"> They would be bombarded by examples of experimentation, of innovation,  of pushing at the envelope of what a library can be.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> That's ammunition.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> That's ammunition that they can take with them  to the mayor of Livingston, to the people of Livingston,  and say, there's no one answer to what a library is today.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> Let's be a part of this.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> This abundance of experimentation  gives them the freedom to run their own experiment.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> Everything is different now.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> Architects are no longer these mysterious creatures  that use big words and complicated drawings,  and you aren't the hapless public,  the consumer that won't accept anything that they haven't seen anymore.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> Architects can hear you,  and you're not intimidated by architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> That means that that pendulum swinging back and forth  from style to style, from movement to movement, is irrelevant.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> We can actually move forward  and find relevant solutions to the problems that our society faces.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> This is the end of architectural history,  and it means that the buildings of tomorrow are going to look a lot different than the buildings of today.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> It means that a public space in the ancient city of Seville  can be unique and tailored to the way that a modern city works.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> It means that a stadium in Brooklyn can be a stadium in Brooklyn,  not some red-brick historical pastiche of what we think a stadium ought to be.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> It means that robots are going to build our buildings,  because we're finally ready for the forms that they're going to produce.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> And it means that buildings will twist to the whims of nature  instead of the other way around.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> It means that a parking garage in Miami Beach, Florida,  can also be a place for sports and for yoga  and you can even get married there late at night.    </seg>
<seg id="135">   It means that three architects can dream about swimming in the East River of New York,  and then raise nearly half a million dollars  from a community that gathered around their cause,  no one client anymore.    </seg>
<seg id="136"> It means that no building is too small for innovation,  like this little reindeer pavilion  that's as muscly and sinewy as the animals it's designed to observe.    </seg>
<seg id="137"> And it means that a building doesn't have to be beautiful to be lovable,  like this ugly little building in Spain,  where the architects dug a hole, packed it with hay,  and then poured concrete around it,  and when the concrete dried,  they invited someone to come and clean that hay out  so that all that's left when it's done is this hideous little room    </seg>
<seg id="138"> that's filled with the imprints and scratches of how that place was made,  and that becomes the most sublime place to watch a Spanish sunset.    </seg>
<seg id="139"> Because it doesn't matter if a cow builds our buildings  or a robot builds our buildings.    </seg>
<seg id="140"> It doesn't matter how we build, it matters what we build.    </seg>
<seg id="141"> Architects already know how to make buildings that are greener  and smarter and friendlier.    </seg>
<seg id="142"> We've just been waiting for all of you to want them.    </seg>
<seg id="143"> And finally, we're not on opposite sides anymore.    </seg>
<seg id="144"> Find an architect, hire an architect,  work with us to design better buildings, better cities, and a better world,  because the stakes are high.    </seg>
<seg id="145"> Buildings don't just reflect our society, they shape our society  down to the smallest spaces:  the local libraries,  the homes where we raise our children,  and the walk that they take from the bedroom to the bathroom.    </seg>
<seg id="146"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2024" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/zak_ebrahim_i_am_the_son_of_a_terrorist_here_s_how_i_chose_peace</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: If you’re raised on dogma and hate, can you choose a different path? Zak Ebrahim was just seven years old when his father helped plan the 1993 World Trade Center bombing. His story is shocking, powerful and, ultimately, inspiring.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Middle East, TED Books, peace, terrorism, violence</keywords> 
<talkid>2024</talkid> 
<title>Zak Ebrahim: I am the son of a terrorist. Here's how I chose peace.</title> 
<reviewer href="http://www.ted.com/profiles/2064042">Mad Aronson</reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> On November 5th, 1990,  a man named El-Sayyid Nosair walked  into a hotel in Manhattan  and assassinated Rabbi Meir Kahane,  the leader of the Jewish Defense League.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> Nosair was initially found not guilty of the murder,  but while serving time on lesser charges,  he and other men began planning attacks  on a dozen New York City landmarks,  including tunnels, synagogues  and the United Nations headquarters.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> Thankfully, those plans were foiled  by an FBI informant.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Sadly, the 1993 bombing  of the World Trade Center was not.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Nosair would eventually be convicted  for his involvement in the plot.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> El-Sayyid Nosair is my father.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> I was born in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania  in 1983 to him, an Egyptian engineer,  and a loving American mother and grade school teacher,  who together tried their best  to create a happy childhood for me.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> It wasn't until I was seven years old  that our family dynamic started to change.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> My father exposed me to a side of Islam  that few people, including the majority of Muslims,  It's been my experience that when people  take the time to interact with one another,  it doesn't take long to realize that for the most part,  we all want the same things out of life.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> However, in every religion, in every population,  you'll find a small percentage of people  who hold so fervently to their beliefs  that they feel they must use any means necessary  to make others live as they do.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> A few months prior to his arrest,  he sat me down and explained that  for the past few weekends, he and some friends  had been going to a shooting range on Long Island  for target practice.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> He told me I'd be going with him the next morning.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> We arrived at Calverton Shooting Range,  which unbeknownst to our group was being watched  by the FBI.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> When it was my turn to shoot,  my father helped me hold the rifle to my shoulder  and explained how to aim at the target  about 30 yards off.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> That day, the last bullet I shot  hit the small orange light that sat on top of the target  and to everyone's surprise, especially mine,  the entire target burst into flames.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> My uncle turned to the other men,  and in Arabic said, "Ibn abuh."    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Like father, like son.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> They all seemed to get a really big laugh out of that comment,  but it wasn't until a few years later  that I fully understood what they thought was so funny.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> They thought they saw in me the same destruction  my father was capable of.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> Those men would eventually be convicted  of placing a van filled with 1,500 pounds of explosives  into the sub-level parking lot of the World Trade Center's North Tower,  causing an explosion that killed six people  and injured over 1,000 others.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> These were the men I looked up to.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> These were the men I called ammu, which means uncle.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> By the time I turned 19,  I had already moved 20 times in my life,  and that instability during my childhood  didn't really provide an opportunity  to make many friends.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Each time I would begin to feel comfortable around someone,  it was time to pack up and move to the next town.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Being the perpetual new face in class,  I was frequently the target of bullies.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> I kept my identity a secret from my classmates  to avoid being targeted,  but as it turns out, being the quiet, chubby new kid in class  was more than enough ammunition.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> So for the most part, I spent my time at home  reading books and watching TV  or playing video games.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> For those reasons, my social skills were lacking,  to say the least,  and growing up in a bigoted household,  I wasn't prepared for the real world.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> I'd been raised to judge people  based on arbitrary measurements,  like a person's race or religion.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> So what opened my eyes?    </seg>
<seg id="31"> One of my first experiences  that challenged this way of thinking  was during the 2000 presidential elections.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Through a college prep program,  I was able to take part  in the National Youth Convention in Philadelphia.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> My particular group's focus was on youth violence,  and having been the victim of bullying for most of my life,  this was a subject in which I felt particularly passionate.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> The members of our group came from many different walks of life.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> One day toward the end of the convention,  I found out that one of the kids I had befriended  was Jewish.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Now, it had taken several days  for this detail to come to light,  and I realized that there was no natural animosity  between the two of us.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> I had never had a Jewish friend before,  and frankly I felt a sense of pride  in having been able to overcome a barrier  that for most of my life I had been led to believe  was insurmountable.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> Another major turning point came when  I found a summer job at Busch Gardens,  an amusement park.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> There, I was exposed to people from all sorts of faiths and cultures,  and that experience proved to be fundamental  to the development of my character.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> Most of my life, I'd been taught  that homosexuality was a sin, and by extension,  that all gay people were a negative influence.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> As chance would have it, I had the opportunity  to work with some of the gay performers  at a show there,  and soon found that many were the kindest,  least judgmental people I had ever met.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> Being bullied as a kid  created a sense of empathy in me  toward the suffering of others,  and it comes very unnaturally to me  to treat people who are kind  in any other way than how I would want to be treated.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Because of that feeling, I was able  to contrast the stereotypes I'd been taught as a child  with real life experience and interaction.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> I don't know what it's like to be gay,  but I'm well acquainted with being judged  for something that's beyond my control.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Then there was "The Daily Show."    </seg>
<seg id="46"> On a nightly basis, Jon Stewart forced me  to be intellectually honest with myself about my own bigotry  and helped me to realize that a person's race,  religion or sexual orientation  had nothing to do with the quality of one's character.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> He was in many ways a father figure to me  when I was in desperate need of one.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Inspiration can often come from an unexpected place,  and the fact that a Jewish comedian had done more  to positively influence my worldview  than my own extremist father  is not lost on me.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> One day, I had a conversation with my mother  about how my worldview was starting to change,  and she said something to me  that I will hold dear to my heart  for as long as I live.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> She looked at me with the weary eyes  of someone who had experienced  enough dogmatism to last a lifetime, and said,  "I'm tired of hating people."    </seg>
<seg id="51"> In that instant, I realized how much negative energy  it takes to hold that hatred inside of you.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Zak Ebrahim is not my real name.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> I changed it when my family decided  to end our connection with my father  and start a new life.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> So why would I out myself  and potentially put myself in danger?    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Well, that's simple.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> I do it in the hopes that perhaps someone someday  who is compelled to use violence  may hear my story and realize  that there is a better way,  that although I had been subjected  to this violent, intolerant ideology,  that I did not become fanaticized.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Instead, I choose to use my experience  to fight back against terrorism,  against the bigotry.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> I do it for the victims of terrorism  and their loved ones,  for the terrible pain and loss  that terrorism has forced upon their lives.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> For the victims of terrorism, I will speak out  against these senseless acts  and condemn my father's actions.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> And with that simple fact, I stand here as proof  that violence isn't inherent in one's religion or race,  and the son does not have to follow  the ways of his father.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> I am not my father.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Thank you.   Thank you, everybody.   Thank you all.   Thanks a lot.     </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2017" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/stella_young_i_m_not_your_inspiration_thank_you_very_much</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Stella Young is a comedian and journalist who happens to go about her day in a wheelchair — a fact that doesn't, she'd like to make clear, automatically turn her into a noble inspiration to all humanity. In this very funny talk, Young breaks down society's habit of turning disabled people into "inspiration porn."</description> 
<keywords>talks, TEDx, activism, comedy, disability, humor, motivation</keywords> 
<talkid>2017</talkid> 
<title>Stella Young: I'm not your inspiration, thank you very much</title> 
<reviewer href="http://www.ted.com/profiles/2064042">Mad Aronson</reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I grew up in a very small country town  in Victoria.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I had a very normal, low-key kind of upbringing.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I went to school, I hung out with my friends,  I fought with my younger sisters.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> It was all very normal.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> And when I was 15, a member of my local community  approached my parents  and wanted to nominate me  for a community achievement award.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> And my parents said, "Hm, that's really nice,  but there's kind of one glaring problem with that.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> She hasn't actually achieved anything."   And they were right, you know.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> I went to school, I got good marks,  I had a very low-key after school job  in my mum's hairdressing salon,  and I spent a lot of time watching  "Buffy the Vampire Slayer" and "Dawson's Creek."    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Yeah, I know. What a contradiction.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> But they were right, you know.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> I wasn't doing anything that was out of the ordinary  at all.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> I wasn't doing anything that could be considered an achievement  if you took disability out of the equation.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Years later, I was on my second teaching round  in a Melbourne high school,  and I was about 20 minutes into a year 11 legal studies class  when this boy put up his hand and said,  "Hey miss, when are you going to start doing your speech?"    </seg>
<seg id="14"> And I said, "What speech?"    </seg>
<seg id="15"> You know, I'd been talking them  about defamation law for a good 20 minutes.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> And he said, "You know, like,  your motivational speaking.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> You know, when people in wheelchairs come to school,  they usually say, like, inspirational stuff?"    </seg>
<seg id="18">   "It's usually in the big hall."    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And that's when it dawned on me:  This kid had only ever experienced disabled people  as objects of inspiration.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> We are not, to this kid --  and it's not his fault, I mean,  that's true for many of us.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> For lots of us, disabled people are not our teachers  or our doctors or our manicurists.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> We're not real people. We are there to inspire.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> And in fact, I am sitting on this stage  looking like I do in this wheelchair,  and you are probably kind of expecting me  to inspire you. Right?   Yeah.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Well, ladies and gentlemen, I'm afraid  I'm going to disappoint you dramatically.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> I am not here to inspire you.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> I am here to tell you that we have been lied to  about disability.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> Yeah, we've been sold the lie  that disability is a Bad Thing, capital B, capital T.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> It's a bad thing, and to live with a disability  makes you exceptional.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> It's not a bad thing, and it doesn't  make you exceptional.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> And in the past few years, we've been able  to propagate this lie even further  via social media.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> You may have seen images like this one:  "The only disability in life is a bad attitude."    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Or this one: "Your excuse is invalid." Indeed.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Or this one: "Before you quit, try!"    </seg>
<seg id="34"> These are just a couple of examples,  but there are a lot of these images out there.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> You know, you might have seen the one,  the little girl with no hands  drawing a picture with a pencil held in her mouth.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> You might have seen a child running  on carbon fiber prosthetic legs.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> And these images,  there are lots of them out there,  they are what we call inspiration porn.    </seg>
<seg id="38">   And I use the term porn deliberately,  because they objectify one group of people  for the benefit of another group of people.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> So in this case, we're objectifying disabled people  for the benefit of nondisabled people.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> The purpose of these images  is to inspire you, to motivate you,  so that we can look at them  and think, "Well, however bad my life is,  it could be worse.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> I could be that person."    </seg>
<seg id="42"> But what if you are that person?    </seg>
<seg id="43"> I've lost count of the number of times that I've  been approached by strangers  wanting to tell me that they think I'm brave  or inspirational,  and this was long before my work  had any kind of public profile.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> They were just kind of congratulating me  for managing to get up in the morning  and remember my own name.   And it is objectifying.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> These images, those images  objectify disabled people  for the benefit of nondisabled people.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> They are there so that you can look at them  and think that things aren't so bad for you,  to put your worries into perspective.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> And life as a disabled person  is actually somewhat difficult.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> We do overcome some things.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> But the things that we're overcoming  are not the things that you think they are.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> They are not things to do with our bodies.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> I use the term "disabled people" quite deliberately,  because I subscribe to what's called the social model of disability,  which tells us that we are more disabled  by the society that we live in  than by our bodies and our diagnoses.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> So I have lived in this body a long time.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> I'm quite fond of it.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> It does the things that I need it to do,  and I've learned to use it to the best of its capacity  just as you have,  and that's the thing about those kids in those pictures as well.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> They're not doing anything out of the ordinary.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> They are just using their bodies  to the best of their capacity.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> So is it really fair to objectify them  in the way that we do,  to share those images?    </seg>
<seg id="58"> People, when they say, "You're an inspiration,"  they mean it as a compliment.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> And I know why it happens.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> It's because of the lie, it's because we've been sold  this lie that disability makes you exceptional.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> And it honestly doesn't.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> And I know what you're thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> You know, I'm up here bagging out inspiration,  and you're thinking, "Jeez, Stella,  aren't you inspired sometimes by some things?"    </seg>
<seg id="64"> And the thing is, I am.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> I learn from other disabled people all the time.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> I'm learning not that I am luckier than them, though.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> I am learning that it's a genius idea  to use a pair of barbecue tongs  to pick up things that you dropped.   I'm learning that nifty trick where you can charge  your mobile phone battery from your chair battery.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Genius.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> We are learning from each others' strength and endurance,  not against our bodies and our diagnoses,  but against a world that exceptionalizes  and objectifies us.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> I really think that this lie that we've been sold  about disability is the greatest injustice.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> It makes life hard for us.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> And that quote, "The only disability in life  is a bad attitude,"  the reason that that's bullshit  is because it's just not true,  because of the social model of disability.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> No amount of smiling at a flight of stairs  has ever made it turn into a ramp.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Never.    Smiling at a television screen  isn't going to make closed captions appear  for people who are deaf.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> No amount of standing in the middle of a bookshop  and radiating a positive attitude  is going to turn all those books into braille.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> It's just not going to happen.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> I really want to live in a world  where disability is not the exception, but the norm.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> I want to live in a world where a 15-year-old girl  sitting in her bedroom  watching "Buffy the Vampire Slayer"  isn't referred to as achieving anything  because she's doing it sitting down.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> I want to live in a world  where we don't have such low expectations  of disabled people  that we are congratulated for getting out of bed  and remembering our own names in the morning.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> I want to live in a world where we value genuine achievement  for disabled people,  and I want to live in a world  where a kid in year 11 in a Melbourne high school  is not one bit surprised  that his new teacher is a wheelchair user.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Disability doesn't make you exceptional,  but questioning what you think you know about it does.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1997" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/kevin_briggs_the_bridge_between_suicide_and_life</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: For many years Sergeant Kevin Briggs had a dark, unusual, at times strangely rewarding job: He patrolled the southern end of San Francisco’s Golden Gate Bridge, a popular site for suicide attempts. In a sobering, deeply personal talk Briggs shares stories from those he’s spoken — and listened — to standing on the edge of life. He gives a powerful piece of advice to those with loved ones who might be contemplating suicide.</description> 
<keywords>talks, culture, depression, mental health, suicide</keywords> 
<talkid>1997</talkid> 
<title>Kevin Briggs: The bridge between suicide and life</title> 
<reviewer href="http://www.ted.com/profiles/2064042">Mad Aronson</reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I recently retired  from the California Highway Patrol  after 23 years of service.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> The majority of those 23 years  was spent patrolling the southern end  of Marin County,  which includes the Golden Gate Bridge.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> The bridge is an iconic structure,  known worldwide  for its beautiful views of San Francisco,  the Pacific Ocean, and its inspiring architecture.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Unfortunately, it is also a magnet for suicide,  being one of the most utilized sites in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> The Golden Gate Bridge opened in 1937.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Joseph Strauss, chief engineer in charge of building the bridge,  was quoted as saying,  "The bridge is practically suicide-proof.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Suicide from the bridge  is neither practical nor probable."    </seg>
<seg id="8"> But since its opening,  over 1,600 people have leapt to their death  from that bridge.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Some believe that traveling  between the two towers  will lead you to another dimension --  this bridge has been romanticized as such —  that the fall from that  frees you from all your worries and grief,  and the waters below  will cleanse your soul.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> But let me tell you what actually occurs  when the bridge is used  as a means of suicide.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> After a free fall of four to five seconds,  the body strikes the water  at about 75 miles an hour.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> That impact shatters bones,  some of which then puncture vital organs.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Most die on impact.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Those that don't  generally flail in the water helplessly,  and then drown.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I don't think that those who contemplate  this method of suicide  realize how grisly a death that they will face.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> This is the cord.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Except for around the two towers,  there is 32 inches of steel  paralleling the bridge.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> This is where most folks stand  before taking their lives.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> I can tell you from experience  that once the person is on that cord,  and at their darkest time,  it is very difficult to bring them back.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> I took this photo last year  as this young woman spoke to an officer  contemplating her life.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I want to tell you very happily  that we were successful that day  in getting her back over the rail.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> When I first began working on the bridge,  we had no formal training.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> You struggled to funnel your way through these calls.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> This was not only a disservice  to those contemplating suicide,  but to the officers as well.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> We've come a long, long way since then.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Now, veteran officers and psychologists  train new officers.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> This is Jason Garber.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> I met Jason on July 22 of last year  when I get received a call  of a possible suicidal subject  sitting on the cord near midspan.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> I responded, and when I arrived,  I observed Jason  speaking to a Golden Gate Bridge officer.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Jason was just 32 years old  and had flown out here from New Jersey.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> As a matter of fact,  he had flown out here on two other occasions  from New Jersey  to attempt suicide on this bridge.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> After about an hour of speaking with Jason,  he asked us if we knew the story of Pandora's box.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Recalling your Greek mythology,  Zeus created Pandora,  and sent her down to Earth with a box,  and told her, "Never, ever open that box."    </seg>
<seg id="34"> Well one day, curiosity got the better of Pandora,  and she did open the box.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Out flew plagues, sorrows,  and all sorts of evils against man.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> The only good thing in the box was hope.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Jason then asked us,  "What happens when you open the box  and hope isn't there?"    </seg>
<seg id="38"> He paused a few moments,  leaned to his right,  and was gone.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> This kind, intelligent young man from New Jersey  had just committed suicide.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> I spoke with Jason's parents that evening,  and I suppose that, when I was speaking with them,  that I didn't sound as if I was doing very well,  because that very next day,  their family rabbi called to check on me.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Jason's parents had asked him to do so.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> The collateral damage of suicide  affects so many people.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> I pose these questions to you:  What would you do if your family member,  friend or loved one was suicidal?    </seg>
<seg id="44"> What would you say?    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Would you know what to say?    </seg>
<seg id="46"> In my experience, it's not just the talking that you do,  but the listening.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Listen to understand.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Don't argue, blame,  or tell the person you know how they feel,  because you probably don't.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> By just being there,  you may just be the turning point that they need.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> If you think someone is suicidal,  don't be afraid to confront them and ask the question.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> One way of asking them the question is like this:  "Others in similar circumstances  have thought about ending their life;  have you had these thoughts?"    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Confronting the person head-on  may just save their life and be the turning point for them.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Some other signs to look for:  hopelessness, believing that things are terrible  and never going to get better;  helplessness, believing that there is nothing  that you can do about it;  recent social withdrawal;  and a loss of interest in life.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> I came up with this talk just a couple of days ago,  and I received an email from a lady  that I'd like to read you her letter.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> She lost her son on January 19 of this year,  and she wrote this me this email  just a couple of days ago,  and it's with her permission and blessing  that I read this to you.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> "Hi, Kevin. I imagine you're at the TED Conference.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> That must be quite the experience to be there.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> I'm thinking I should go walk the bridge this weekend.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Just wanted to drop you a note.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Hope you get the word out to many people  and they go home talking about it  to their friends who tell their friends, etc.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> I'm still pretty numb,  but noticing more moments of really realizing  Mike isn't coming home.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Mike was driving from Petaluma to San Francisco  to watch the 49ers game with his father  on January 19.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> He never made it there.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> I called Petaluma police  and reported him missing that evening.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> The next morning,  two officers came to my home  and reported that Mike's car was down at the bridge.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> A witness had observed him jumping off the bridge  at 1:58 p.m. the previous day.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> Thanks so much  for standing up for those  who may be only temporarily too weak  to stand for themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Who hasn't been low before  without suffering from a true mental illness?    </seg>
<seg id="69"> It shouldn't be so easy to end it.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> My prayers are with you for your fight.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> The GGB, Golden Gate Bridge,  is supposed to be a passage across  our beautiful bay,  not a graveyard.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Good luck this week. Vicky."    </seg>
<seg id="73"> I can't imagine the courage it takes for her  to go down to that bridge and walk the path  that her son took that day,  and also the courage just to carry on.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> I'd like to introduce you to a man  I refer to as hope and courage.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> On March 11 of 2005,  I responded to a radio call of a possible  suicidal subject on the bridge sidewalk  near the north tower.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> I rode my motorcycle down the sidewalk  and observed this man, Kevin Berthia,  standing on the sidewalk.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> When he saw me, he immediately traversed  that pedestrian rail,  and stood on that small pipe  which goes around the tower.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> For the next hour and a half,  I listened as Kevin spoke about  his depression and hopelessness.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Kevin decided on his own that day  to come back over that rail  and give life another chance.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> When Kevin came back over,  I congratulated him.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> "This is a new beginning, a new life."    </seg>
<seg id="82"> But I asked him, "What was it  that made you come back  and give hope and life another chance?"    </seg>
<seg id="83"> And you know what he told me?    </seg>
<seg id="84"> He said, "You listened.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> You let me speak, and you just listened."    </seg>
<seg id="86"> Shortly after this incident,  I received a letter from Kevin's mother,  and I have that letter with me,  and I'd like to read it to you.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> "Dear Mr. Briggs,  Nothing will erase the events of March 11,  but you are one of the reasons Kevin is still with us.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> I truly believe Kevin was crying out for help.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> He has been diagnosed with a mental illness  for which he has been properly medicated.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> I adopted Kevin when he was only six months old,  completely unaware of any hereditary traits,  but, thank God, now we know.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> Kevin is straight, as he says.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> We truly thank God for you.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> Sincerely indebted to you,  Narvella Berthia."    </seg>
<seg id="94"> And on the bottom she writes,  "P.S. When I visited San Francisco General Hospital that evening,  you were listed as the patient.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> Boy, did I have to straighten that one out."    </seg>
<seg id="96"> Today, Kevin is a loving father  and contributing member of society.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> He speaks openly  about the events that day and his depression  in the hopes that his story  will inspire others.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> Suicide is not just something I've encountered on the job.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> It's personal.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> My grandfather committed suicide by poisoning.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> That act, although ending his own pain,  robbed me from ever getting to know him.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> This is what suicide does.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> For most suicidal folks,  or those contemplating suicide,  they wouldn't think of hurting another person.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> They just want their own pain to end.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> Typically, this is accomplished in just three ways:  sleep, drugs or alcohol, or death.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> In my career, I've responded to  and been involved in hundreds  of mental illness and suicide calls  around the bridge.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> Of those incidents I've been directly involved with,  I've only lost two,  but that's two too many.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> One was Jason.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> The other was a man I spoke to  for about an hour.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> During that time, he shook my hand  on three occasions.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> On that final handshake,  he looked at me, and he said,  "Kevin, I'm sorry, but I have to go."    </seg>
<seg id="112"> And he leapt.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> Horrible, absolutely horrible.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> I do want to tell you, though,  the vast majority of folks  that we do get to contact on that bridge  do not commit suicide.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> Additionally, that very few  who have jumped off the bridge and lived  and can talk about it,  that one to two percent,  most of those folks have said  that the second that they let go of that rail,  they knew that they had made a mistake  and they wanted to live.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> I tell people, the bridge not only connects  Marin to San Francisco,  but people together also.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> That connection, or bridge that we make,  is something that each and every one of us  should strive to do.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> Suicide is preventable.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> There is help. There is hope.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1954" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/ziauddin_yousafzai_my_daughter_malala</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Pakistani educator Ziauddin Yousafzai reminds the world of a simple truth that many don’t want to hear: Women and men deserve equal opportunities for education, autonomy, an independent identity. He tells stories from his own life and the life of his daughter, Malala, who was shot by the Taliban in 2012 simply for daring to go to school. "Why is my daughter so strong?” Yousafzai asks. “Because I didn’t clip her wings."</description> 
<keywords>talks, education, family, feminism, global issues, women, yesallwomen</keywords> 
<talkid>1954</talkid> 
<title>Ziauddin Yousafzai: My daughter, Malala</title> 
<reviewer href="http://www.ted.com/profiles/2064042">Mad Aronson</reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> In many patriarchal societies and tribal societies,  fathers are usually known by their sons,  but I'm one of the few fathers  who is known by his daughter,  and I am proud of it.    </seg>
<seg id="2">   Malala started her campaign for education  and stood for her rights in 2007,  and when her efforts were honored in 2011,  and she was given the national youth peace prize,  and she became a very famous,  very popular young girl of her country.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> Before that, she was my daughter,  but now I am her father.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Ladies and gentlemen,  if we glance to human history,  the story of women  is the story of injustice,  inequality,  violence and exploitation.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> You see,  in patriarchal societies,  right from the very beginning,  when a girl is born,  her birth is not celebrated.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> She is not welcomed,  neither by father nor by mother.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> The neighborhood comes  and commiserates with the mother,  and nobody congratulates the father.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And a mother is very uncomfortable  for having a girl child.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> When she gives birth to the first girl child,  first daughter, she is sad.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> When she gives birth to the second daughter,  she is shocked,  and in the expectation of a son,  when she gives birth to a third daughter,  she feels guilty like a criminal.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Not only the mother suffers,  but the daughter, the newly born daughter,  when she grows old,  she suffers too.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> At the age of five,  while she should be going to school,  she stays at home  and her brothers are admitted in a school.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Until the age of 12, somehow,  she has a good life.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> She can have fun.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> She can play with her friends in the streets,  and she can move around in the streets  like a butterfly.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> But when she enters her teens,  when she becomes 13 years old,  she is forbidden to go out of her home  without a male escort.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> She is confined under the four walls of her home.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> She is no more a free individual.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> She becomes the so-called honor  of her father and of her brothers  and of her family,  and if she transgresses  the code of that so-called honor,  she could even be killed.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And it is also interesting that this so-called  code of honor,  it does not only affect the life of a girl,  it also affects the life  of the male members of the family.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I know a family of seven sisters and one brother,  and that one brother,  he has migrated to the Gulf countries,  to earn a living for his seven sisters  and parents,  because he thinks that it will be humiliating  if his seven sisters learn a skill  and they go out of the home  and earn some livelihood.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> So this brother,  he sacrifices the joys of his life  and the happiness of his sisters  at the altar of so-called honor.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> And there is one more norm  of the patriarchal societies  that is called obedience.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> A good girl is supposed to be  very quiet, very humble  and very submissive.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> It is the criteria.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> The role model good girl should be very quiet.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> She is supposed to be silent  and she is supposed to accept the decisions  of her father and mother  and the decisions of elders,  even if she does not like them.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> If she is married to a man she doesn't like  or if she is married to an old man,  she has to accept,  because she does not want to be dubbed  as disobedient.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> If she is married very early,  she has to accept.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Otherwise, she will be called disobedient.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> And what happens at the end?    </seg>
<seg id="32"> In the words of a poetess,  she is wedded, bedded,  and then she gives birth to more sons and daughters.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> And it is the irony of the situation  that this mother,  she teaches the same lesson of obedience  to her daughter  and the same lesson of honor to her sons.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> And this vicious cycle goes on, goes on.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Ladies and gentlemen,  this plight of millions of women  could be changed  if we think differently,  if women and men think differently,  if men and women in the tribal and patriarchal societies  in the developing countries,  if they can break a few norms  of family and society,  if they can abolish the discriminatory laws  of the systems in their states,  which go against the basic human rights of the women.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Dear brothers and sisters, when Malala was born,  and for the first time,  believe me,  I don't like newborn children, to be honest,  but when I went and I looked into her eyes,  believe me,  I got extremely honored.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> And long before she was born,  I thought about her name,  and I was fascinated with a heroic  legendary freedom fighter in Afghanistan.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> Her name was Malalai of Maiwand,  and I named my daughter after her.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> A few days after Malala was born,  my daughter was born,  my cousin came --  and it was a coincidence --  he came to my home  and he brought a family tree,  a family tree of the Yousafzai family,  and when I looked at the family tree,  it traced back to 300 years of our ancestors.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> But when I looked, all were men,  and I picked my pen,  drew a line from my name,  and wrote, "Malala."    </seg>
<seg id="41"> And when she grow old,  when she was four and a half years old,  I admitted her in my school.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> You will be asking, then, why should I mention about  the admission of a girl in a school?    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Yes, I must mention it.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> It may be taken for granted in Canada,  in America, in many developed countries,  but in poor countries,  in patriarchal societies, in tribal societies,  it's a big event for the life of girl.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Enrollment in a school means  recognition of her identity and her name.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Admission in a school means  that she has entered the world of dreams  and aspirations  where she can explore her potentials  for her future life.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> I have five sisters,  and none of them could go to school,  and you will be astonished,  two weeks before,  when I was filling out the Canadian visa form,  and I was filling out the family part of the form,  I could not recall  the surnames of some of my sisters.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> And the reason was  that I have never, never seen the names  of my sisters written on any document.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> That was the reason that  I valued my daughter.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> What my father could not give to my sisters  and to his daughters,  I thought I must change it.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> I used to appreciate the intelligence  and the brilliance of my daughter.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> I encouraged her to sit with me  when my friends used to come.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> I encouraged her to go with me to different meetings.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And all these good values,  I tried to inculcate in her personality.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And this was not only she, only Malala.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> I imparted all these good values  to my school, girl students and boy students as well.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> I used education for emancipation.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> I taught my girls,  I taught my girl students,  to unlearn the lesson of obedience.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> I taught my boy students  to unlearn the lesson of so-called pseudo-honor.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Dear brothers and sisters,  we were striving for more rights for women,  and we were struggling to have more,  more and more space for the women in society.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> But we came across a new phenomenon.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> It was lethal to human rights  and particularly to women's rights.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> It was called Talibanization.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> It means a complete negation  of women's participation  in all political, economical and social activities.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Hundreds of schools were lost.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Girls were prohibited from going to school.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> Women were forced to wear veils  and they were stopped from going to the markets.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Musicians were silenced,  girls were flogged  and singers were killed.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Millions were suffering,  but few spoke,  and it was the most scary thing  when you have all around such people  who kill and who flog,  and you speak for your rights.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> It's really the most scary thing.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> At the age of 10,  Malala stood, and she stood for the right  of education.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> She wrote a diary for the BBC blog,  she volunteered herself  for the New York Times documentaries,  and she spoke from every platform she could.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> And her voice was the most powerful voice.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> It spread like a crescendo all around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> And that was the reason the Taliban  could not tolerate her campaign,  and on October 9 2012,  she was shot in the head at point blank range.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> It was a doomsday for my family and for me.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> The world turned into a big black hole.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> While my daughter was  on the verge of life and death,  I whispered into the ears of my wife,  "Should I be blamed for what happened  to my daughter and your daughter?"    </seg>
<seg id="79"> And she abruptly told me,  "Please don't blame yourself.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> You stood for the right cause.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> You put your life at stake  for the cause of truth,  for the cause of peace,  and for the cause of education,  and your daughter in inspired from you  and she joined you.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> You both were on the right path  and God will protect her."    </seg>
<seg id="83"> These few words meant a lot to me,  and I didn't ask this question again.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> When Malala was in the hospital,  and she was going through the severe pains  and she had had severe headaches  because her facial nerve was cut down,  I used to see a dark shadow  spreading on the face of my wife.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> But my daughter never complained.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> She used to tell us,  "I'm fine with my crooked smile  and with my numbness in my face.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> I'll be okay. Please don't worry."    </seg>
<seg id="88"> She was a solace for us,  and she consoled us.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> Dear brothers and sisters,  we learned from her how to be resilient  in the most difficult times,  and I'm glad to share with you  that despite being an icon  for the rights of children and women,  she is like any 16-year old girl.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> She cries when her homework is incomplete.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> She quarrels with her brothers,  and I am very happy for that.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> People ask me,  what special is in my mentorship  which has made Malala so bold  and so courageous and so vocal and poised?    </seg>
<seg id="93"> I tell them, don't ask me what I did.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> Ask me what I did not do.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> I did not clip her wings, and that's all.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
<seg id="97">   Thank you. Thank you very much. Thank you.     </seg>
</doc>
</srcset>
</mteval>
